<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2020</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2019-03</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>DoD Human Resources Activity</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0300D</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Procurement, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserP1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit P-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>P-1 Exhibit_022619_DHRA_DHRA#XxEFg.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserP1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:WorkFlowStatus>DRAFT</jb:WorkFlowStatus>
        <jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>Title(s) undefined</jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
        <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <proc:LineItemList xmlns:proc="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/20100219/procurement">
        <proc:LineItem quantityUnits="Each" quantityUnitName="Each" unitCostUnits="Millions" totalCostUnits="Millions" manufacturerRateUnits="Monthly" combinedP5Flag="false">
            <proc:LineItemNumber>500</proc:LineItemNumber>
            <proc:LineItemTitle>Personnel Administration</proc:LineItemTitle>
            <proc:P1LineNumber>3</proc:P1LineNumber>
            <proc:BudgetYear>2020</proc:BudgetYear>
            <proc:BudgetCycle>PB</proc:BudgetCycle>
            <proc:SubmissionDate>2019-03</proc:SubmissionDate>
            <proc:ServiceAgencyName>DoD Human Resources Activity</proc:ServiceAgencyName>
            <proc:AppropriationNumber>0300D</proc:AppropriationNumber>
            <proc:AppropriationTitle>Procurement, Defense-Wide</proc:AppropriationTitle>
            <proc:BudgetActivityNumber>1</proc:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetActivityTitle>Major Equipment</proc:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>20</proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>Major Equipment, DHRA</proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>
            <proc:ResourceSummary>
                <proc:TotalCost>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>23.573</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>14.588</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>10.63</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>5.118</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>5.215</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>6.51</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>6.64</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalCost>
                <proc:NetProcurementP1>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>23.573</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>14.588</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>10.63</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>5.118</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>5.215</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>6.51</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>6.64</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:NetProcurementP1>
                <proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>23.573</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>14.588</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>10.63</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>5.118</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>5.215</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>6.51</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>6.64</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
            </proc:ResourceSummary>
            <proc:CodeBProgramElementList>
                <proc:ProgramElementNumber>0901220SE</proc:ProgramElementNumber>
            </proc:CodeBProgramElementList>
            <proc:Description>The Department of Defense Human Resources Activity (DHRA) is a consolidated Field Activity under the direction and control of the Under Secretary of Defense (Personnel and Readiness) (USD (P&amp;R)) established for the collection and interaction of manpower and personnel data to support Department-wide tracking, analysis, research, studies, and a wide variety of reporting requirements. DHRA provides functional information management, civilian personnel policy support, and civilian personnel administrative services to DoD Components and activities. The scope of operations is necessarily broad and encompasses all aspects of data collection and utilization of Defense manpower and personnel data records to support DoD-wide analysis, studies, research, and reporting requirements. DHRA is the responsible organization within DoD for the interchange of automated manpower data with other government agencies. 

In FY 2017, as a result of a Business Process and Systems Review, DHRA implemented a major reorganization impacting the DHRA procurement budget. The most significant aspect of this reorganization, from a procurement perspective, was the integration of the Enterprise Human Resources Information System (EHRIS) into the Defense Manpower Data Center's (DMDC) portfolio of information technology (IT) initiatives. Additionally, DHRA implemented a major reorganization of the DMDC programs to more accurately align budget program lines with the DHRA Information Technology (IT) data reported in the DHRA IT Budget. The Defense Eligibility and Enrollment System (DEERS); Data Governance/Data Acquisition &amp; Decision Support (EDS); Real Time Automated Personnel Identification System (RAPIDS); Common Access Card (CAC); the Cyber Security program was integrated into the DEERS and RAPIDS programs, with CAC being retained as part of the RAPIDS program. Synchronized Pre-deployment and Operational Tracker (SPOT) was integrated into a Personnel Accountability (PA) program, which also includes Joint Personnel Accountability Reconciliation and Reporting (JPARR), and Noncombatant Evacuation Operations (NEO) Tracking System (NTS).

Enterprise Human Resources Information System (EHRIS) includes the Defense Civilian Personnel Data System (DCPDS), the Department's enterprise civilian human resources (HR) transactional system supporting 900,000 employees, representing approximately one-third of the federal government's civilian work force.  Network and system operations span worldwide, with 24/7 operations. 

Defense Eligibility and Enrollment System (DEERS) is DoD's only authoritative repository for all manpower and personnel data on military, civilian, selected contractors, retirees, and family members. DEERS determines eligibility for statutory benefits and entitlements, and tracks and verifies enrollment in these programs.  DEERS also maintains medical and personnel readiness information on all Uniformed Services members, to include managing TRICARE eligibility and enrollment. DEERS provides identity, enrollment, and eligibility verification through DEERS client applications and interfacing systems, as well as to the DoD Components and non-DoD information systems and directly to the beneficiary.

The Identity Credential Management program (formerly RAPIDS) sustains the infrastructure systems that support the issuance of DoD and Uniformed Services identification cards and provides on-line updates to DEERS. This includes RAPIDS, which issues the CAC to Service members, civilian employees, and eligible contractors, thus providing an enterprise-wide credential for both physical and logical access to DoD facilities and networks. These DoD credentials use the DEERS database for authentication and personnel information.  RAPIDS is also the primary source for adding family members to DEERS, and it provides the seven Uniformed Services the means to verify eligibility for specific benefits and entitlements.

The Personnel Accountability (PA) program designs and implements technological solutions to gather, analyze, and share information on the physical location of DoD members and affiliated personnel in order to ensure the safety and enhance the readiness of the Armed Forces of the United States. The PA program is comprised of several initiatives, including: Synchronized Pre-deployment and Operational Tracker Enterprise Suite (SPOT-ES), Joint Personnel Reporting Systems (JPRS), and the Noncombatant Evacuation Operations (NEO) Tracking System (NTS). This family of systems represents end-to-end tracking, reconciliation and reporting of DoD personnel location and movements, to include military, DoD affiliated civilians, contractors, and U.S. citizens. This includes DoD travel, contracts, and contractor personnel tracking in support of contingencies, military readiness, reporting of locations at the unit and person level, accountability of DoD personnel during (and after) natural or man-made disasters, and accountability and visibility of noncombatant evacuees.

As the Master Data Management (MDM) arm of DMDC, the Enterprise Data Services (EDS) program governs the data collection, data storage and data distribution of DMDC data assets to include:  data modeling, database standardization, data quality, database architectures, and data distribution safeguarded by the security mechanisms which ensure compliance with the DoD information assurance standards and the PII directives of the DoD.  EDS is also the enterprise focal point for cybersecurity toolset management and data center consolidation.  The EDS program is comprised of 5 initiatives: Data Governance, Data Acquisition and Decision Support (DA&amp;DS), Personnel Data Reporting Systems, Data Center Consolidation and Cyber.</proc:Description>
            <proc:Justification>Project: EHRIS. In FY 2020, DMDC reduced Procurement investment in the EHRIS program.  In compliance with the Data Center Optimization Initiative (DCOI) established by OMB Memorandum M-16-19, DMDC has secured Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) capabilities from DISA.  With this shift to IaaS, DMDC will no longer procure its own infrastructure, but will instead reimburse DISA annually to provide infrastructure and hosting services.  DMDC has reprogrammed $5.450M to O&amp;M funding to support this requirement.  A small amount of Procurement funding is still required to support any requirements that are not included in DISA's standard IaaS offerings.  

Project: DEERS. FY 2020 investment will be used to procure infrastructure for MilConnect to expand secure self-service capabilities for DoD beneficiaries to increase our service members' ability to access the right data at the right time.  Emphasis will be on enabling use of personal communication devices such as smart phones, tablets, and other mobile devices which play an ever-increasing role in the lives of DoD beneficiaries.  

Project: RAPIDS/CAC.  FY 2020 investment in Automated Data Processing (ADP) equipment includes the acquisition of the DMDC RAPIDS/CAC infrastructure, allowing the replacement of outdated and/or maintenance-intensive equipment in order to continue to ensure full functionality, system security, and HSPD-12 compliance of the RAPIDS/CAC system.

Project: PA. FY 2020 investment in the NEO Tracking System (NTS) will be used to upgrade fielded NTS across the COCOMs and the National Guard as called for in Joint Requirements Oversight Council Memorandum (JROCM) 117-10 dated 29 JUL 2010. This centralized procurement of equipment will enable DMDC to track the systems in the field and provide support such as software upgrades, training and equipment tracking which are also responsibilities of DMDC called out in JROCM 117-10.  Upgraded equipment will provide the COCOMs with more manageable and reliable systems.  

Other PA programs such as SPOT-ES will receive upgraded equipment that decreases the footprint and meets the requirement of reducing redundant IT services across the Department.  SPOT-ES will also increase their global presence through improved guidance at the COCOMs and additional hardware will be required to support the use of JAMMS in the SPOT-ES program. 

FY 2020 investment in the JPARR will allow for continued expansion. This investment will allow for the acquisition of hardware and software needed to include the U.S. Northern Command (NORTHCOM) into JPARR. USNORTHCOM will be the sixth Combatant Command supported by these reports. Investments will also be made to modernize the applications and improve reporting capabilities. 

Project: EDS. FY 2020 investment will be used to procure hardware and software to consolidate the Person Data Repository (PDR) and many other sister databases while implementing common access services to improve DMDC's insider threat posture and mature data cyber security capability.</proc:Justification>
            <proc:ItemExhibitList>
                <proc:P40AItemGroup>
                    <proc:Name>Major Equipment</proc:Name>
                    <proc:CategoryList>
                        <proc:Category>
                            <proc:Name>Major Equipment, DHRA</proc:Name>
                            <proc:ItemList>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>DCPDS Central Operations</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>1</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>4.643</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>4.643</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>RAPIDS/CAC</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>2</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>0.646</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>0.991</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>0.646</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>0.991</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>DEERS/RAPIDS/CAC/JPARR/NTS/Data Governance/CYBER</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>3</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>2</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>4.254</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>2.127</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>Virtual Lifetime Electronic Record (VLER)</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>4</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>0.444</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>0.444</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>Enterprise Human Resource Information Systems (EHRIS)</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>5</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>5.733</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>7.1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>5.945</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0.75</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>0.75</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>5.733</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>7.1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>5.945</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0.75</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>0.75</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>DEERS</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>6</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>4.993</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1.203</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1.851</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1.42</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1.42</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>4.993</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1.203</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1.851</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1.42</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1.42</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>Personnel Accountability (PA)</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>7</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1.36</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1.36</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1.348</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1.36</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1.36</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1.36</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1.36</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1.348</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1.36</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1.36</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                                <proc:Item>
                                    <proc:Name>Enterprise Data Systems (EDS)</proc:Name>
                                    <proc:ItemNumber>8</proc:ItemNumber>
                                    <proc:ResourceSummary>
                                        <proc:Quantity>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>1</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>1</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>1</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:Quantity>
                                        <proc:TotalCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1.5</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>3.925</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>0.495</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0.5</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>0.5</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:TotalCost>
                                        <proc:UnitCost>
                                            <proc:AllPriorYears>1.5</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                            <proc:PriorYear>3.925</proc:PriorYear>
                                            <proc:CurrentYear>0.495</proc:CurrentYear>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0.5</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>0.5</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                        </proc:UnitCost>
                                    </proc:ResourceSummary>
                                </proc:Item>
                            </proc:ItemList>
                            <proc:CategorySubtotal>
                                <proc:TotalCost>
                                    <proc:AllPriorYears>23.573</proc:AllPriorYears>
                                    <proc:PriorYear>14.588</proc:PriorYear>
                                    <proc:CurrentYear>10.63</proc:CurrentYear>
                                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    <proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>0</proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>
                                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                                </proc:TotalCost>
                            </proc:CategorySubtotal>
                        </proc:Category>
                    </proc:CategoryList>
                    <proc:TotalCost>
                        <proc:TotalCost>
                            <proc:AllPriorYears>23.573</proc:AllPriorYears>
                            <proc:PriorYear>14.588</proc:PriorYear>
                            <proc:CurrentYear>10.63</proc:CurrentYear>
                            <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>0</proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>
                            <proc:BudgetYearOne>5.03</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                        </proc:TotalCost>
                    </proc:TotalCost>
                </proc:P40AItemGroup>
            </proc:ItemExhibitList>
            <proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                <proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>item</proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>
            </proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        </proc:LineItem>
    </proc:LineItemList>
</jb:JustificationBook>