<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2018</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2017-05</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>R1.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:GenerateR1>true</jb:GenerateR1>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:ProgramElementList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604826J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint C5 Capability Development, Integration, and Interoperability Assessments</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>104</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2018</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2017-05</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>4</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Advanced Component Development &amp; Prototypes (ACD&amp;P)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>21.700</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>23.642</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>23.638</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>23.638</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>23.148</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>20.809</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>20.809</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>20.809</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>Lead command, control, communications, computers, and cyber (C5) assessments, analyses, capability development, and Joint Fires Command and Control (C2) interoperability efforts required to achieve an effective, integrated, and interoperable Joint Force.  Efforts include C5 requirements determination, C5 architectures development and integration, C5 data standardization, Joint Fires C2 interoperability, and C5 integration and interoperability assessments. This was a new PE for FY 2016 and consolidates legacy U. S. Joint Forces Command (JFCOM) PEs that transitioned to the Joint Staff in FY 2013 after JFCOM disestablishment. The following PEs are no longer used:  0604828J - Joint Fires Integration and Interoperability Team (JFI), 0604787J - Joint Systems Integration Command (JSI), and 0607828J - Joint Integration and Interoperability (JII).</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>21.700</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>23.642</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>23.638</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>23.638</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>21.700</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>23.642</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>23.638</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>23.638</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Prior Year Carryover</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                    </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>Decrease in funding for FY 2019 thru FY 2022 is a result of mandated 25% Management Headquarters Activities (MHA) reductions prescribed by the 2016 NDAA.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>C5 Assessments and Analyses</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>10.196</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>12.898</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>12.898</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>12.898</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>12.361</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>10.022</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>10.022</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>10.022</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Conduct analysis and assessment activities to inform and enhance Joint warfighter capabilities in support of U.S. National Security requirements. Provide timely, facts-based findings and recommendations for action through the formal DoD decision-making processes used to validate operational requirements and apply funding to field effective, interoperable capabilities. Conduct interoperability assessments and analyses that evaluate capability and interoperability of fielded and emerging command, control, communications, computers, and cyber (C5), and systems in response to operational issues and shortfalls.  Conduct integration and integration assessment efforts focused on emerging capabilities in wireless devices and security, tactical command and control and networking, satellite communications, advanced secure digital datalinks, and coalition data exchanges.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>C5 Assessments and Analyses</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Conduct analysis and assessment activities to inform and enhance Joint warfighter capabilities in support of U.S. National Security requirements. Provide timely, facts-based findings and recommendations for action through the formal DoD decision-making processes used to validate operational requirements and apply funding to field effective, interoperable capabilities. Conduct interoperability assessments and analyses that evaluate capability and interoperability of fielded and emerging command, control, communications, computers, and cyber (C5), and systems in response to operational issues and shortfalls.  Conduct integration and integration assessment efforts focused on emerging capabilities in wireless devices and security, tactical command and control and networking, satellite communications, advanced secure digital datalinks, and coalition data exchanges.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>10.196</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Conducted eight (8) integration initiatives of new capabilities; twenty-five (25) interoperability assessments of joint and coalition systems; thirty-four (34) Coalition Interoperability Assurance and Validation (CIAV) events that provided eighty-five (85) recommendations and one hundred-ten (110) findings or observations; eight (8) exercises and events conducted in the field; and provided C2 Systems and Persistent C4 Environment support by leveraging training events for capability development efforts.  FY 2016 assessment, analysis and integration initiatives were focused on: Joint C2 Capability Development, Mission Partner Environment (MPE)/NATO/Multinational Engagement, Joint Fires Combat Identification, Counter Unmanned Aerial Systems, Data and Services Standards, and Cyber Capability Development.  The most important projects included:

(1)	Friendly Force Tracking (FFT) Ground to Air (G2A) Situational Assessment – Conducted an operational assessment of US and Coalition partner ground to air situational awareness systems.  Validated that the systems received correct information data, processed a high volume of data, and the data management/processing capability correctly sorted track data to reduce risk of fratricide.

(2)	Joint Operational Long Term Evolution Deployable (JOLTED) Tactical Cellular System (TACTICS) Joint Capability Technology Demonstration (JCTD) Technical Manager – JOLTED TACTICS is an Internet Protocol (IP) based system designed to provide secure cellular communications to tactical users at much higher data rates than other tactical networks.  This system leverages innovations in Fourth Generation (4G) LTE Cellular technologies and mobile Ka band spread spectrum satellite communications to deliver megabits of data to mobile and dismounted teams armed with mobile devices such as smartphones or netbooks.   As the JCTD Technical Manager C4AD conducted the operational assessments to prove the system's validity.  The successful JCTD resulted in transition agreements to field the system being executed with PM WIN-T, NAVAIR, and PdM Nett Warrior as program managers. 

(3)	Air Operation Center (AOC) and Joint Operations Center (JOC) C2 Information Systems (C2IS) Capability Integrations (six (6) events) – Provided a persistent operational cyber environment to USPACOM where Blue Teams and Red Teams interacted with operational command and control systems and networks.

(4)	Automated NATO Database Interface Interoperability Assessments – Assessed the automated exchange of targeting data between the US Joint Targeting Toolbox (JTT) and the NATO Joint Targeting System (JTS) which enables faster joint and coalition targeting by automating the transfer of targeting data, reducing manpower requirements, and data entry errors.

(5)	C17 Hatch Mount Satellite Antenna (HMSA) Operational Assessment – The C-17 HMSA provided enhanced bandwidth to support on-board mission commander’s requirement for communications capable of enroute mission planning during forcible entry operations.  The successful operational assessment resulted in operational commanders recommending that the system be fielded, but there has not yet been a fielding decision.

(6)	Commercial Solutions for Classified (CSFC)/Secure Wireless Local Area Network (SWLAN) Integration Assessments - Assisted the National Security Agency in the development, assessment, and fixed site deployment of a Suite B software encryption solution. This capability supports communicating over classified wireless networks without encryption hardware.

(7)	Coalition Warrior Interoperability Exercise 2016 (CWIX16) – Supported the technical validation of eleven (11) Federated Mission Networking (FMN) specifications, participating countries use of them, and the interoperability of these networked services in a federated environment.  Conducted an assessment of FMN Spiral Specifications as an extension of CIAV and related them to US Mission Partner Environment (MPE) networking.

(8)	Executive Command and Control-Generation Next (EC2 GenNext) Data at Rest Technical Solution – Provided Senior Leadership with an e-reader solution that uses a Windows Surface Pro tablet running an NSA approved data at rest security solution.  The capability provides Executive/Senior Leaders with access to classified material on a device that is NSA approved secure and unclassified when powered down.

(9)	Distributed Assured and Dynamic Configuration (DADC) Support – Assessed DADC’s capability to detect/repair equipment misconfigurations and C2 system’s version incompatibilities to optimize network performance in USPACOM.    
                                                               
(10)	USPACOM Targeting and ISR Interoperability Assessment – Conducted an initial PACOM HQ and Service/Coalition assessment of joint targeting and command/decision systems. 

(11)	Black Dart – Led data collection and analysis on the integration of counter-UAS (C-UAS) operational architectures, operational concepts, and tactics, techniques, and procedures (TTPs) during BLACK DART event.  Evaluated current and proposed operational concepts for C-UAS operations, providing recommendations based on qualitative/quantitative findings to stakeholders.  Supported organizations include JS, all Services, Combatant Commands, DHS, and select U.S. and foreign acquisition programs (both fielded &amp; emerging technologies).

(12)	Squad-X – Provided quantitative/qualitative data collection and analysis to baseline current U.S. small unit mission command technologies in support of DARPA’s Squad-X project.  This baseline objectively describes the accuracy, completeness, and timeliness of current capabilities, as well as their interoperability with current/future Mission Partner Environments.  Technologies injected in follow-on phases of the project will be measured against this baseline, supporting future development and procurement decisions based on measurable improvements in effectiveness and interoperability. 

(13)	CAS JT&amp;E – Leading DOT&amp;E effort for Digitally-Aided Close Air Support (DACAS) Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures (TTPs) Standardization development. The nomination, endorsed by all Services and USSOCOM, resulted in implementation of the DACAS TTP Standardization Joint Test with Joint Deployable Analysis Team (JDAT) tasked to direct and support these efforts.

(14)	Bold Quest Technical Demonstration – Designed, built, accredited, and managed the Bold Quest exercise networks for US and coalition partners.  Enabled actions include establishment of transport nodes, institution of quality of service policies, cross domain services, sustainment of network core services, data collection from remote and field nodes, Voice over IP services, joining procedures, and all required documentation.

(15)	BOLD Quest Exercise Analysis – Conducted evaluations of demonstrated Joint/Coalition capabilities, resulting in detailed analysis of interoperability gaps and integration shortfalls relating to the following:  Joint Fires Capabilities, Coalition Intelligence, Surveillance, and Reconnaissance (CISR), Digitally Aided Close Air Support (DACAS), and Joint Close Air Support (JCAS).  Results inform U.S. Joint, all Services, and Coalition (to include NATO) partner decisions to field interoperable and integrated capabilities.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>12.898</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Conduct interoperability assessments and analysis in both field and persistent environments that evaluate capability and interoperability of fielded and emerging command, control, communications, computers, and cyber (C5), systems in response to operational issues and shortfalls.  FY 2017 focus areas include: Command and Control, Counter UAS, Joint Fires, Mission Partner Environment, and operations in Cyberspace Capability Development. This includes the impact of technology advances in wireless devices, modem technology, RF communications, and small secure digital capabilities on warfighter command and control capabilities to match emerging requirements with near-term technology solutions. 

Projects include:  
(1)	Bold Quest 2017 Technical Demonstration – Design, build, accreditation, assessment, and management of the exercise networks for US and coalition partners. 
(2)	Counter-UAS (C-UAS) – Data collection and analysis during BLACK DART or similar events. 
(3)	Small Unit Joint C2 Capabilities – Quantitative/qualitative data collection and analysis of DARPA’s Squad-X project. 
(4)	Joint Expeditionary Integration C5ISR Integration Kit Assessments – Integrate and assess emerging technologies, respond to issues reported from operating forces, and support the transition of SOF “best practices” to conventional forces and acquisition programs.  
(5)	4G LTE Security as a Commercial Solutions for Classified (CSfC) Security Layer 4G LTE CSfC Pilot – In partnership with the NSA, integrate and demonstrate the viability of using the native security of LTE as a security layer for the transmission of classified information.
(6)	Automated NATO Database Interface (ANDI) Interoperability Assessment – Continue to assess the automated exchange of targeting data between the US Joint Targeting Toolbox (JTT) and the NATO Joint Targeting System (JTS) which reduces manpower requirements and data entry errors by automating the transfer of targeting data.
(7)	HAMMERHEAD JCTD (P) and Mounted Long-Term Evolution (LTE) Node Technical Integration Assessment (MOLTEN Dragon) – Conduct a technical assessment of multi-purpose airborne pods supporting tactical and SATCOM communications, tactical datalinks, and intelligence sensors.
(8)	Classified Reconfigurable Operational Wireless Network (CROWN) Capability Integration – Develop and assess a deployable secure “Campus” wireless architecture based on layered software encryption in partnership with the National Security Agency (NSA).
(9)	Proximity Lock Technology (PLT) Integration Assessment – Assess a proximity and heart beat dependent data-at-rest automatic locking capability for classified tactical mobile devices, partnership with NSA.
(10)	Virtual Enterprise Mobile Security (VEMS) Integrated Solutions – Assess the usability/functionality of the Hypori Virtual Mobile Infrastructure (VMI) as a way to enable classified tactical communications on unclassified end-user devices, partnership with NSA.
(11)	Coalition Interoperability Assurance  and Validation (CIAV) – Resolute Support Mission – Afghanistan (RSMA) Assessments – Support ongoing overseas operations through continued interoperability assessments of coalition systems supporting coalition mission threads.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>12.898</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>12.898</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Conduct interoperability assessments and analysis in both field and persistent environments that evaluate capability and interoperability of fielded and emerging command, control, communications, computers, and cyber (C5) systems in response to operational issues and shortfalls. A comprehensive Joint Task Force (JTF) environment will support the integration and operational assessment process and support cyber training, capability development and assessments, separately and in coordination with the Department of Defense Cyber Range Environment (DECRE). This is achieved by maintaining a persistent C5 laboratory environment that allows for a rapidly reconfigurable joint, coalition, and inter-agency interoperability assessments, including participation in the Coalition Interoperability and Assurance Validation (CIAV) which supports on-going war efforts. In a live setting, a deployable capability allows the collection and analysis of decision quality data for command and control operations from the operational to lowest tactical echelons of command.  This objective, joint analysis supports capability development, acquisition, and systems employment decisions based on quantifiable performance in replicated operational environments.  FY 2018 focus areas include: Capability development in Command and Control, Mission Partner Environment (Federated and Virtual), Joint Fires Support, and operations in Cyberspace, plus Joint Test and Evaluation of Digitally Aided Close Air Support (DACAS). C5 Assessments and Analyses activities are conducted through both: persistent, reconfigurable C5 laboratories that connect joint and coalition system of systems operational environments to other virtual, constructive, and live environments across national and multi-national operational, research, and test networks leveraging operational venues/exercises; and, a deployable assessment capability (including contested joint environments) that allows range instrumentation and the collection and analysis of quantitative data in replicated operational environments. 

 Projects include:

(1)	Coalition Interoperability Assurance Validation (CIAV) Assessments – Conduct interoperability assessments of coalition systems supporting coalition mission threads.  CIAV assessments validate complete and timely exchange of critical information and improve overall interoperability allowing Coalition forces to fight more effectively and efficiently.
(2)	Advanced Tactical Wireless Integration Capability (ATWIC) – Perform technical integration and assessments of advanced communication systems hardware, software, and security solutions to identify capabilities that address warfighter requirements.
(3)	Joint Fires Support Joint Mission Thread (JFS JMT) Interoperability Assessment – Assess Joint and Coalition fire support command and control systems digital (machine-to-machine) interoperability and provide findings and observations.
(4)	Advanced Wide Area Network Security (AWANS) Capability Integration – Demonstrate an integrated wide area network security solution using NSA approved Commercial Solution for Classified virtual private networks between two or more sites.
(5)	Cyber Guard (CG)/Cyber Flag (CF) 2018 Assessment and Technical Support – Provide C2 systems, a common operational picture, and conduct assessment of cyber effects on these systems integrated into the Navy Defensive Cyber Operation DoD Information Network (DoDIN) Simulation, Training, and Exercise Platform (STEP) environment.
(6)	Bold Quest 2018 Technical Demonstration – Design, build, accreditation, assessment and management of the exercise networks for U.S. and coalition partners.
(7)	Counter-UAS (C-UAS) – Data collection and analysis during BLACK DART or similar FY18 events.
(8)	C2 Systems Support to DoD Enterprise Cyber Range Environment – Provide a persistent and distributed cyber environment for cyber mission forces development.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Biannual review of C4/Cyber resources includes an examination of the current and future Budget/Spend Plan, Lines of Effort and Acquisition Strategy.

The award of a Multi Award Contract (MAC) seeks efficiencies in the performance of requirements for C4/Cyber and Information services, and promotes contractor teaming to provide critical technical and management support.  The MAC approach also seeks to reduce the costs of current contract support through the elimination of multiple fees for service contracts, and through the competitive award of contract services.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>(1) Conduct a minimum of fifteen (15) interoperability assessments designed to identify Joint and Coalition interoperability issues and recommend fixes/solutions to Program Managers, Combatant Commands, all Services, and Agencies.

(2) Conduct a minimum of one (1) broad-spectrum Counter-UAS (C-UAS) analysis event; providing data collection, analysis, and recommendations that directly address identified C-UAS capability gaps and interoperability shortfalls for partners including: Joint, all Services, Intergovernmental, and Coalition stakeholders.

(3) Provide C2 Systems and Persistent command, control, communications, and computers (C4) Environment supporting at least two (2) Combatant Command Exercises to satisfy Combatant Command training objectives, including the cyber threat to mission systems.

(4) Support up to four (4) Squad-X experiment events, providing objective analysis on performance and interoperability that directly informs the acquisition of improved C2 capabilities for U.S. small units. 

(5) Support a minimum of thirty (30) Coalition Interoperability Assurance and Validation (CIAV) events and provide a minimum of one hundred (100) observations/findings to resolve end-to-end mission based interoperability issues, validate Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures, and support NATO Future Mission Networking (FMN) and U.S. Mission Partner Environment (MPE) implementation plans.

(6) Provide analyses for at least six (6) field assessments/demonstrations in the areas of Joint Fires Capabilities, C2, CISR, DACAS, and FMN/MPE.  Analyses results will inform continued development of evaluated capabilities, including acquisition/fielding decisions and system TTPs.  

(7) Provide C2 Systems and Persistent C4 Environment supporting at least four (4) individual/team training events per year to meet Cyber training and certification objectives.

(8) Provide C2 Systems and Persistent C4 Environment to support at least four (4) Cyber Assessments promoting Cyber capability development.

(9)  Integrate at least two (2) new capabilities per year supporting Combatant Command, Service, Agency, and Commercial Solutions for Classified and Mobile Computing program requirements.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    <r2:R3Exhibit>
                        <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                <r2:Name>Test and Evaluation</r2:Name>
                                <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:Name>Contract Management and Engineering Technical Services</r2:Name>
                                        <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                        <r2:ContractType>CPFF</r2:ContractType>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivity>Various</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Norfolk, Suffolk, Eglin</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                        <r2:Cost>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:Amount>10.196</r2:Amount>
                                                <r2:AwardDate>2016-03</r2:AwardDate>
                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:Amount>12.898</r2:Amount>
                                                <r2:AwardDate>2016-10</r2:AwardDate>
                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:Amount>12.898</r2:Amount>
                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:Amount>12.898</r2:Amount>
                                                <r2:AwardDate>2017-10</r2:AwardDate>
                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        </r2:Cost>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                        </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                    </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    <r2:R4aExhibit>
                        <r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                            <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                <r2:Title>Joint C5I</r2:Title>
                                <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>C5 Assessments and Analyses</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2018</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2018</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                            </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                        </r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                    </r2:R4aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>C5 Capability Development</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>7.079</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>6.594</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>6.590</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>6.590</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>6.637</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>6.637</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>6.637</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>6.637</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Lead C2 capability development and integration in order to achieve an interdependent joint force. This will be accomplished through four focus areas:
Capability Development, C4 Architectures, Data and Services, and Interoperability and Integration.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>C5 Capability Development</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Lead C2 capability development and integration in order to achieve an interdependent joint force. This will be accomplished through four focus areas: 
Capability Development, C4 Architectures, Data and Services, and Interoperability and Integration.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>7.079</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Led C2 capability development and integration to achieve an interdependent joint force. This was accomplished through four focus areas:

(1) Capability Development – Joint Staff lead and Requirements Working Group lead for DoD CIO &amp; OSD/AT&amp;L – directed Business Case Analysis (BCA) for a proposed $99M recapitalization of the Global Command and Control System – Joint (GCCS-J) – a cyber enhanced Enterprise Common Operational Picture to facilitate globally integrated operations. Led Combatant Command (CCMD) command and control (C2) Integrated Priority List Capability Gap Analysis review and Operational Priorities analysis for FY18-22 identifying key warfighter requirements resulting in JROC approval. Executed CJCSI 3265.01 – directed requirements and validation duties for Joint C2 Governance and Management.  Results included:  additional DoD-compliant web browsers for Navy – Marine Corps Internet (NMCI); COP overlays for Google Earth users; consolidated management of Deployable Joint C2 kits; JROC validation of Air Operations Center Weapons System (AOC WS) modernization efforts; Combatant Command and Service collaboration on structural changes to targeting databases; formalized requirements management for Situational Awareness Services in the Joint C2 portfolio; and a warfighter assessment of the Defense Collaboration Services (DCS).

(2) C4 Architectures - Expanded the scope of Joint Information Environment (JIE) and DoD CIO architecture content on the Warfighting Mission Area (WMA) Architecture Portal by 30% and increased the user base by 30% from 5200 to 7000+ users. Staffed, analyzed and validated 51 JIE Architectures ranging from solutions architectures, Engineering Design Specifications and reference architectures in collaboration with CCMDs. Developed selected architectures and design specifications in support of JIE capability objectives.  Assisted in the development of the JIE Security Classification Guide to provide classification guidance for DoDIN architecture and engineering practices. Produced six mission thread architectures, enabling the definition and evaluation of System of System architecture attributes, covering Cyberspace Operations, Joint Suppression of Enemy Air Defense (2 threads), Homeland Security Border Security Operations, Humanitarian Assistance/Disaster Relief, and Intelligence Enabling. Conducted three analytical studies related to Joint Suppression of Enemy Air Defense. Supported NATO in the creation of guidelines and methodology for development of mission threads.

(3) Data and Services - Developed an updated Federal Government vetted and approved National Information Exchange Model Military Operations Domain that was successfully demonstrated and used by DOD, Department of Homeland Security and NATO member nations for increased Command and Control interoperability.  Established and began execution of a DOD campaign plan to align and provide warfighter interoperability across five different existing command and control tactical and messaging data standards now in operational use by DOD and mission partners. Developed and submitted for formal DOD vetting and approval, a command and control cyber symbology Military Standard to provide standardized C2 Common Operational Picture representations in a transregional threat environment across Combatant Commands.

(4) Interoperability and Integration - Led the development and implementation of improved Combatant Command (CCMD) unity of effort and speed of command with mission partners known as Mission Partner Environment (MPE) by developing requirements and standards for Unclassified Information Sharing Services (UISS), development of the annual MPE Action Plan, and integration of MPE into Senior Leader and Joint Professional Military Education (JPME) programs, Joint Doctrine and Joint Training. Shaped NATO’s Federated Mission Networking (FMN) implementation to maintain alignment with MPE, through participating as the Flag/General Officer/SES level U.S. representative to the FMN Management Group and providing U.S. representatives to the FMN working groups that coordinate FMN capability development, Coalition Interoperability Assurance and Validation (CIAV), Joining, Membership and Exit Instructions (JMEI) development, cyber security, training, and other interoperability activities across 27 NATO and 6 non-NATO nations which are implementing FMN.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>6.594</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>(1) Capability Development – Continue to serve as direct liaison between operational users and materiel developers throughout the capability lifecycle, to include prioritization of requirement and development efforts.  Manage the Net-Enabled Requirements Identification Database (NRID) and the Decision Support Tool (DST) to provide accessibility and visibility into C2 capability needs and potential solutions.  Develop and seek JROC approval of FY 2019/2020 Joint C2 Operational Requirements based upon top-down Integrated Priorities List and bottom-up warfighter requirements.  Host three Joint C2 Integration Workshops to synchronize Joint C2 materiel development efforts.  Coordinate with the warfighter community, to include multinational and other mission partners, to identify common requirements and priorities, as well as materiel and non-materiel solutions to address similar/common needs and capability gaps.  Produce/coordinate an Information System-Capability Development Document (IS-CDD) for an Enterprise Common Operational Picture capability for JROC approval.  Further, produce Capability Definition Packages and subordinate Capability Packages for Targeting and Geospatial Intelligence, Maritime Tactical C2, Unified Action Plan COP, Operational Design and Joint Planning Process, Joint Friendly Force Tracking, and Enterprise Force Structure.  Coordinate assessment of newly developed Command and Control of the Operational Environment capabilities. Facilitate collaboration between GCCS-J and AOC WS program offices to ensure synchronized release of capabilities with effective data exchanges.  Facilitate warfighter prioritization of GCCS-J Global COP requirements for incremental capability development and release.

(2) C4 Architectures - Improve WMA Architecture Portal usability and develop a basic set of architecture analysis and visualization tools and services. Continue to improve the quality of and expand the amount of the C4/Cyber portfolio architecture information available on the WMA Architecture Portal.  Establish and populate Joint Staff Protection and Force Application Functional Capability Board (FCB) portfolio architecture content on the WMA Architecture Portal to facilitate architecture information sharing, integration, analysis, and re-use. Validate JIE architectures, functional requirements documents and engineering design specifications to increase compliance with JIE architecture standards and metrics across DOD. Assist in the analysis of FYDP 2019 - 2023 Capability Gap Assessment (CGA), specifically the FCB IPL Review and the CGA gaps. Revise the Joint C2 Reference Architecture in conjunction with DISA Services Development Directorate. Align Joint Mission Thread guidance/governance/production priorities to Chairman’s priorities. Provide analytical support to the Chairman’s Joint Military Net Assessment and the Chairman’s Net Assessment. Support coalition partner efforts to define and develop mission threads.

(3) Data and Services - Develop, promote and integrate data and services requirements, standards, technical specifications, and policy to support improved warfighter interoperability and information sharing with joint, mission partners and other U.S. Government departments and agencies. Collaborate with Allied Command Transformation (NATO) to develop the NATO Core Data Framework as a means to achieve coalition interoperability. Align and standardize emerging Tactical Data Link and Messaging standards with enterprise information sharing.  Develop and promulgate a major release of the National Information Exchange Data Model, Military Operations domain. Refine and mature enterprise IT service lifecycle management processes and procedures with the DoD CIO and Services.

(4) Interoperability and Integration – Support emergent cyber priorities throughout all Department focus areas by performing analysis and assessments and support the development of the Persistent Training Environment (PTE) to emulate the C4/cyberspace domain. Support C4/cyber system developers with operational/developmental Cyber Security testing and assessment, including integration of data collection and analysis instrumentation. Continue to lead the implementation of improved Combatant Command (CCMD) unity of effort and speed of command with mission partners through enhanced information sharing with partner nations by leading the continuing implementation of the JROC approved Future Mission Network 90 Day Study recommendations (known as Mission Partner Environment (MPE)). Facilitate use of force development events as operational environment opportunities to further explore and validate the potential for MPE concepts (e.g. virtualization of CENTRIX networks in exercises STEADFAST COBALT and JUDICIOUS RESPONSE). Support the deployment of a federated enduring MPE capability within the CCMDs. Lead the development and maturation of DoD MPE Joining Instructions providing the joint force a baseline technical document for establishing federated mission networks.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>6.590</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>6.590</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>1) Capability Development – Continue to sustain and utilize the Net-Enabled Requirements Identification Database (NRID) and the Decision Support Tool (DST) to provide accessibility and visibility into C2 capability needs and potential solutions for C2 stakeholders and materiel developers.  Develop/coordinate the annual Joint C2 Operational Priorities for JROC approval, and host four Joint C2 Integration Workshops. Align capability requirements and JCIDS documentation to enable material solution development, and ensure warfighter equities are represented through Joint C2 Governance and Management forums and formal processes. Develop Capability Definition Packages and Capability Packages to support on-going Enterprise COP, Command and Control Information Exchange (C2IE), and Joint Planning Services capabilities, and develop warfighter assessment criteria for same. Update CJCSI/M 3265.01, “Joint C2 Governance and Management,” to strengthen requirements management for enterprise-level, globally integrated operations.  Ensure requirements development efforts include architecture, data, cross-functional, cyber, and Joint Information Environment capability areas and equities. Implement plans and schedules to assess Enterprise COP incrementally developed capabilities.

(2) C4 Architectures – Update the WMA Architecture Development Standards to meet emerging JCIDS process improvements. Provide foundational components of the WMA Enterprise Architecture by populating the WMA Architecture Portal with all relevant and available FCB portfolio Areas/Communities of Interest architecture content. Improve the WMA Architecture Portal for the Combatant Command, services and DoD agencies by broadening access, integration, reusability and information sharing of architecture artifacts and data sets through federation and standardized data exchanges National Information Exchange Model (NIEM).  Provide architecture development and analysis efforts as required to support the Chairman's directed focus areas and Lines of Operations.

(3) Data and Services – Continue to develop, promote, and integrate data and services requirements, standards, technical specifications, and policy to support improved warfighter interoperability and information sharing with joint, mission partners and other U.S. Government departments and agencies. Socialize and perform proof of concept activities of the NATO Core Data Framework, to achieve coalition interoperability and demonstrate operational effectiveness. Continue to align and standardize emerging Tactical Data Link and Messaging standards with enterprise information sharing. Support the implementation of NIEM as the common interoperability information exchange standard for new IT services. In coordination with the DoD CIO, implement IT enterprise service lifecycle management processes, procedures, and capabilities.

(4) Interoperability and Integration – Support cyber priorities throughout all Department focus areas by performing analysis, assessments and supporting materiel developers. Review and monitor the continued development of the MPE-Information System (MPE-IS) to ensure it meets the operational requirements of the CCMDs and Services. Continue to shape FMN implementation to ensure it remains aligned with MPE, including related capability development (e.g. Spiral 2.0 specifications and risk mitigation activities that leverage CIAV and the BOLD QUEST capability demonstration) and FMN Framework JMEIs that are complementary to DoD MPE Joining Instructions. Support development and maturation of DECRE C2IS to support US and Coalition cyber force readiness, cyber defense of coalition networks, integration, interoperability, and survivability of Mission Partner Environment.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Biannual review of C4/Cyber resources includes an examination of the current and future Budget/Spend Plan, Lines of Effort, and Acquisition Strategy.

The award of a Multi Award Contract (MAC) seeks efficiencies in the performance of requirements for C4/Cyber and Information services, and promotes contractor teaming to provide critical technical and management support.  The MAC approach also seeks to reduce the costs of current contract support through the elimination of multiple fees for service contracts, and through the competitive award of contract services.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>1) Secure JROC approval of the FY 2019 Joint C2 operational priorities defining C2 capability needs/gaps providing senior level oversight and direction to Joint C2 capability development.

(2) Secure DoD approval for seven (7) JCIDS requirements documents to support materiel development of Joint C2, Adaptive Planning/Execution, Global-Theater Security Cooperation, Readiness, and Cross Functional information technology capabilities enabling timely delivery of materiel solutions to meet warfighter capability needs/gaps.

(3) Ensure Joint C2 requirements development supports the DoD-directed Better Buying Power 100% by continuing the rapid development and fielding of virtualized C2 system capabilities to CCMDs and Services, i.e., GCCS-J Global (COP &amp; I3), Agile Client – an x86 (PC-based) infrastructure, Enterprise Widget Storefront for web access of Joint C2 data and applications, Joint Planning and Execution Services to replace legacy systems.  

(4) Provide two (2) planned releases of Global-Theater Security Cooperation Management Information System (G-TSCMIS) capability on both NIPRnet &amp; SIPRnet for CCMDs/Services allowing G-TSCMIS use in a disconnected, intermittent, or limited bandwidth (DIL) environment, as well as providing an initial cross domain data exchange capability between security levels.

(5) Validate the architectures and engineering design specifications for twenty-seven (27) JIE and MPE projects.

(6) Conduct three (3) National Information Exchange Model Military Operations Domain Configuration Control Board sessions to improve and increase information sharing via promulgation of one Domain content update.

(7) Lead a minimum of six (6) Enterprise Service and Data Panels (ESDP) with the goal to improve and increase the interoperability and reusability of DOD Enterprise Services and Authoritative Data Sources.

(8)  Include mission partnering concepts in four (4) Combatant Command and Service exercises.

(9)  Establish at least two (2) new or enhanced information/sharing and collaboration areas NLT 30 Jun 18.

(10) Establish and refine processes and procedures to ensure FMN implementation is included in two (2) NATO exercises.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>003</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Fires C2 Interoperability</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>4.425</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>4.150</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.150</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.150</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>4.150</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>4.150</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>4.150</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>4.150</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Lead interoperability efforts across DoD and partner nations at the operational and tactical level for mission partner operations, fire support, Combat Identification (CID), and Friendly Force Tracking (FFT) capabilities. Conduct Joint Fire Support (JFS)/Joint Close Air Support (JCAS) and CID-FFT action plans to fulfill CJCSI-directed, General Officer/Flag Officer (GOFO) level responsibilities. Conduct JFS Executive Steering Committee (ESC) standardization team accreditation visits to U.S. and partner nation schoolhouses to ensure Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) signatories are accomplishing schoolhouse training in compliance with the Memorandas.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Joint Fires C2 Interoperability</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Execute Joint Staff-sponsored Bold Quest systems-of-systems interoperability assessment, including integration of Cyber capabilities with command and control of Conventional and Special Operations Force missions from a multinational perspective at the tactical level. These efforts directly support 2014 Quadrennial Defense Review and 2016 National Military Strategy goals to increase interoperability with allies and partners.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.425</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Conducted Joint Staff sponsored Bold Quest Coalition Capability Demonstration and Assessment involving fourteen (14) nations, all U.S. Services and U.S. Special Operations Command successfully expanding utility of Mission Partner Environment concepts; the integration of ground-to-air situational awareness capabilities; integrated air &amp; missile defense threads; and digitally enhanced call-for-fire and close air support operations through live, virtual, construction dismounted operations at Ft Stewart, GA and Savannah, GA.

Led accreditation visits to ten (10) Joint Terminal Attack Controller (JTAC); 1 Forward Air Controller (Airborne); and 7 Joint Fires Observer (JFO) Schoolhouses. Accreditation of U.S. and partner nation schoolhouses ensured trained and qualified personnel meet standardized performance metrics, enabling enhanced trust and interoperability during current and future combat operations.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.150</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Execute Joint Staff-sponsored Bold Quest systems-of-systems interoperability assessment, including integration of Cyber and ISR capabilities with command and control of Conventional and Special Operations Force missions from a multinational perspective at the tactical level. Continue incorporating Mission Partner Environment concepts to increase Allied and coalition interoperability. These efforts directly support the 2016 National Military Strategy and the CJCS’ focus areas. Continue leading accreditation visits of current JFS ESC member programs and provided staff assistance for development of new start close air support-related training and certification programs.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.150</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.150</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Plan and execute Joint Staff-sponsored Bold Quest 2018 systems-of-systems interoperability assessment, including integration of Cyber and ISR capabilities with command and control of Conventional and Special Operations Force missions from a multinational perspective at the tactical level. These efforts directly support the 2016 National Military Strategy and the CJCS’ focus areas. Continue leading accreditation visits of current JFS ESC member programs and provided staff assistance for development of close air support-related training and certification programs.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Biannual review of C4/Cyber resources includes an examination of the current and future Budget/Spend Plan, Lines of Effort and Acquisition Strategy.

The award of a Multi Award Contract (MAC) seeks efficiencies in the performance of requirements for C4/Cyber and Information services, and promotes contractor teaming to provide critical technical and management support.  The MAC approach also seeks to reduce the costs of current contract support through the elimination of multiple fees for service contracts, and through the competitive award of contract services.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>1) Lead development of situational awareness and cooperative/non-cooperative identification capabilities that enable U.S. and NATO/Coalition warfighters to identify friendly, enemy, and neutral forces for “shoot/don’t shoot” decisions.

(2) Synchronize Service testing, acquisition and fielding of Mode 5 IFF capability, with focus on Full Operational Capability (FOC) in 2020. Monitor Service fielding progress of one hundred sixty-nine (169) platform types.

(3) Complete Definition Package for Block 2 of Digitally Aided Close Air Support (DACAS) coordinated implementation in conjunction with participating Service programs of record. Effort will enable over twenty (20) U.S. and partner nation systems to be more interoperable in the CAS mission area.

(4) Expand digital call-for-fire solution development to include enhanced multi-national interoperability with six (6) partner nations.

(5) Conduct Accreditation Assessments for fourteen (14) of thirty current signatory schoolhouses (8 Joint Terminal Attack Controller (JTAC), 2 Forward Air Controller (Airborne), and 4 Joint Fires Observer (JFO) Schoolhouses).

(6) Lead development and refinement of four (4) U.S. and NATO joint fires-related doctrine and Tactics, Techniques, and Procedures (TTP) publications.

(7) Lead planning, coordination and execution of two (2) Bold Quest systems of systems interoperability assessment to facilitate U.S. and coalition integration.

(8) Plan and conduct quarterly Joint Fire Support and Combat ID-Friendly Force Tracking Executive Steering Committee and working group meetings to address identified shortfalls in those mission areas.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605126J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint Integrated Air &amp; Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>145</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2018</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2017-05</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>343.535</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>34.139</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>38.059</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>36.581</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>36.581</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>36.469</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>33.901</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>33.500</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>33.500</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization(JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Integrated Air and Missile Defense (IAMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the Joint Staff (JS), JIAMDO supports the Chairman in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to IAMD issues.  JIAMDO is the operational community’s proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in IAMD, and is the joint IAMD proponent within the DoD’s resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads IAMD mission and utility analysis, integrates IAMD within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations, demonstrations of joint IAMD architectures, and provides advocacy for innovative, technically mature, and affordable solutions.  

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with U.S. Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) and U.S. Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  JIAMDO provides the CJCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule, and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in the development of the IAMD Prioritized Capabilities List and the Global Integrated IAMD Assessment and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System.  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM ballistic missile early warning mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to North American Aerospace Defense Command and USNORTHCOM for homeland air and cruise missile surveillance issues and technical oversight of homeland capability solutions.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>33.983</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>32.759</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>32.581</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>32.581</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>34.139</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>38.059</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>36.581</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>36.581</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.156</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>5.300</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:Reprogrammings>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.156</r2:PriorYear>
                    </r2:Reprogrammings>
                    <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Additional Support to P005: Nimble Fire</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>FY17PB Amend: Addition funds for JRICM (JIAMDO-Core)</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:CurrentYear>5.300</r2:CurrentYear>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                    </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>JIAMDO-Core:   JIAMDO moved its offices out of contracted facilities into government-owned facilities and merged its processes with those of the Joint Staff J8, avoiding the need for administrative and security support contracts, rent, and the various support costs associated with rental offices.

JIAMDO-Core (FY17):  $5.3 million is required to address emergency warfighting readiness requirements. Joint Regional IAMD Capability Mix (JRICM) II is a DepSecDef and JROC directed Regional IAMD study, directing the Joint Staff, Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO), in coordination with USSTRATCOM, USCYBERCOM, Intelligence Communities, Agencies and Services to assess the impact of emerging non-kinetic capabilities to supplement regional IAMD.

JIAMDO-Homeland:  Program development and management were handed off to the Air Force. JIAMDO retains only requirements and integration oversight responsibilities not requiring program funding.  

JIAMDO-Nimble Fire:  Increased funding for FY 2018 will be used to hold two large Nimble Fire events in support of U.S. Fleet Forces Command, USPACOM, USSTRATCOM and USEUCOM.  Additionally, funds will be used to improve Electronic Warfare, Multi-spectral Environment, Advanced Capability Model, and Space Warfare.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Core</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>119.901</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>14.339</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>14.329</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>9.343</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>9.343</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>10.271</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>10.271</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>10.476</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>10.476</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense (IAMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the Joint Staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to IAMD issues.  JIAMDO is the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in IAMD, and is the joint IAMD proponent within the DoD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads IAMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates IAMD within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint IAMD architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with USSTRATCOM and USNORTHCOM in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  JIAMDO provides the CJCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule, and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM, and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in development of the IAMD Prioritized Capability List, the Global Integrated IAMD Assessment, and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM ballistic missile early warning mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to North American Aerospace Defense Command and USNORTHCOM for homeland air and cruise missile surveillance issues.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Core</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Provides overall staff support for JIAMDO operations in the area of ballistic missile defense, air and cruise missile defense, homeland defense, requirements management, combat identification, modeling &amp; simulation, all other JIAMDO analytical functions and products, senior level briefings, and all travel costs for government and contractor support personnel (including Combatant Commander liaison personnel).  This includes performing analyses, demonstrations, and programmatic assessments of technology, operations, requirements, and weapons systems.  In coordination with Services and CCMDs, JIAMDO Core also funds the definition, assessment, development, and approval of Joint IAMD Operational Concepts, Operational Architectures, and capability requirements to guide the Department's joint/interagency/combined fully integrated and net-centric capable IAMD (including defense against cruise missiles, unmanned aerial vehicles, and ballistic missiles).  JIAMDO Core also provides funding to:
• Develop and integrate joint studies, simulations, wargames, force resource allocation, and interoperability initiatives
• Manage relevant Congressional interaction and CCMD interface through a cadre of liaisons collocated with major headquarters
• Directly support and sponsor homeland air surveillance related demonstration and analysis activities
• Run the IAMD Working Group and co-chair the Protection Functional Capabilities Board focusing CCMD, Joint Staff, and Service collaboration efforts in generation of joint concepts and development of the IAMD architecture and roadmap
• Develop U.S. positions for, and provide the U.S. head of delegation to, the NATO Air and Missile Defense Committee

JIAMDO Core further enables strategic planning development, infrastructure, security, travel, and other support activities.  Funding pays for: contracted Systems Engineering and Technical Assistance (SETA) support for Air &amp; Cruise Missile Defense (ACMD), Ballistic Missile Defense (BMD), Homeland Air Security (HAS) strategic planning, studies &amp; analysis, combat ID, modeling &amp; simulation, all other JIAMDO analytical functions and products, senior level briefings, and all travel costs for government and contractor support personnel (including Combatant Commander liaison personnel). Additionally, the JIAMDO CORE budget funds daily on-site security management personnel to meet DoD, National Industrial Security Program Operating Manual (NISPOM), and other security regulations, for all administrative and support functions related to higher security classifications, as well as basic office supplies and furniture, and classified/unclassified data connections.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>14.339</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Performed Air and Cruise Missile Defense, and Ballistic Missile Defense directed studies in support of the Chairman and related program support activities including:  contracting, finance, systems engineering and technical assistance, administration, security, communications, leased space, and supply.  Provided contracted expertise in support of studies and analysis directed by Congress, Defense Planning Guidance, Resource Management Decisions, Joint Requirements Oversight Council, and other higher sources.  Additional reductions in contract advisory and assistance services are projected. Awarded new SETA contract in Aug 2016.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>14.329</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Continue performing Ballistic Missile Defense studies as directed by higher authority and provide contracted expertise in support of all JIAMDO analytical and requirements management activities.  Pursue further changes in program support activities as a result of reorganization and office move to the Pentagon.  Ancillary support functions such as administrative, security, communications, Information Technology, and finance will no longer require JIAMDO funding as they will be provided by the JS. Systems Engineering and Technical Assistance contract will still be in place to provide necessary mission support.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>9.343</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>9.343</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Continue performing Ballistic Missile Defense studies as directed by higher authority and provide contracted expertise in support of all JIAMDO analytical and requirements management activities.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>(1) Support two major Nimble Fire exercises during FY 2018.

(2) Conduct two IAMD Working Groups and at least one Functional Capabilities Board per month.

(3) Conduct the annual Black Dart Counter-Unmanned Aerial System technology demonstration.

(4) Support U.S. Representative to NATO Air Defense Council and Missile Defense Committee including 2 overseas meetings per year and numerous lower-level supporting functions.

(5) Develop and maintain operational architecture compliance with DoD Architectural Framework (DODAF) standards.

(6) Ensure 100% of all government employee travel is in accordance with the Joint Federal Travel Regulation/Joint Travel Regulation and all contractor travel is in accordance with applicable regulations.

(7) Maintain all unclassified/classified LANs on a daily basis in accordance with the Joint Staff's Office of the Chief Information Officer guidance/policy.

(8) Ensure all computers, NIPRNET/SIPRNET, are refreshed according to applicable policy/guidance.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Homeland</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>1</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>67.544</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Homeland program transitioned to a USAF-led Program of Record across the Future Year Defense Program in the beginning of FY 2016.  JIAMDO will retain operational and requirements oversight.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P003</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Black Dart</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>23.039</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>2.444</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>3.300</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.300</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.366</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.366</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense (IAMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the Joint Staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to IAMD issues.  JIAMDO is the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in IAMD, and is the joint IAMD proponent within the DoD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint IAMD architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with U.S. Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) and U.S. Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  JIAMDO provides the CJCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule, and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in development of the IAMD Prioritized Capability List, the Global Integrated Air and Missile Defense Assessment, and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM ballistic missile early warning mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to North American Aerospace Defense Command and USNORTHCOM for homeland air and cruise missile surveillance issues.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Black Dart Counter Unmanned Aircraft Systems Technology Demonstration</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Provides funding to support administration and execution of Black Dart demonstrations. Black Dart is a unique joint, interagency demonstration focusing on rapid development and implementation of Counter - Unmanned Aircraft Systems (CUAS) technology from readily-available commercial and governmental products.  Objectives include:
•	Execute live-fly, live-fire CUAS technology demonstration to assess and validate existing and emerging Integrated Air and Missile Defense  (IAMD) capabilities
•	Present emerging solutions to inform requirements decision-making 
•	Identify and develop IAMD operational concepts, system interoperability, and operational architectures for the CUAS mission set
•	Advocate for Warfighters’ desired CUAS capabilities and affordable, integrated solutions</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.444</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Most tactically relevant BLACK DART to date:
•	Flew 355 sorties from 25 different UAS variants
•	Flew tactical ISR and Attack flight profiles from 16 geographically dispersed launch locations
•	Developed detailed threat scenarios based on direct input from Combatant Commanders to provide specific recommendations on materiel and non-materiel requirements to the warfighter
•	Created a contested electromagnetic spectrum for CUAS sensors
  Provided a venue for rapid capability delivery to the Warfighter:
•	Developed innovative materiel and non-materiel solutions that enhance all phases of the Joint Engagement Sequence versus the UAS threat
•	Refined non-kinetic negation system techniques and capabilities through 89 separate negation events
  Provided a venue for innovation and collaboration:
•	Expanded interagency participation to demonstrate C-UAS options in both Title 10 and Title 50 operational environments
•	Multiple cross-governmental development programs were exercised to include DoD/DoE and DoD/DHS
•	Increased observation from coalition partners from the Pacific operational theater</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>3.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Continue FY 2016 plans including: Demonstrate UAS capabilities to employ within visual range (WVR) and beyond visual range (BVR) weapons in a counter-UAS role.  Explore ‘On-the-Move’ capabilities.  Expand the breadth, complexity, and integration of cyber capabilities. Expand scenarios to include dynamic and contested electromagnetic spectrum.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>3.000</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>3.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Continue FY 2017 Plans including: Expand coalition partner participation. Develop scenarios integrating systems across land, littoral, and maritime domains.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>(1) Complete events within schedule and budget. Events provide useful data to improve C-UAS capability.

(2) Document gaps, develop and substantiate hardware, software, and employment concepts.

(3) Field C-UAS capability.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P004</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Distributed Engineering Plant</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>14.248</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>3.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>2.500</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.738</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.738</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>2.900</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>2.475</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>2.533</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>2.533</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense (IAMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the Joint Staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to IAMD issues.  JIAMDO is the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in IAMD, and is the joint IAMD proponent within the DoD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint IAMD architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with U.S. Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) and U.S. Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  JIAMDO provides the CJCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule, and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in development of the IAMD Prioritized Capability List, the Global Integrated Air and Missile Defense Assessment, and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM ballistic missile early warning mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to North American Aerospace Defense Command and USNORTHCOM for homeland air and cruise missile surveillance issues.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Joint Distributed Engineering Plant (JDEP)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Conducted a joint test event to assess the interoperability of joint, IAMD weapon systems that leveraged commercial-off-the-shelf (COTS) Networks to perform Joint Integrated Fire Control. This effort provided users the means to create family-of-system (FoS) environments by linking existing capabilities using hardware, software, and operators in a live-fly environment.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>3.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Fund an appropriate joint distributed test event to assess the interoperability of joint, IAMD weapons systems. Provide users the means to create FoS environments by linking existing capabilities using hardware, software, and operator-in-the-loop. Link existing Service and Joint combat system engineering and test sites via distributed communications.  Conducted a high-fidelity weapons system hardware-in-the-loop Coalition Correlation/Decorrelation Interoperability Test (C/DIT) which identified and accelerated change to the Military Standard 6016 default parameter values, promoting increased IAMD interoperability across the joint and Allied link networks.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.500</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Fund an appropriate joint/coalition IAMD interoperability program and test event to link Service and Agency systems, providing test and evaluations to improve the Joint Common Tactical Airspace Picture (CTAP). Supervise and conduct a live, virtual and constructive test event utilizing real-world C-UAS data within a hardware-in-the-loop model to improve L16 network IAMD communications; determine IAMD capability requirements and verify architectures; improve interoperability and ensure IAMD of current weapon systems; and evaluate concepts of operations and tactics, techniques, and procedures.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.738</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.738</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Fund an appropriate joint distributed test event to assess the interoperability of joint, IAMD weapons systems. Provide users the means to create FoS environments by linking existing capabilities using hardware, software, and operator-in-the-loop. Link existing Service and Joint combat system engineering and test sites via distributed communications.  Reduce developmental cycle times by leveraging existing facilities.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>(1)  Each JDEP event develops measures of effectiveness (MOE) &amp; measures of performance (MOP) based on an eighteen month test planning and event process.
(2)  Complete events within schedule and budget. 
(3)  Events provide useful data to improve Air Missile Defense interoperability, with implemented and recommended corrective changes.
(4)  Events must be linked to the current approved IAMD Architecture, provide joint benefit, contribute to Joint Interoperability, and address IAMD ICD capability gaps.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P005</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Nimble Fire</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>61.539</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>8.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>12.230</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>16.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>16.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>14.500</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>13.500</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>12.650</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>12.650</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense (IAMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the Joint Staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to IAMD issues.  JIAMDO is the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in IAMD, and is the joint IAMD proponent within the DoD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint IAMD architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with U.S. Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) and U.S. Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  JIAMDO provides the CJCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule, and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in development of the IAMD Prioritized Capability List, the Global Integrated Air and Missile Defense Assessment, and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM ballistic missile early warning mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to North American Aerospace Defense Command and USNORTHCOM for homeland air and cruise missile surveillance issues.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>JIAMDO Nimble Fire</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>The Deputy Secretary of Defense assigned responsibility for IAMD development at the Virtual Warfare Center to JIAMDO.  Nimble Fire is the Department’s only joint IAMD operator-in-the-loop modeling and simulation capability exploring the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff’s top 5 most critical Joint IAMD capabilities: wide-area surveillance and engagement quality tracking, pre-launch interdiction, non-kinetic post-launch capabilities, ballistic missile discrimination, and increased weapons ranges and lethality.  Nimble Fire events explore joint IAMD capabilities and concepts in the FYDP (+2) timeframe combining experienced operators from the tactical communities, virtual simulations accredited by the program offices, current and future advanced capabilities, an integrated air, ballistic and cruise missile threat, and informed scenarios from the Department’s analytical agenda and CCMD operational plans.  JIAMDO brings together stakeholders across the engineering, analytical, and tactical communities to conduct multiple events to assess Joint interoperability of Service and MDA programs of record, explore concepts of employment, inform tactics, techniques and procedures and concepts of operation, provide insights that help shape CCMD integrated priorities and future operational plans, and inform senior leader acquisition and requirements decisions.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>8.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>In response to JROC tasking, JIAMDO built upon FY 2015 accomplishments executing two Nimble Fire events in FY 2016 in support of the Services, MDA, USEUCOM, USPACOM, and USSTRATCOM and providing funding and personnel that were instrumental in successfully executing two additional events in support of the Joint Strike Fighter Joint Project Office (JSF JPO) and the Navy respectively.  Across all four events executed in FY 2016, Nimble Fire project resulted in significant cost-avoidance for the Department and Services through identifying real-world system issues, supporting live venues, and providing the backbone simulation environment for other users.  Major accomplishments include:
•	Identifying real-world issues on multiple systems including E-2, E-3, Integrated Air and Missile Defense Battle Command System (IBCS), and F-15. Issues fed back to program offices to take corrective action
•	Impact of advanced capabilities on tactical fight (details classified)
•	Human-machine and Link-16 network challenges associated with executing integrated fire control kill chains
•	Potential benefits of future sensors, weapons and capabilities (e.g., next generation jammer (NGJ), airborne early warning)
•	Concepts of employment (CONEMPS) for 4th and 5th generation fighters employing with F-35 Joint Strike Fighter to inform Service tactics, techniques and procedures (e.g., Air Force 3-1) 
•	USMC operator feedback on CAC2S tactical display and CTN interface identified key limitations with respect to track functionality 
•	Continued exploration of Naval Integrated Fire Control – Counter Air (NIFC-CA) related kill chains (details classified)</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>12.230</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Execute two Nimble Fire events in support of U.S. Fleet Forces Command, USPACOM, USSTRATCOM and USEUCOM.  Provide material support for two additional Service and/or program office events.  Additionally, accomplish significant upgrades to the VWC environment and IAMD systems and capabilities:
•	Electronic Warfare improvements in coordination with USSTRATCOM, Joint Electromagnetic Preparedness for Advanced Combat (JEPAC), the Services and MDA to better model red and blue electronic attack and electronic protection, visualize impacts, and conduct analysis of its impact on the tactical fight.  E.g., Eagle Passive-Active Warning Survivability Systems (EPAWSS) for F-15, Integrated Defensive Electronic Countermeasures (IDECM) for F/A-18E, Surface Electronic Warfare Improvement Program (SEWIP) for Aegis, basic electromagnetic interference effects, and foundation for representing GPS modeling
•	Multi-spectral Environment improvements include upgrading the simulation backbone and service models to better handle capabilities such as Infrared Search and Track (IRST) sensors and kill chains, environmental effects such as rain and clouds, and higher-fidelity threat signatures 
•	Advanced Capability Model improvements include expanded integrated fire control concepts involving capabilities such as Naval Integrated Fire Control – Counter Air (NIFC-CA) and fighter-centric kill chains, incorporation of advanced sensor capabilities such as the new IAMD Radar (AMDR) for Aegis, Link-16 network enhancements, future threat kill chains and capabilities, and directed energy.  Additionally, integrate an Advanced Gun Weapon System model into the environment to explore tactical command and control challenges and contributions to the overall defense of critical assets
•	Space Warfare – integrate higher fidelity representations of Overhead Persistent Infrared (OPIR) assets and national to tactical (N2T) contributions to the tactical fight
•	Non-Program of Record Experimentation of innovative uses of existing sensors and weapons across traditional IAMD assets.  E.g., ground-based sensors providing fire-control quality tracking to tactical air assets, contributions of unmanned assets to the air picture and joint engagement sequence
•	Explore integration of offensive and defensive capabilities (kinetic and non-kinetic) in protection of select critical assets in USEUCOM</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>16.000</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>16.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Execute two large Nimble Fire events in support of U.S. Fleet Forces Command, USPACOM, USSTRATCOM and USEUCOM.  Provide material support for two additional Service and/or program office events.  Additionally, accomplish significant upgrades to the VWC environment and IAMD systems and capabilities:
•	Electronic Warfare improvements in coordination with USSTRATCOM, JEPAC, the Services and MDA to better model red and blue electronic attack and electronic protection, visualize impacts, and conduct analysis of its impact on the tactical fight  E.g., Eagle Passive-Active Warning Survivability Systems (EPAWSS) for F-15, Integrated Defensive Electronic Countermeasures (IDECM) for F/A-18E, Surface Electronic Warfare Improvement Program (SEWIP) for Aegis, basic electromagnetic interference effects, and foundation for representing GPS modeling
•	Multi-spectral Environment improvements include upgrading the simulation backbone and service models to better handle capabilities such as Infrared Search and Track (IRST) sensors and kill chains, environmental effects such as rain and clouds, and higher-fidelity threat signatures 
•	Advanced Capability Model improvements include expanded integrated fire control concepts involving capabilities such as Naval Integrated Fire Control – Counter Air (NIFC-CA) and fighter-centric kill chains, incorporation of advanced sensor capabilities such as the new IAMD Radar (AMDR) for Aegis, Link-16 network enhancements, future threat kill chains and capabilities, and directed energy.  Additionally, integrate an Advanced Gun Weapon System model into the environment to explore tactical command and control challenges and contributions to the overall defense of critical assets
•	Space Warfare – integrate higher fidelity representations of Overhead Persistent Infrared (OPIR) assets and national to tactical (N2T) contributions to the tactical fight
•	Non-Program of Record Experimentation of innovative uses of existing sensors and weapons across traditional IAMD assets.  E.g., ground-based sensors providing fire-control quality tracking to tactical air assets, contributions of unmanned assets to the air picture and joint engagement sequence
•	Explore integration of offensive and defensive capabilities (kinetic and non-kinetic) in protection of select critical assets in USEUCOM</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>(1) Complete events within schedule and budget.

(2) Document gaps and shortfalls.

(3) Inform the Joint Capabilities Board (JCB) on results and findings.

(4) Specific details are classified.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P006</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Cruise Missile Combat Identification (CID)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>57.264</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>6.356</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>6.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.500</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.500</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>5.498</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>4.355</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>4.475</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>4.475</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) is the organization within the Department of Defense (DoD) chartered to plan, coordinate, and oversee Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense (IAMD) requirements, joint operational concepts, and operational architectures.  As part of the Joint Staff, JIAMDO supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in meeting his Title 10 responsibilities as they relate to IAMD issues.  JIAMDO is the operational community's proponent for characteristics, requirements, and capabilities in IAMD, and is the joint IAMD proponent within the DoD's resource allocation structures.  JIAMDO also leads AMD mission area and utility analyses, integrates air and missile defense within the Force Protection joint capability area, and conducts evaluations and demonstrations of joint IAMD architectures and concepts.

JIAMDO has established a close partnership with Combatant Commands (CCMDs) and maintains liaison offices at major CCMD locations to facilitate coordination of integration issues and requirements.  In particular, JIAMDO maintains close coordination with U.S. Strategic Command (USSTRATCOM) and U.S. Northern Command (USNORTHCOM) in support of ballistic missile defense of the U.S.  JIAMDO provides the CJCS and the Joint Requirements Oversight Council the ability to meet statutory responsibilities to review the cost, schedule, and performance criteria of Missile Defense Agency missile defense programs, and assesses the validity of those criteria in relation to national and military requirements.  At the request of USSTRATCOM and at the direction of the CJCS, JIAMDO supports USSTRATCOM in development of the IAMD Prioritized Capability List, the Global Integrated Air and Missile Defense Assessment, and analysis of the Ballistic Missile Defense System (BMDS).  JIAMDO supports the USSTRATCOM ballistic missile early warning mission by ensuring operational and technical requirements are integrated into the theater missile warning architecture.  JIAMDO also provides direct support to North American Aerospace Defense Command and USNORTHCOM for homeland air and cruise missile surveillance issues.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Cruise Missile Combat Identification (CID)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Establishes joint requirements for emerging national and tactical combat identification technology and
positions it for fielding to frontline weapon systems and the warfighter. Monitors, assesses, and enhances current joint Air and Cruise Missile Defense Combat ID programs.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>6.356</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Details of this program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>6.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Details of this program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.500</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.500</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Details of this program are classified.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>Not required for Budget Activities 1, 2, 3 and 6.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Details of this program are classified.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0204571J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Joint Staff Analytical Support</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>171</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2018</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2017-05</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>13.516</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>5.983</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>7.464</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.712</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.712</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>6.870</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>5.135</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>5.134</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>5.134</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS) family of programs provides defense analytical support capabilities for The Joint Staff (TJS) and Combatant Commands (CCMDs).  JSAS encompasses the developmental tools and infrastructure required to conduct analyses and formulates the results to best assist the Chairman in fulfilling his statutory responsibilities.  Key deliverables provided by JSAS include development and implementation of Joint Concepts, wide-ranging force structure assessments, course of action development for the Joint Force environment, analyses and studies to aid in decision-making, and other analysis efforts to implement timely, low-cost joint force development initiatives.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>5.983</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>7.464</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>6.312</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>6.312</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>5.983</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>7.464</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>7.712</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>7.712</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Additional support for Global Force Management Data Initiative (GFM DI)</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.400</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.400</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                    </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>FY 2018: Increase in funding to P003 GFM DI to complete development and fielding of Joint Planning Services pilot that is fully integrated with Joint Planning and Execution Services Framework.

FY 2019 thru FY 2022: Decrease in funding for FY 2019 thru FY 2022 is a result of mandated 25% Management Headquarters Activities (MHA) reductions prescribed by the 2016 NDAA.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Future Joint Force Development</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>4.410</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>5.983</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>5.564</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.712</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.712</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>5.470</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>5.135</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>5.134</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>5.134</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS) program supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) Title 10, Section 153 statutory responsibilities that directs the analytical support, management, development, evaluation, and implementation of joint concepts in order to advance the operational effectiveness of the future Joint Force and enable the introduction of new capabilities.  The Joint Concepts Program assists the CJCS in the formulation of “best military advice” by providing a long-term (out to 20 years) vision of how the Joint Force will be developed to respond to the future operating environment characterized by trans-regional, multi-domain, and multi-functional challenges.    Key deliverables include:  The Joint Operating Environment (JOE); Capstone Concept for Joint Operations (CCJO); identification, development, and implementation of Joint Concepts necessary to address future operating environment challenges and achieve objectives of the National Military Strategy (NMS); and CJCSI 3010 Guidance for Development and Implementation of Joint Concepts.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Future Joint Force Development</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>FY 2016 efforts focused on supporting the President’s “Sustaining U.S. Global Leadership Priorities for the 21st Century Defense” with emphasis on concept assessment of the Chairman’s Capstone Concept for Joint Operations, implementing the Joint Operational Access Concept, and developing new operational concepts to support achievement of the NMS. Specific work focused on joint concept development, implementation, and assessment through the Iron Crucible Wargaming series resulting in joint capability gap analysis and recommendations for non-materiel solutions that will improve current and future joint force capability including operating in anti-access and area denial (A2/AD) environments, joint command &amp; control, counterterrorism, and defeating threats in all domains, including cyber.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.983</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>FY 2016 efforts focused on completing the update of the Capstone Concept for Joint Operations: Joint Force 2030 (CCJO) (in draft with the CJCS at the end of FY 2016), publishing the Joint Operating Environment 2035 (JOE), developing a new Family of Joint Concepts framework aligned with the NMS, and developing five new Joint Concepts with the Joint Concept Community to guide and shape future joint force development.  Active implementation included 14 Joint Concepts into Doctrine, Organization, Training, Materiel Leadership and Education, Personnel, Facilities, and Policy (DOTMLPF-P) processes during FY 2016 resulting in 3 studies, 5 Capabilities-Based Assessments (CBA), 14 DOTMLPF-P Change Requests (DCR), 1 Initial Capabilities Document (ICD), 3 Capability Development Documents (CDD), 1 Capability Production Document (CPD), and development of 3 Joint Knowledge Online (JKO) courses. The final update for the Joint Operational Access Concept Implementation Plan was signed May 2016 signaling that appropriate DOTMLPF-P processes are developing capabilities critical to addressing Anti-Access/Area Denial (A2/AD) challenges.  18 legacy concepts were approved by the Director of the Joint Staff for archival.  The CJCSI 3010 was approved Aug 2016 with improved terminology and process descriptions to guide joint concept development and implementation.  Initiated the pilot year of the DepSecDef directed Warfighting Lab Incentive Fund (WLIF) program, resulting in 13 OSD-funded projects designed to spur and support warfighting field experiments, demonstrations, and operational user input to develop innovative capabilities, and new operational and organizational constructs to address emerging warfighter challenges.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.564</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Complete CJCS approval of the CCJO.  In partnership with selected CCMDs and the Services, begin developing the approved Family of Joint Concepts needed to address the 4+1 strategic challenges expressed in the NMS, out to 2035.  Continue futures study to inform our understanding of the challenges of the future operating environment. Complete development of 5 new Joint Concepts from FY 2016 and initiate 2 new Joint Concepts aligned to the National Military Strategy (NMS).  Continue implementing approved Joint Concepts IAW CJCSI 3010.  Expand multinational partnerships in futures and concept development.  Support Joint Staff 2017 efforts by integrating Joint Concepts across the Joint Staff to inform capability development decisions.  Continue to lead execution and oversight of the DepSecDef directed WLIF program to spur innovative force development.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.712</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>5.712</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Continue support for CJCS's NMS and CCJO.  In partnership with selected CCMDs and the Services, continue developing the approved Family of Joint Concepts needed to address the 4+1 strategic challenges expressed in the NMS, out to 2035.  Continue futures study to inform our understanding of the challenges of the future operating environment. Complete development of 2 new Joint Concepts from FY 2017 and initiate 2 new Joint Concepts aligned to the NMS. Continue implementing approved Joint Concepts IAW CJCSI 3010.  Continue multinational partnerships in futures and concept development.  Continue integrating Joint Concepts across the Joint Staff to inform capability development decisions.  Continue to lead execution and oversight of the DepSecDef directed WLIF program to spur innovative force development.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Concept development performance metrics are derived from the Chairman’s Title 10 responsibilities and CJCSI 3010.02E Guidance for Developing and Implementing Joint Concepts and, as such, support the purpose of informing the Department’s senior leadership by examining military problems and providing an azimuth for future joint force development. 

Performance measure 1 – Identify and develop Joint Concepts to examine military challenges and propose innovative joint solutions and associated capabilities in support of defense needs and priorities.
Metrics: Aligns with and informs the NMS. Informed by rigorous futures analysis. Creates relevance and advocacy among operations, plans, and force development communities.  

Performance measure 2 – Lead the development of Joint Concepts in collaboration with joint and multinational partners.
Metrics: Joint Concepts governance system promotes “best military advice” for the CJCS.  Ideas and solutions are rigorously and objectively evaluated within a joint and multinational context.  Joint concepts are continually monitored to ensure consistency, relevancy, and utility throughout their life cycle.  

Performance measure 3 – Implement Joint Concepts. 
Metrics:  Transition plans promote informed decisions for joint force development.  Leverage, integrate or inform related capability development programs for maximum efficiency and effectiveness.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Global Force Management Data Initiative (GFM DI)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>9.106</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS) family of programs provides defense analytical support capabilities for the Joint Staff (TJS) and Combatant Commands (CCMDs).   JSAS encompasses the developmental tools and infrastructure required to conduct analyses and formulates the results to best assist the Chairman in fulfilling his statutory responsibilities.   Under the umbrella of analytical support tools are the Automated Global Force Management Tool (AGT) and the Collaborative Issue Resolution Tool (CIRT), both which will meet requirements set forth in Title 10 U.S.C. and the Unified Command Plan (UCP) for automating the Global Force Management Implementation Guidance Forces For (Assignment and Apportionment) tables.  Additionally, the Joint Organizational Server (JOS) will be the enabler system for Joint Staff personnel to be entered, near-real-time, into the automated Forces For Process.

RDT&amp;E efforts for GFM DI ended in FY 2015.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>N/A</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>N/A</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>0.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>N/A</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>N/A</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P003</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>GFM DI Enterprise Force Structure (EFS) Integration</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>1.900</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>1.400</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Global Force Management Data Initiative (GFM DI) Enterprise Force Structure (EFS) integration effort provides the next steps for GFM Mission Application enhancements intrinsic to balancing global force demand against the total military force. This complex and multi-variant task requires modernized technologies that must provide integrated information by linking authoritative force structure data (derived from the GFM DI Organizational Servers) to C2 data (resident in GFM mission applications). The Joint Staff Operations Directorate is responsible for GFM Allocation and is the Functional Manager of the GFM mission applications. Accordingly, the Joint Staff Operations Directorate will employ a joint strategy for efficiently fulfilling Enterprise Force Structure (EFS) data utility.

The DoD must quickly transition from legacy systems that promulgate data disparity across the Defense enterprise in order to meet National military objectives that have evolved from large force scenarios to operations that include small-to-full scale activities. As stated in both the NSS and NMS, our adversaries demonstrate the ability to readily transition from non-kinetic to kinetic means. Consequently, Information Technology (IT) superiority, capabilities, and recognition of associated vulnerabilities are an operational imperative. Yet, warfighters, strategic planners and GFM decision makers are unable to seamlessly exchange information in a manner that keeps pace with globally changing threats to rapidly and accurately accomplish force sourcing activities to support SecDef allocation decisions. TJS is mandated to utilize the Service Org Server (OS) EFS data to enhance managing, assessing, and displaying the worldwide disposition of U.S. Forces. Key deliverables include incrementally developed, operationally realistic capability enhancements focused on Resource-Informed Planning and GFM sourcing functionality required by JROCMs, the Capability Development Document (CDD) for GFM DI; Joint Command and Control (JC2) Capability Definition Package (CDP); Joint Operation Planning Process (JOPP) and Assessment CDP; and Force Planning &amp; Deployment Planning/Execution CDP.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Critical upgrades to GFM Mission Applications directly supporting Enterprise Force Structure Integration.</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>The GFM Mission DI EFS integration effort requires RDT&amp;E funds to upgrade GFM Mission Applications in order to operationalize the force structure data from the Service's Organizational Servers to actual forces for employment within the purview of Allocation and Joint Command and Control. This GFM DI effort within the Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS) family of programs: will immediately streamline the SECDEFs "Forces for Unified Commands" memorandum Assignment Tables. RDT&amp;E efforts for Assignment and Apportionment functions ended in FY 2015 with the declaration of the Automated Global Force Management Tool (AGT) Full Operation Capability (FOC). In order to complete the GFM DI tasks, efforts must begin as early as possible to ensure all GFM DI planned milestones, reflected in Section E, are realized and thereby enable a Global Visibility Capability. GFM applications managed by the Joint Staff are used by the JSAS family of programs. This effort to fund critical upgrades is a precondition to GFM DI EFS Integration.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>1.900</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Specific RDT&amp;E work will focus on development of a Joint Force Capabilities Catalog (JFCC) that draws upon authoritative Service force structure and GFM data aggregated in a prototype Global Laydown Server (GLS). This approach is essential in a budget constrained environment to fulfill the DoD CIO "DoD Cloud Way Forward" focused on service-oriented architecture that flattens the legacy "Silos of Databases" paradigm by leveraging decentralized infrastructure services. It will enable DoD CIO foundational IT changes with enhanced cybersecurity that provides information sharing within the Joint Command and Control mission partner environment without redundant or duplicative resources. The strategy will result in initial incremental development of the Joint Force Capability Catalog (JFCC) virtual application with a Force Element Inventory Predictive Analysis Tool (FEI PAT) utilizing dynamic force visibility that provides timely, accurate and dynamic data representing U.S. Forces in motion for the 34 GFM leading indicators and Combatant Commanders initial force requirements as identified in the NMS priority OPLANS.  The Initial Operating Capability (IOC) will be achieved by first aggregating the Service Org Server data into the Global Laydown Server to link Service generated Organization Unique Identifiers (OUIDs) for  force elements identified to establish the Joint C2 relationships to the Allocation process (OPCON and TACON Links). This will provide the capability to establish the OUID/ Unit Identification Code (UIC) linkages in Joint Operation Planning and Execution System (JOPES) Time-Phased Force Deployment Data (TPFDDs), then map them to GFM allocation information (Force Tracking Number [FTN], Request for Forces [RFF], Deployment Order/Line Number [DEPORD/LNR]), and Assignment of the Forces For Unified Commands</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.000</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.000</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Specific RDT&amp;E work will focus on the continued incremental development of the Joint Force Capabilities Catalog (JFCC) that will operationalize the DoD directed GFM DI by linking full DoD Service force structure to dynamic GFM factors (Capabilities, Readiness, Availability, Employment/Location) within the GLS thereby providing a dynamic representation of the disposition of all military forces. The GLS algorithms will enable the GFM mission applications to present meaningful information required for timely and accurate decision making to assist the Chairman in providing best military advice. The JFCC will serve as a user interface that uses the GLS algorithms to streamline operations planning and GFM execution in support of CCMD Warfighter requirements. The FY 2018 strategy will focus on a Unit Type Capabilities registration functionality within the JFCC that will unify the unit-based readiness and unit type reporting process by obtaining on-hand forces (personnel and equipment) via the EFS (GFM DI) standard format. The FY 2018 incremental development of the JFCC virtual application and associated dynamic force visibility will provide the true inventory of force availability based on Service employable entities (Unit Types) and sustainability factors, to enable the use of on-hand Service Force capabilities identified down to the Service-defined lowest deployable entities (Unit Types) for executive decision making and GFM mission execution.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>The JSAS efforts will result in a Global Laydown Server and Joint Force Capabilities Catalog that supports a Global Visibility Capability (GVC) allowing for enhanced GFM and Joint future force integration along with implementation of concepts to meet the information requirements needed to support timely and dynamic response to combatant commanders’ unforeseen contingency requirements. This is a cost-effective yet full spectrum approach to support and assist the Chairman in fulfilling his statutory responsibilities while improving current and future joint force management, and are measured by the following:

(1)	Meet IOC that enables rapid generation of GFM decision-making information for Policy-makers and warfighting Combatant Commands based on authoritative Service force capability, readiness, availability and current employment data.

(2)	Reducing the manual process of assembling Capability, Readiness, Availability, Employment (CRAE) data, is the first step to providing enhanced force management decision-making. Mining this data is currently a labor-intensive, time-consuming process and significantly impedes rapid response capabilities. Automating this data aggregation requires EFS Data services and Web Service Interfaces supporting a Joint Force Capabilities Catalog (JFCC) as described in the EFS Capability Package (CP) and is critical to operationalizing the force structure data and achieve GFM DI Next Steps Allocation.

(3)	Services, CCMDs, Joint Staff and OSD will be able to efficiently manage (collect and analyze) force generation data supporting GFM in far less time than the current process, and with an authoritative common view of the sourcing-to-employment tracking of forces. This is accomplished by the automated linking of the Organization Unique Identifier (OUID) attributes from the GFM DI Org Servers (OS) to the Unit Identification Code (UIC) resident in JOPES.

(4)	The JFCC will enable the rapid generation of information when making time-sensitive decisions and allow a Joint Planner to inculcate the association of standard and consistent force structure instance data and consistently applied data "types" with force structure data referenced over time in the GFM sourcing solution generation and deployment planning, execution, and distribution processes.

(5)	Ability to meet the VCJCS guidance to meet the GFM DI Full Operating Capability (FOC) by FY 2020 for GFM Allocation.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" format="R2Long" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0303166J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Support to Information Operations Capability (IO) Capabilities</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>174</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2018</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2017-05</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>23.875</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>10.404</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>0.857</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.673</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.673</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.781</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.781</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>10.404</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.857</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>10.404</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.857</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>Decrease from FY 2016 to FY 2017 due to realignment of funds to Operations and Maintenance (O&amp;M).</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Information Operations Range</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>23.875</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>10.404</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.857</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.673</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.673</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.673</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.781</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.781</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) provides DoD a closed-loop, persistent, geographically distributed network to conduct training, testing, and experimentation in support of Computer Network Attack (CNA)/Computer Network Defense (CND) in a threat representative environment with realistic and relevant targets and command &amp; control systems of interest. JIOR uniquely provides Services, Combatant Commanders (CCMD), and other government agencies the ability to test deployment and collaboratively gain insights into advanced Cyberspace, Information Operations (IO), and Electronic Warfare (EW) capabilities under current and future operational environment conditions. JIOR integrates other cyberspace ranges, replicates critical infrastructure, cyber targets, Internet traffic, and opposing forces.  These provide the capacity to meet Presidential policy and CJCS mandates for training and certification of 6000+ cyber warriors by 2017 and DoD/Interagency cyber vulnerability assessments. The JIOR security construct allows users to develop, test, and secure their unique cyber capabilities and protect their identity during range activities. The JIOR conducts multiple, simultaneous, and disparate training, testing, and experimentation events.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Information Operations Range</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>The Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) is a closed-loop network that forms a live-fire range utilizing encrypted tunneling over existing networks to conduct training, testing, and experimentation in support of Information Operations (IO), Electronic Warfare (EW), Computer Network Attack (CNA)/Computer Network Defense (CND)), and Cyberspace mission areas in a threat representative environment.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>10.404</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Continued FY 2015 efforts:

(1) Expanded national, DoD, and Inter-Agency awareness and support regarding IO and cyber related activities.
(2) Improved the threat representation and operational relevance of the network.
(3) Improved the integration of LVC simulations with other Joint training and testing communities and infrastructures.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>0.857</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>The Joint Staff conducted a thorough program review and determined the majority of IO Range expenses were better suited to the O&amp;M appropriation for proper execution.  

Continues FY 2016 efforts:

(1) Expand national, DoD, and Inter-Agency awareness and support regarding IO and cyber related activities.
(2) Improve the threat representation and operational relevance of the network.
(3) Improve the integration of LVC simulations with other Joint training and testing communities and infrastructures.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>0.673</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>0.673</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>(1) Continues FY 2017 efforts.
(2) Evaluate and deploy network automation tools to better manage the JIOR.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>The Joint Staff conducted a thorough program review and determined the majority of IO Range expenses were better suited to the O&amp;M appropriation for proper execution.  

Measures:  JIOR modernization results in reduced network reconfiguration time for use and reuse of DoD Enterprise Cyber Range Environment (DECRE) ranges.

- Number of Defense Research and Engineering Network (DREN) circuits remaining and rate of replacement with Defense Information Systems Network (DISN) circuits (Cost).

- Estimated man-hours saved due to transforming manual paper-driven planning processes to on-demand automated services (Schedule).

- Sufficient capacity &amp; agility to support Cyber Mission Forces force development and MDAP/C2 systems cybersecurity assessments &amp; testing (Outcomes).

- Improved rapid response for short-notice mission rehearsal requirements from days to on-demand (Outcomes).</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0804767J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>COCOM Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2) - MHA</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>183</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2018</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2017-05</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>6</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>RDT&amp;E Management Support</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>44.500</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>44.500</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>42.940</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>40.071</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>40.063</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>41.044</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>These programs support readiness of the joint force by creating a Joint Training Environment to replicate the complex and changing operational environment.  These investments directly support defense strategic guidance and enhance joint warfighting readiness by building training capabilities that support the operational readiness of the force.  The elements associated with this coordinated effort consist of:

- Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)

- Joint Simulation System (JSS)

- Joint Knowledge Development &amp; Distribution Capability (JKDDC)

- USSTRATCOM SPACE CYBER

- Air Force Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)

- Navy Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)

JNTC:  The mission of the Joint National Training Capability (JNTC) program is to advance joint capabilities and interoperability by concentrating on emerging joint training requirements through collective training experiences using a managed set of globally distributed capabilities and activities. The program resources Service and SOF joint training and enabling capabilities that improve interoperability and realism of tactical and operational joint training between the Services and USSOCOM. JNTC enables joint collective training for Combatant Commands and Services by developing relevant joint training content and ensuring global distributed access. The enabling capabilities support the Services and USSOCOM in their requirement to provide trained and ready forces in support of Combatant Command operational requirements. This program will focus efforts on improving, rather than consuming readiness and create a ready surge force consistent with Chairman’s guidance.

JSS:  The Joint Simulation System (JSS), consisting of the Joint Theater Level Simulation (JTLS) and the Joint Conflict and Tactical Simulation (JCATS), provides a low cost, distributed or deployable, web-based joint training capability with a small technical and operator footprint.  JSS funding provides warfighters with joint simulations and tools that enhance and enable Joint training across Services, Combatant Commands, Combat Support Agencies, NATO, and multinational partners. The Joint simulations and tools provided by JSS funding are critical enablers that support the delivery of trained, capable, and interoperable joint forces.  JSS’s intent is to maintain a capability to share simulation environments with coalition partners by continuing limited investments to ensure JTLS and JCATS remain relevant and provide reliable, low-cost, small footprint, distributed, and deployable joint training solutions. 
 
JKDDC:  Joint Knowledge Development &amp; Distribution Capability (JKDDC) Joint Knowledge Online (JKO) is the program of record for online joint training that implements and operationalizes the OSD T2 JKDDC.  JKO directly supports the CE2T2 program by developing, delivering, tracking, reporting, and supporting online training for Combatant Command exercises; Combatant Command required training; doctrinally based Joint Operations Core Curriculum; multinational, coalition, Interagency training; OSD required training (externally funded): and, administration of the Senior Enlisted Joint Professional Military Education (SEJPME) program.  JKO expends research, development test and evaluation (RDTE) funding for leading edge technology review, market research, and integration to directly enhance specific aspects of the training capability as required to support Combatant Commanders, CE2T2 Program Goals and Objectives, and the Chairman Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) training guidance. JKO satisfies all requirements necessary to provide the CE2T2 stakeholders with a distributed learning capability and access to web-based training content, learning resources, and distributed online training tools.

USSTRATCOM CYBER: The USSTRATCOM CYBER funding provided architecture and analysis support to Space Security and Defense Program (SSDP) and the JOINT SPACE OPERATIONS CENTER (JICSpOC) through Modeling, Simulation and Analysis (MS&amp;A); Trade-Off Analysis; Concept Development; Scenario Development; and Military Utility Analysis.

Air Force JNTC:  The Air Force JNTC funding provides a focused upgrade to develop models for space-based and Cyber capabilities for integration into the Joint Live, Virtual, and Constructive (JLVC) environment.  The Air Force supports development of cross-domain solutions that enable the integration of systems with disparate security requirements, and significantly increases the training audience to additional joint and coalition participants.  Additionally, the Air force supports the integration of tactical models into the virtual environment.  

Navy JNTC:  These funds enable the Navy to develop unique maritime capabilities that integrate JLVC elements into a seamless joint training environment. The Navy program activities include conducting research, development, test and evaluation, and cross-service architecture certification on joint-capable systems.  Additionally, the program develops cross-domain architectures for U.S. and Coalition Forces and ensures sister service modeling/simulation and instrumentation efforts follow a unified standard.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>44.500</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>44.500</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>44.500</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>44.500</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>COCOM Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2) transfers to The Joint Staff in FY 2018 in PE 0804767J from 0804767D8Z.  All Prior Year, FY 2016 and FY 2017 data will be reported by OSD P&amp;R.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>758</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>32.550</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>32.550</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>31.370</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>29.052</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>29.044</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>30.025</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectNote>COCOM Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2) transfers to The Joint Staff in FY 2018 in PE 0804767J from 0804767D8Z.</r2:ProjectNote>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Investment in the Joint National Training Capability (JNTC) program will enable Service and Combatant Commands to train as they operate.  The net funding increase from FY 2016 through FY 2018 represents planned growth and internal reprogramming decisions to accelerate development of a cloud-enabled joint training environment.  The funding requested continues to modernize joint training capabilities into a single integrating architecture for Joint Training that is aligned to the DoD Chief Information Officer IT mandates.  Funding supports the development of cloud-enabled modular training application services.  Program intent is to reduce dependence on touch labor, and mitigate the impact of reductions in operation and sustainment funding.  Focus must be maintained to deliver operationally relevant training environments and respond to changes in global security landscape and the warfighter’s operational environment.  JNTC enables the Department of Defense to be responsive to the warfighters’ pace of changing operational concepts, threat environments, and best practices. In FY 2018, this investment continues expanding capabilities and access for Service and Combatant Command trainers to plan and execute joint training.  Funds support improved relevance and realism of training by providing capabilities that replicate the contemporary and future operating environment.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>JNTC provides the technical standards, architecture (blueprint), and development processes required to integrate/link joint training programs.  The Joint Training Environment is envisioned as an integrated network of training sites and nodes, and accessible joint training and force development services.  By leveraging existing training programs and initiating specific actions, JNTC develops credible opposing force capabilities and expanded access to assets typically unavailable to the training audience.  This enhances the integration of joint training objectives into Service training events.  Funding in this account supports the technical integration of Joint and Service modeling and simulation training capabilities.  The resulting capabilities enable selective aggregation of training audiences at the Combatant Command, Joint Task Force, and Component Command Headquarter levels.  The funding supports modernization of the Joint Training Environment (JTE) to increase warfighter access to semi-automated training enablers within the Joint Training Synthetic Environment (JTSE) through web-based, modular cloud capabilities. 

The Adaptive Training Capability Program (ATCP) is a subordinate component of JNTC that enables the Joint Force to be responsive to the warfighters’ pace of changing operational concepts, threat environments, and best practices.  ATCP funding advances joint capabilities and interoperability by addressing emerging joint training requirements through a managed set of globally distributed JLVC enablers.  ATCP funding promotes joint context to Service training programs and joint enablers supporting Combatant Command training requirements and CJCS High Interest Training Issues identified in the Chairman’s Annual Training Guidance.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>32.550</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>32.550</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>• Integrate the role player access capability into the Joint Training Tool environment.
• Continue to mature Joint Training Tool modular services to reach a Tier 1 and 2 joint training initial operating capability in FY 2019.  This includes smart graphics that allow planners to describe an operation with graphics which auto-initiates the Joint Training Tool service modules to replicate the movement of forces, adjudicate interaction with opposing forces, and return results of the operation that can drive a training scenario and stimulate the appropriate decision points. 
• Continue Joint Training Tool scenario development to support a broader range of joint training options.
• Continue to mature Joint Training Tool cloud capabilities and explore cloud hosting options for the long-term.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>RDT&amp;E development efforts are evaluated based on the performance metrics below.  This ensures the Joint Force Trainer capabilities development effort synchronizes with warfighter requirements.  Performance metrics include, but are not limited to: access, cost, realism, relevance, and technology and are defined below.

• Access – Develop design standards that enable participation across DoD and, as applicable, with Coalition Partners. Make the environment available to meet user demands.
• Cost – Enable the Joint Force Trainer to prepare and execute training at a more effective and efficient cost than current capabilities allow. 
• Realism – Enable the Joint Force Trainer to create a training environment that is closer to the real world environment than current capabilities allow.
• Relevance – Maintain operational relevance through adaptation to the changing operational environment.
• Technology – Sustain the training environment network through developments for distributed home station training that include modular cloud-enabled training services.

Measures:

• Cost - Vendors provide ordered hours and projected costs remain within 10 percent of government estimates.
• Schedule - Task completions (software enhancements, bug fixes, and cyber security requirements) delivered within 6 months of government estimate.
• Performance - Product results, outcomes or milestones meet specified requirements and successfully pass more than 80 percent of operational assessment test cases.
• DoD Demand - Number of Commands, Services, and Agencies using Joint Staff developed training products.
• Partner Nation Demand - Number of partner nations using Joint Staff developed training products.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>761</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Simulations Systems (JSS)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.103</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.103</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>1.067</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>1.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>1.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>1.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectNote>COCOM Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2) transfers to The Joint Staff in FY2018 in PE 0804767J from 0804767D8Z.</r2:ProjectNote>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Joint Simulation System (JSS) will decompose, harvest, and reuse DoD investment in joint simulations to develop cloud-enabled modular services (CEMS), reaching Initial Operating Capability in FY 2016.  JSS will further development of existing Joint Conflict and Tactical Simulation (JCATS) and Joint Theater Level Simulation (JTLS) as required, to remain relevant and responsive to meet Combatant Command training requirements as the Joint Training Environment is implemented.  JSS will provide design and development of web-based applications used as services in CEMS environment.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Joint Simulation System (JSS)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>This effort provides warfighters with joint simulations and tools that enhance and enable Joint training across Services, Combatant Commands, agencies and coalition partners.  These joint simulations and tools are part of an overall Joint Live Virtual Constructive baseline of training capabilities.  They represent a set of training enablers, and “certified systems” that are interoperable and acceptable for usage within the joint training environment.  The joint simulations and tools provided by JSS are critical enablers that support the delivery of trained, capable, and interoperable Joint Forces.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>1.103</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>1.103</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>• Modernize Joint Theater Level Simulation graphical user interface to take advantage of established open source and commercial enhancements.
• Modernize Joint Theater Level Simulation after action review capability for more efficient and faster queries and data retrieval.
• Develop the Joint Theater Level Simulation Combat Systems Prototype into a web-based modular capability in support of the Joint Training Synthetic Environment.
• Virtualize and eliminate the Joint Theater Level Simulation and Joint Conflict and Tactical Simulation client server architecture in pursuit of a fully web-based service.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>RDT&amp;E development efforts are evaluated based on performance metrics.  This ensures the development of Joint Force Trainer (subject matter experts) capabilities synchronizes with warfighter requirements.  Performance metrics include, but are not limited to: time, cost, realism, and fidelity and are defined below.

• Time – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training more timely than current capabilities allow?
• Cost – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training at a more effective and efficient cost than current capabilities allow?
• Realism – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create a training environment that is closer to the real world environment than current capabilities allow?
• Fidelity – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create more detailed capabilities in the training environment than current capabilities allow?

Measures:
• Cost - Vendors provide ordered hours and projected costs remain within 10 percent of government estimates.
• Schedule - Task completions (software enhancements, bug fixes, and cyber security requirements) delivered within 6 months of government estimate.
• Performance - Product results, outcomes or milestones meet specified requirements and successfully pass more than 80 percent of operational assessment test cases. JTLS and JCATS availability of use in support of all training activities remains above 95 percent.
• DoD Demand - Number of exercises/events supported by JTLS and JCATS.
• Partner Nation Demand - Number of partner nations using Joint Staff developed training products (active foreign military sales cases).</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>769</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Knowledge Development &amp; Distribution Capability (JKDDC)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>4.168</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>4.168</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>4.126</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>4.108</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>4.108</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>4.108</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectNote>COCOM Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2) transfers to The Joint Staff in FY2018 in PE 0804767J from 0804767D8Z.</r2:ProjectNote>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Joint Knowledge Online (JKO) is the DoD unique and authoritative source for online joint training.  JKO is tasked to develop a DoD enterprise-wide, Joint Individual Training Toolkit of web-enabled individual and small group training products, services, and enabling training technology.  Products and services are developed in response to OSD (P&amp;R) CE2T2 Program Goals &amp; Objectives guidance, CJCS High Interest Training Issues, Joint Staff training priorities, and JKO Stakeholders (Combatant Commands, Services, and Combat Support Agencies, Interagency, and Multinational) prioritized training requirements.  JKO supports a career-long joint learning continuum, joint professional military education, and tailored common training standards to Service members for tasks that are jointly executed, resulting in trained, capable, and interoperable joint forces.  JKO research and development will improve all components of the Joint Content Management Architecture including:  

• JKO Learning Content Management System (LCMS): Development and enhancement is required to integrate advanced individual and staff training technologies and methodologies with larger scale, collective training exercises, and modernize military training capability with a DoD enterprise-wide online training toolkit. JKO LCMS is necessary to develop, host and deliver JKO courses and track/report students’ progress, completions and survey results more effectively and efficiently. JKO LCMS extends web-based, distributed access to mission-critical joint training requirements. There are currently over 2.7 million registered users of the JKO LCMS.

• Small Group Scenario Trainer (SGST) desktop modeling and simulation based training: This JKO capability trains and prepares thousands of military and civilian personnel deploying to Combatant Command theaters of operation prior to serving in their assigned Combined/Joint Task Force (C/JTF) billets. Specifically, C/JTF ‘battle staffs’ will be adequately trained, as individuals and the staffs collectively, based on SGST development and implementation throughout the joint training enterprise. JKO integration of SGST simulation exercise scenarios and prerequisite JKO courses enable blended learning training support to large-scale, collective training exercises that augment the Joint Event Learning Cycle and in meeting combatant commanders exercise objectives.

• JKO mobile application training device development:  Development and enhancements facilitate the global distribution of web-based joint training content on portable, hand-held platforms (cell phones and tablets).  JKO Mobile App extends access to training courses and learning resources to personal use of mobile phones and tablets.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Joint Knowledge Development &amp; Distribution Capability (JKDDC)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Joint Knowledge Online (JKO) advance technology initiatives primarily include the JKO Learning Content Management System (LCMS) application, Small Group Scenario Trainer (SGST) desktop modeling and simulation based training capability, and mobile courseware training applications.  These capabilities increase access to, and facilitate the training and preparation of hundreds of thousands of military and civilian personnel deploying to Combatant Command (CCMD) theaters of operation prior to serving in their assigned Combined/Joint Task Force (C/JTF) billets.  JKO LCMS development and enhancements are required to develop, host, deliver, track/report and support students’ completions, progress and survey results more effectively and efficiently.  C/JTF “battle staffs” will be better trained, as individuals and the staffs collectively, based on SGST development and implementation throughout the joint training enterprise.  JKO mobile courseware training device development facilitates the global distribution of web-based joint training content on portable, hand-held platforms for DoD personnel.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.168</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>4.168</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Develop, test and deliver 2 JKO Learning Content Management System (LCMS) releases resulting in improved cybersecurity, and a more effective and efficient online training management application that is interoperable with DoD personnel management systems.  Requirements will be derived from CCMD user feedback and DoD training priorities directed by DASD(R) and the Chairman’s Training Guidance to provide a DoD enterprise-wide online training toolkit, and develop content for pre-exercise training and support - as required by the Services - and support individual and unit training for Special Purpose - Marine Air Ground Task Force (SP-MAGTF) missions.  JKO anticipates these enhancements will improve access and the ease of use for the projected ~50,000 daily log-ins and ~550,000 monthly course completions by DoD personnel.  Improvements to the JKO LCMS will directly benefit thousands of individuals by providing them global 24/7 access to mandatory joint training as they prepare to participate in CCMD exercises and real world missions. JKO will also focus on enhancements to improve the management of individuals’ training records and readiness reporting as the JKO LCMS extends information sharing and web services with DoD personnel management systems.  JKO will continue to enhance functionality based on user experience and feedback.
• Develop, test, and deliver 4 JKO Small Group Scenario Trainer (SGST) desktop modeling and simulation application releases resulting in a more effective and efficient training capability integrated within the JKO Learning Content Management System (LCMS).  JKO anticipates these enhancements will improve the quality of the training experience for CCMD exercise participants resulting in their heightened preparedness for real world operations.  The SGST will be used as part of the OSD endorsed Blended Learning Training component in approximately 8 CCMD collective training exercises to prepare individuals serving on CCMD required small functional teams and C/JTF "battle staffs."  Individual training proficiency improvement will be measured and quantified as part of the exercise design.  JKO will continue to enhance SGST functionality based on user experience and feedback.
• JKO will assess, refine, and continue executing its comprehensive plan to enhance the JKO mobile application and mobile training products. JKO’s planned components include courseware and video conversions to portable hand-held devices while leveraging other DoD agencies, interagency, and multinational training courseware ported to the JKO mobile application.  JKO anticipates the development and conversion of ~200 training courses, eBooks, Podcasts, job aids, and videos resulting in reduced cost for classroom training and thousands of hours delivered onsite and on demand to DoD personnel mobile platforms worldwide.  JKO will continue to enhance its mobile capability based on user experience and feedback.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>Joint Staff prescribed performance metrics include, but are not limited to: time, cost, realism, and fidelity and are defined below.

• Time – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training more timely than current capabilities allow?
• Cost – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training at a more effective and efficient cost than current capabilities allow?
• Realism – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create a training environment that is closer to the real world environment than current capabilities allow? 
• Fidelity – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create more detailed capabilities in the training environment than current capabilities allow? 

Measures:
• Identify, develop, test and implement 15 or more cyber-security, operational, and functional JKO LCMS requirements.   
• Identify, develop, test and implement 12 or more cyber-security, operational, and functional JKO SGST requirements. 
• Identify, develop, test and implement 6 or more cyber-security, operational, and functional JKO mobile App requirements.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>701</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Air Force Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>2.964</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>2.964</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>2.917</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>2.869</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>2.869</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>2.869</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectNote>COCOM Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2) transfers to The Joint Staff in FY2018 in PE 0804767J from 0804767D8Z.</r2:ProjectNote>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Air Force JNTC funding provides a focused upgrade to develop models for space-based capabilities for integration into the Joint Live, Virtual, and Constructive (JLVC) environment.  The Air Force supports development of cross-domain solutions that enable the integration of systems with disparate security requirements, and significantly increases the training audience to additional joint and coalition participants.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Air Force Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>The Air Force continues to develop joint enablers that drive realistic/effective training by producing a deployable Electronic Warfare training capability for Europe which replicates highly advanced Surface-to-Air Missiles and advanced Anti-Aircraft Artillery threats for U.S. and coalition forces.  Additionally, the Air Force assists in the engineering, development, and deployment of Joint Cross Domain Information Sharing (JCDIS) Enterprise Network Architecture which will enable joint and coalition participants to train while protecting classified information.  Furthermore, the Air Force is creating cyber-contested environments in the distributed mission operations setting to challenge the joint exercise/training audience.  Finally, comprehensive space effects are being integrated into the JLVC federation of models.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.964</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.964</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>• Live, Virtual, Constructive - Operational Training (LVC-OT) training solution supporting collaborative planning, cost, after-action, and ROI metrics.
• Cyber simulator environment generator/Blue cyber effects simulation.
• Space Simulation improvements to model both space effects and OPFOR capabilities affecting the space environment.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>RDT&amp;E development efforts are evaluated based on performance metrics.  This ensures the development of Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) capabilities synchronize with warfighter requirements.  Performance metrics include, but are not limited to: time, cost, realism, and fidelity and are defined below.

• Time – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training more timely than current capabilities allow?
• Cost – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training at a more effective and efficient cost than current capabilities allow?
• Realism – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create a training environment that is closer to the real world environment than current capabilities allow?
• Fidelity – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create more detailed capabilities in the training environment than current capabilities allow?

Measures:
• Cyber: Establish a persistent simulation environment that can be configured rapidly and accurately to reflect the desired operating environment of the training audience.  Also, create an ability to reflect cyber activities against a live Integrated Air Defense system.
• Space: a fully operational GPS environment which allows space operators to actively participate in Distributed Mission Operations-Space LVC missile warning, GPS disruption and Infrared special events. Also develop space models to model Space as a contested environment to accurately portray impacts of adversary actions in the Space domain.
• OPFOR: a prototype for a next generation tactical surface to air threat simulator emulating modern fielded threats fielded with potential adversary maneuver elements.
• A plan for integrating Army ground instrumentation within the Air Force run Polygon range complex.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>772</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Navy Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.715</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.715</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>3.460</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.042</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.042</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.042</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectNote>COCOM Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2) transfers to The Joint Staff in FY2018 in PE 0804767J from 0804767D8Z.</r2:ProjectNote>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>These funds enable the Navy to develop unique maritime capabilities that integrate JLVC elements into a seamless joint training environment. The Navy program activities include conducting research, development, test and evaluation, and cross-service architecture certification on joint-capable systems.  Additionally, the program develops cross-domain architectures for U.S. and Coalition Forces and ensures sister service modeling/simulation and instrumentation efforts follow a unified standard.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Navy Joint National Training Capability (JNTC)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Develops unique maritime capabilities that integrate Joint Live, Virtual, and Constructive (JLVC) elements into a seamless joint training environment.  Using a scientific and phased approach that focuses on modeling ground, air, space, and maritime capabilities, this program researches new technologies and methods that provide a crucial technology-based foundation that supports all JNTC Training Transformation (T2), JLVC Federation, and Combatant Commanders Exercise and Engagement (CE2) operations.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>3.715</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>3.715</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>• Continue alignment of Navy LVC training standards with JLVC training standards to include with research of integrated standards with USMC’s Aviation Distributed Virtual Training Environment (ADVTE).
• Prototype and develop of integrated capabilities between Navy tactical training ranges and synthetic training capabilities in support of Navy LVC efforts.
• Accelerate research and development of combat identification training simulation as an enabler for spectrum operations in support of the information warfare commander (IWC).
• Accelerate exploration of technologies to enable Integrated Air and Missile Defense (IAMD) and other combined warfare area and joint training with coalition partners in the Pacific Fleet (PACFLT) Area of Responsibility including Japan, Korea, and Australia.  
• Continue collaborative development with Service and Agency partners to improve the realism and relevancy of tactical to operational level of war training capabilities.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>RDT&amp;E development efforts are evaluated based on performance metrics.  This ensures the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) capabilities development effort synchronizes with warfighter requirements.  Performance metrics include, but are not limited to: time, money, realism, and fidelity and are defined below.

• Time – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training more timely than current capabilities allow?
• Cost – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to prepare and execute training at a more effective and efficient cost than current capabilities allow?
• Realism – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create a training environment that is closer to the real world environment than current capabilities allow?
• Fidelity – Will the effort enable the Joint Force Trainer (subject matter expert) to create more detailed capabilities in the training environment than current capabilities allow?
• The Navy will produce one Navy Training Baseline (NTB) software release to include documentation; will design and implement upgrades to Joint Semi-Automated Forces (JSAF) consistent with approved requirements and contractual requirements and document the effects of JSAF capabilities (robustness) and stability.  Will design, implement, test, and integrate NTB enhancements in accordance with requirements.
• For JSAF, Joint Simulation BUS (JBUS) reliability, scalability, and tactical control, the Navy will continuously update the Common Operational Picture (COP) during large scale JLVC exercises.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" format="R2Long" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0208043J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Planning and Decision Aid System (PDAS)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>195</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2018</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2017-05</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>12.919</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>1.842</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>3.038</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>3.037</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.037</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.097</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.097</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>1.842</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>3.038</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>1.842</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>3.038</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>Classified details provided in a separate budget exhibit submitted on SIPRNET.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Planning and Decision Aid System OPS</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>1</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>12.919</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>1.842</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.038</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>3.037</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>3.037</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>3.037</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>3.097</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>3.097</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Provides engineering and testing support to the Planning and Decision Aid System, a classified Joint Staff automated information system supporting the combatant commanders, Services, and Department of Defense Agencies.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0902298J</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Management HQ - OJCS</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>247</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2018</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2017-05</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>15.722</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>2.953</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>0.826</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ProgramElementNote>Deputy Secretary of Defense (DepSecDef) approved the alignment of IT services in the Pentagon and the National Capital Region (NCR) to the Joint Service Provider (JSP) operating as a field service activity in Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA). In FY 2018, JSIN resources will permanently transfer to JSP (DISA PE 0305830K).</r2:ProgramElementNote>
            <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>Provides RDT&amp;E funds for the Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN). JSIN is the network infrastructure (for both classified and unclassified information) enabling collaboration and information-sharing among the Joint Staff, Combatant Commands (CCMD) and the Services. The JSIN also provides crucial business-related, decision-making information, and workflow support affecting military operations in support of the JCS. JSIN improves actions processing for faster coordination of critical issues with Combatant Commands, Services, and Agencies, as well as within TJS.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>2.953</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.826</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.861</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.861</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>2.953</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.826</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.861</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.861</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                            <r2:Title>Transfer to Joint Service Provider</r2:Title>
                            <r2:Funding>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>-0.861</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>-0.861</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            </r2:Funding>
                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                    </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                <r2:SummaryExplanation>Deputy Secretary of Defense (DepSecDef) approved the alignment of IT services in the Pentagon and the National Capital Region (NCR) to the Joint Service Provider (JSP) operating as a field service activity in Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA). In FY 2018, JSIN resources will permanently transfer to JSP (DISA PE 0305830K).</r2:SummaryExplanation>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>P001</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>15.722</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>2.953</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.826</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Provides RDT&amp;E funds for the Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN). JSIN is the network infrastructure (for both classified and unclassified information) enabling collaboration and information-sharing among the Joint Staff, Combatant Commands (CCMD) and the Services. The JSIN also provides crucial business-related, decision-making information, and workflow support affecting military operations in support of the JCS. JSIN improves actions processing for faster coordination of critical issues with Combatant Commands, Services, and Agencies, as well as within TJS.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN)</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>Provides RDT&amp;E funds for the Joint Staff Information Network (JSIN). JSIN is the network infrastructure (for both classified and unclassified information) enabling collaboration and information-sharing among the Joint Staff, Combatant Commands (CCMD) and the Services. The JSIN also provides crucial business-related, decision-making information, and workflow support affecting military operations in support of the JCS. JSIN improves actions processing for faster coordination of critical issues with Combatant Commands, Services, and Agencies, as well as within TJS.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>2.953</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Joint Staff migration to JIE continues with placement of applications into JIE Core Data Centers and participation within Installation Processing Nodes.  Mobile user access to JSIN services includes unclassified and classified mobile device use of JSIN-U and JSIN-S portals.  Subscription to the Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA) provided Unified Capabilities portfolio will allow a full complement of voice, video, chat, web conferencing, email, and mobility functionality.  Continued refinement of the U.S. Army Information Technology Agency desktop as a service,  Application Virtualization (U/S), Cross Domain Services, Enterprise Content Management  and Task Management (U) optimization and integration, Enterprise Services Implementation including Enterprise Task Management (U/S), Identity and Access Management capabilities, completion of a Managed Print Service (MPS) and consideration of DoD cloud services will achieve efficiencies, improve mission effectiveness, and strengthen our security posture.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>0.826</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>Work with the Joint Service Provider (JSP) to develop and refine methodologies to improve Active Directory hardening, network consolidation strategies, and improve data protection. Continue to develop and integrate more mobile capacities in the JS users as more and more systems are handheld and data hosted in the DOD cloud.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:OtherProgramFundingSummaryRemarks>N/A</r2:OtherProgramFundingSummaryRemarks>
                        <r2:PerformanceMetrics>(1) Reduce technical support hours per desktop a minimum of 10% through deployment of thin client and virtualized management of the IT baseline.

(2) Avoid cost for technology refresh of NIPR and SIPR desktops via the proper planning, testing, and piloting of a Joint Staff Thin Client solution.

(3) Reduce the cost of building, operating, and maintaining Joint Staff specific solutions through implementation of enterprise capabilities, and adoption of new cost models for execution (Enterprise Task management, Unified Communications, JIE, and Managed Print Services (MPS)

(4) Reduce redundancies in Core and Mission IT Capabilities through implementation of a comprehensive portfolio management policy and avoid cost through the institutionalization of investment management governance model.

(5) Reduce cost of Joint Staff controlled IT-services by subscribing to locally hosted IT services providers, i.e, JSP.</r2:PerformanceMetrics>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
    </r2:ProgramElementList>
</jb:JustificationBook>