<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2018</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2017-05</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0300D</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Procurement, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserP1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit P-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>P1C1F 2.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserP1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:GenerateP1>true</jb:GenerateP1>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
        <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <proc:LineItemList xmlns:proc="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/20100219/procurement">
        <proc:LineItem quantityUnits="Each" quantityUnitName="Each" unitCostUnits="Millions" totalCostUnits="Millions" manufacturerRateUnits="Monthly" combinedP5Flag="false" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <proc:LineItemNumber>10</proc:LineItemNumber>
            <proc:LineItemTitle>Major Equipment, TJS</proc:LineItemTitle>
            <proc:P1LineNumber>43</proc:P1LineNumber>
            <proc:BudgetYear>2018</proc:BudgetYear>
            <proc:BudgetCycle>PB</proc:BudgetCycle>
            <proc:SubmissionDate>2017-05</proc:SubmissionDate>
            <proc:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</proc:ServiceAgencyName>
            <proc:AppropriationNumber>0300D</proc:AppropriationNumber>
            <proc:AppropriationTitle>Procurement, Defense-Wide</proc:AppropriationTitle>
            <proc:BudgetActivityNumber>1</proc:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetActivityTitle>Major Equipment</proc:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>15</proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>Major Equipment, TJS</proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>
            <proc:ResourceSummary>
                <proc:TotalCost>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>63.002</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>13.027</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>7.988</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>9.341</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>9.341</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>8.503</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>8.533</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>8.337</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>8.377</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalCost>
                <proc:NetProcurementP1>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>63.002</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>13.027</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>7.988</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>9.341</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>9.341</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>8.503</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>8.533</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>8.337</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>8.377</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:NetProcurementP1>
                <proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>63.002</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>13.027</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>7.988</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>9.341</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>9.341</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>8.503</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>8.533</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>8.337</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>8.377</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
            </proc:ResourceSummary>
            <proc:Description>The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) is the principal military adviser to the President, National Security Council, and Secretary of Defense. The Chairman presides over and serves as a member of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. CJCS relies upon the Joint Staff (TJS) to craft and distribute guidance for combatant forces' unified strategic direction, operations under unified commands, and integration into effective combat forces. On behalf of the Chairman, TJS provides Combatant Commands (CCMDs), the Services, and U.S. war fighters with joint policy, strategy, and doctrine necessary to employ effective joint combat forces in contingencies worldwide.</proc:Description>
            <proc:Justification>Remarks/Justification:

The FY 2018 Joint Staff procurement appropriation requests $9.341M for mission critical information technology (IT) systems, applications investment requirements, and for commercial heavy-armored vehicles (CHAV). The procurement appropriation resources support various efforts across the Joint Staff including: New investments in Joint Force Development data center and Information Technology/Information Security equipment, the management of video teleconferencing services, and operations to ensure IT services at the Pentagon and remote site locations operate efficiently. 

1. Joint Lessons Learned Information System (JLLIS): 
No new FY 2018 procurement funding is required.  FY 2016 procurement funding was for JLLIS to support periodic JLLIS computer technical refresh/new capability enhancements.  

Joint Staff Analytical Support (JSAS) is made up of five major categories:  Joint Collaborative Analysis (JCA), Functional Capabilities Boards (FCBs), Joint Logistics, Adaptive Planning, and Joint Training System (JTS).  Procurement funding for JLLIS falls under the JCA category.

a. The JLLIS supports the Chairman's Title X responsibilities and is the DoD system of record supporting the Chairman's Joint Lessons Learned Program. JLLIS enables the capture of observations and the management of lessons learned across the four lessons learned phases – discovery, validation, integration, and evaluation. JLLIS supports programs across OSD, TJS, Services, Combatant Commands, Combat Support Agencies, National Guard Bureau, the Interagency, the Intelligence Community, and international partners.

b. Requirement:

• Provide an effective system and authoritative database to capture, record, and disseminate critical lessons learned from operations, exercises, training, experiments, and other real world events
• Provide a comprehensive information and knowledge management system for sharing of lessons and managing workflow associated with lesson resolution

NOTE: Due to the cyclic nature of the JLLIS technical refresh requirement, this program presents a non-linear funding profile with noticeable spikes in funding requirements during technical refresh years.  Expenditure plan for FY 17-18 outlined in paragraph e.

c. Accomplishments to Date / FY 2017 – FY 2018 Plans:
$1.066M was used in support of the LINK-16 Pulse De-confliction Server (LPDS) Phase II. As the vendor has nearly completed the contract, C4Transport and Joint Interoperability Division (JID) began working to connect and operate the new server on the Joint Training Exercise Network (JTEN). They discovered that an immediate change in the scope of an existing contract was required to increase the virtual machines, and support the information assurance accreditation package to support authority to connect and operate the new server.

d. $1.094M was provided for technical refresh requirements to video teleconference (VTC) and to enhance presentation capabilities for both classified and unclassified systems In Building NH-95, in Norfolk, Va. 

e. The JLLIS program is in the beginning stages of employing IBM Watson Analytics as an advanced search engine that also facilitates data analysis. The current configuration does not support Single Sign-On (SSO); therefore, users are required to maintain separate Watson and JLLIS accounts and log into each independent of the other. JLLIS and Watson require a more seamless method to the allow users to access information based on their permissions between the two applications without having to log in using multiple accounts. Additionally, JLLIS needs a practical method to manage JLLIS and Watson accounts and access. Other enhancements planned for FY 17-18 include cross domain transfer which will combine NIPR and SIPR data onto the SIPR domain in order to allow for a single search of both sets of data, data integration which will allow data to be transferred between JLLIS, the Joint Training Information Management System (JTIMS) and the Defense Readiness Reporting System (DRRS), and an off-site backup for JLLIS data.

2. Planning and Decision Aid System (PDAS):
PDAS is a classified, protected program operated by the Joint Staff.  PDAS supports the planning and execution of Joint Staff and Unified Combatant Commanders (COCOM) Operations.  PDAS is a world-wide network protecting sensitive information that meets the Intelligence Community Directive (ICD) 503 security requirements.  PDAS provides office automation packages, document and information management tools; collaboration, voice, and video tools in a secure, flexible architecture that promotes a distributed enterprise.  Within the enterprise, PDAS users have access to their data regardless of log-on location and secure data exchange and conferencing and planning sessions among physically distributed Continental United States (CONUS) and Outside Continental United States (OCONUS) locations. The operational user community is provided access to Help Desk and remote troubleshooting within the enterprise. 

NOTE: Due to the cyclic nature of the PDAS technical refresh requirement of datacenters, client computers and other IT equipment, this program presents a non-linear funding profile with noticeable spikes in funding requirements during technical refresh years.  Equipment is purchased in increments across fiscal years which mitigates spikes in funding requirements.

PDAS funding will be used to procure additional Program Site Installations, datacenter refresh, client refresh, and equipment modernizations. 

a.	Procurement of additional PDAS Program Site Installations will allow the Joint Staff Operational Sponsor/ Acquisition Program Manager to complete the installation of additional PDAS user sites. PDAS is comprised of hundreds of user sites with thousands of users worldwide. In recent years, the number of PDAS sites grew by 25% and is expected to continue to add sites and users annually.  These sites will provide PDAS capabilities, services and the infrastructure necessary to support the expansion of PDAS services and capabilities to meet operational mission needs. 

b.	Datacenter Refresh will allow the Joint Staff to provide refreshed datacenter hardware and software to replace hardware and software for user and test datacenters.  The hardware and software to be replaced is reaching the end of its service life and approaching obsolescence.  New equipment for the datacenters will enable the PDAS program to consolidate equipment baselines and provide commonality at the datacenters.  This periodic update provides PDAS with an updated IT infrastructure, enabling improved performance, security, efficiency and reduced logistical requirements.  From an operational perspective, it moves the IT team from event-driven, reactive situations of coping with the latest problem to a more proactive, forward-facing operational posture. The focus becomes one of preemptive quality assurance, standardization, and optimization while deferment leads to unsupportable hardware and software due to end-of-life or end-of-service issues.

c.	Client Refresh will allow the Joint Staff to provide updated computer hardware to the PDAS users in order to be compliant with Security Control 28 (SC-28), which is protection of information at rest to prevent insider threats.   This periodic update provides the users with an up to date information technology (IT) infrastructure, enabling improved performance, security, efficiency, reducing logistical requirements and other benefits.  From an IT operational perspective, it moves the IT team from event-driven, reactive situations of coping with the latest problem to a more proactive, forward-facing operational posture. The focus becomes one of preemptive quality assurance, standardization, and optimization while deferment of this purchase will require development of additional computer operating system baselines on deployed computer clients, additional baselines will significantly increase life-cycle sustainment cost.  

d.	Equipment Modernization will allow the Joint Staff to develop plans to provide and implement materiel solutions to address hardware and software configuration items that are outdated, nearing end-of-life or end-of-support or which can no longer be commercially acquired.  Historically, this equipment has been purchased as required due to failures, end-of-life, or end-of-service constraints which has led to many baselines and configurations of deployed IT and communications equipment.  These items reach end-of-life in different years, providing a cascade of equipment replacement requirements.  This spacing lessens the financial impact but requires constant purchase, integration, testing and installation.  The integration and extensive testing will ensure the hardware or software is compatible with other installed hardware and software configuration items and does not introduce vulnerabilities into PDAS, or allow unauthorized personnel to gain access to information for which they are not authorized.

3. Management Headquarters:
Management Headquarters provides the day-to-day financial resources necessary to conduct Joint Staff operations and enabling Information Technology (IT) requirements. The most critical of these is staff action processing (decision-making) for faster coordination of critical classified and unclassified issues between the CJCS, Joint Staff, the CCMDs, Services, Agencies, and the Department. It provides information management resources required for decision processing that empowers the Joint Staff as a knowledge enabled organization. Funding supports the Joint Integrated Air &amp; Missle Defense Organization (JIAMDO), Joint Range Extender (JRE), commercial heavy-armored vehicle (CHAV) program, and technology upgrades for the joint training facility. 

a. JIAMDO uses these funds to support a Near Real Time (NRT) Server in support of Combat Identification (CID) applications. The NRT Server provides an increased storage capacity for NRT data for real-time processing as well as testing and evaluation of new capabilities. It provides the ability to store non-standard data securely and also to enable future use of the data in development and testing. This item supports JIAMDO's National-to-Tactical CID mission. Additional details are classified.

b. Procure JRE, semi-rugged laptops (with JRE software license) and JRE Help Desk support. These JREs are required to support the Joint Integrated Air and Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO) Advanced-Combat Identification (A-CID) efforts. These JREs will be installed in the AF Digital Integration for Combat Employment (AFDICE) Joint Mobile Lab and will support hosting of Link 16 Terminals for participation in exercises, testing, and operational events. The purpose of this funding is to conduct activities to develop and operationalize enhanced CID capability. This will also entail collaboration with other governmental or industrial sources, as directed. This item supports JIAMDO's National-to-Tactical CID mission. Additional details are classified.

c. The Management Headquarters program element also funds costs associated with the CHAV program for transportation of senior military leadership.  Reference DoDI O-2000.22, Designation and Physical Protection of DoD High Risk Personnel (HRP); Change 1: (June 19, 2014) designates the CJCS and VCJCS as High Risk Personnel (HRP) level 1, authorizing them personal security detail (PSD) support.  Based on the Personal Security Vulnerability Assessment for the CJCS, and the professional judgement of the CJCS's Protective Service Detail (PSD), an operable CHAV is required to provide the necessary level of protection.  A Memorandum of Agreement (MOA) between the Protective Services Battalion (PSB), US Army Criminal Investigation Command (USACIDC) and the Joint Staff Support Services Office (JSSSO) describes responsibilities related to CHAVs used for Protection of the CJCS and VCJCS and assigns responsibility for programming, budgeting, funding, and acquiring CHAVs to the JSSSO.

d. Procures major hardware and software technology upgrades for the Suffolk, VA joint training facility. Provides significant network distribution/security, data processing, and capacity upgrades to the Suffolk Data Center to increase performance, security, reliability, and accessibility to the combatant commands and Services. Capability upgrades are required to host current joint training applications (Joint Knowledge Online, Joint Training Information Management System, Joint Lessons Learned Information Systems, and Joint Live, Virtual, and Constructive simulations) as well as provide support to multi-site, multi-command, distributed Live, Virtual, and Constructive joint force training events, such as the Globally Integrated Exercise (GIE) Program addressing transregional, multi-domain, and multi-functional (TMM) threat environment in support of the National Military Strategy.

Note:  Deputy Secretary of Defense (DepSecDef) approved the alignment of IT services in the Pentagon and the National Capital Region (NCR) to the Joint Service Provider (JSP) operating as a field service activity in Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA). In 2018, JSIN resources will permanently transfer to JSP (DISA PE 0305830K).  The overall effect to the Department is a net-zero profile change for FY 2018.

4.  Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR):
The JIOR provides DoD a closed-loop, persistent, geographically distributed network to conduct training, testing, and experimentation in support of Computer Network Attack (CNA)/Computer Network Defense (CND) in a threat representative environment with realistic and relevant targets and command &amp; control systems of interest. JIOR uniquely provides Services, Combatant Commanders (CCMDs), and other government agencies the ability to test deployment and collaboratively gain insights into advanced Cyberspace, Information Operations (IO), and Electronic Warfare (EW) capabilities under current and future operational environment conditions. JIOR integrates other cyberspace ranges, replicates critical infrastructure, cyber targets, Internet traffic, and opposing forces.  These provide the capacity to meet Presidential policy and CJCS mandates for training and certification of 6000+ cyber warriors by 2017 and DoD/Interagency cyber vulnerability assessments. The JIOR security construct allows users to develop, test, and secure their unique cyber capabilities and protect their identity during range activities. The JIOR hosts multiple, simultaneous, and disparate training/certification, testing, and experimentation events on a secure, closed-loop enterprise network.</proc:Justification>
            <proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                <proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>expandItemSuppressExhibit</proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>
            </proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        </proc:LineItem>
        <proc:LineItem quantityUnits="Each" quantityUnitName="Each" unitCostUnits="Millions" totalCostUnits="Millions" classification="UNCLASSIFIED">
            <proc:LineItemNumber>80</proc:LineItemNumber>
            <proc:LineItemTitle>Major Equipment, TJS - CE2T2</proc:LineItemTitle>
            <proc:P1LineNumber>44</proc:P1LineNumber>
            <proc:BudgetYear>2018</proc:BudgetYear>
            <proc:BudgetCycle>PB</proc:BudgetCycle>
            <proc:SubmissionDate>2017-05</proc:SubmissionDate>
            <proc:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</proc:ServiceAgencyName>
            <proc:AppropriationNumber>0300D</proc:AppropriationNumber>
            <proc:AppropriationTitle>Procurement, Defense-Wide</proc:AppropriationTitle>
            <proc:BudgetActivityNumber>1</proc:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetActivityTitle>Major Equipment</proc:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>15</proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>Major Equipment, TJS</proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>
            <proc:ResourceSummary>
                <proc:TotalCost>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>0</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>0</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>0</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0.903</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>0</proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>0.903</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>0.904</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>0.912</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>0.915</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>1.024</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalCost>
                <proc:NetProcurementP1>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>0</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>0</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>0</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0.903</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>0</proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>0.903</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>0.904</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>0.912</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>0.915</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>1.024</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:NetProcurementP1>
                <proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>0</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>0</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>0</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0.903</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>0</proc:BudgetYearOneOCO>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>0.903</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>0.904</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>0.912</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>0.915</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>1.024</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
            </proc:ResourceSummary>
            <proc:Description>The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) is the principal military adviser to the President, National Security Council, and Secretary of Defense. The Chairman presides over and serves as a member of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. CJCS relies upon the Joint Staff (TJS) to craft and distribute guidance for combatant forces' unified strategic direction, operations under unified commands, and integration into effective combat forces. On behalf of the Chairman, TJS provides Combatant Commands (CCMDs), the Services, and U.S. war fighters with joint policy, strategy, and doctrine necessary to employ effective joint combat forces in contingencies worldwide.</proc:Description>
            <proc:Justification>Remarks/Justification:

The FY 2018 Joint Staff procurement appropriation requests $.903M for mission critical hardware/software requirements for Commander's Exercise Engagement &amp; Training Transformation (CE2T2).

Combatant Commanders Exercise Engagement and Training Transformation (CE2T2): 
Increase between FY 2017 and FY 2018 is due to CE2T2 transferring to the Joint Staff from the Office of the Undersecretary of Defense (Personnel and Readiness) for direct execution and oversight of the program across the Services, Combatant Commands, and the Joint Staff.  Transferring the funding flow for the execution of CE2T2 through the Joint Staff is intended to focus improvement on the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff focus areas consisting of the following: 1) Restoring joint readiness; 2) Improving our joint warfighting capability; and 3) Developing leaders for Joint Forces Next.

The CE2T2 program continues to strengthen, expand, and develop within the Joint Force warfighting capabilities and competencies. Specifically, it includes the following programs:

a.  Joint Deployment Training Center (JDTC): JDTC funding provides the equipment and infrastructure required to train Combatant Command/Service/Agency warfighters on Joint Deployment, Situational Awareness, and Global Force Management applications. The JDTC procurement is necessary to provide the assets (servers, workstations and software) required to train Combatant Command/Service/Agency warfighters and provide world-wide exercise support. The equipment and infrastructure enable training on Joint Deployment, Situational Awareness, and Global Force Management applications. The Situational Awareness application, Common Operating Picture, will be upgraded to a new version which will require entirely new hardware/software to create a realistic and effective training environment. Funding ends in FY 2017 and has been moved to OM in the out years.

b.  USSTRATCOM requires procurement funding for hardware and software capabilities to preserve and expand current range infrastructure.  The funding for hardware and software capabilities to preserve and expand current range infrastructure. The current Cyber Range Instrumentation procures a Cyberspace Training Range to support United States Cyber Command (USCYBERCOM)-led CYBER FLAG, CYBER GUARD, and CYBER KNIGHT exercises. As part of the Cyberspace Training Initiative, continuance and expansion of the cyber range infrastructure is needed to support the Combatant Commanders, Services and USCYBERCOM joint cyber training and exercise requirements. The current target environment includes a Blue forces Department of Defense Information Network to include Network Operations Security Centers, a Gray network of internet spaces to include .gov and .edu domains that will emulate Internet sites and user activities, a realistic representation of an Adversary "Red" network, and a management (control) systems network. This emulated training environment is designed to utilize the existing elements of the Joint Information Operation Range (JIOR) as a transport layer to directly support USSTRATCOM's cyber mission. Moreover, it helps establish the Joint Force Cyber Training Range capability and directly supports the training and certification of Cyber Mission Forces. Procurement funding is imperative to increase storage capacity and improve the survivability/durability of the target environment. Additionally, ongoing hardware modernization efforts coupled with Opposing Forces (OPFOR) software requirements necessitate CE2T2 procurement funding lines.
• Hardware and software will provide a high fidelity immersive background for synthetic battlespace that creates interactive synthetic entities that can simulate real world systems
• Hardware and software will be used to replicate networks in order to train the Ground Combat Element (GCE) to integrate with Tactical MAGTF Integration Course (TMIC) students in the best techniques for planning and executing combat and stability operations
• A modular video and data system will enable warfighters to remotely downlink live surveillance images and geospatial data directly from manned and unmanned aircraft used in various trainings
• Procurement of PLEXComm 16 Channel LVC Systems that provide interface between N-NC tactical level (AFNORTH DTC, EADS, 176 ACS, 169 ACWS) communications panels and Distributed Interactive Simulation (DIS) voice communications
• Enhance the existing Distributed Interactive Simulation (DIS) based interface to the current Simulation Scenario Generator (SSG) of Battle Control System – Fixed (BCS-F)
• Distributed Mission Operations DIS based simulation tools to provide a distributed stimuli to the real-world BCS-F system, supporting Simulated only and Simulated over live training events
• Creation of cyber-contested environments in joint exercises to force cyber defenders to demonstrate ability to defeat/mitigate cyber attacks

c.  Joint Interoperability Division (JID): JID affords datalink computers, radios, antennas, crypto, and Link-16 simulator equipment for the Joint Interface Control Cell – Pope. Additionally, JID refreshes IT computers and accessories for two classrooms, five Mobile Training Teams and 58 administrative offices to enable joint/coalition training of 1,700 US and 400 Allied/Coalition students in the employment, planning, and management of tactical data links and joint C4I interoperability.  JID is a critical enabler to the T2 program as sole DoD provider Tactical Data Link (TDL)/JICO training and ops. Funding procures one Multifunctional Information Distribution System – Joint Tactical Radio System (MIDS-JTRS / MIDS-J). The MIDS-J is the future, software programmable four-channel (from 2 MHz – 2 GHz) Link-16, Enhanced Throughput, Frequency Remapping, Wideband Networking Waveform, UHF/VHF specialized radio that brings real-time situational awareness, location, targeting, and C2 data to smart bombs, mobile, dispersed joint forces on foot or operating in tactical vehicles in the Air, Land, or Maritime environments. The MIDS-J radio system is required to support planning, implementation, and operations of mobile network connectivity to tactical war fighters and disadvantaged platforms such as ground vehicles, helicopters, unmanned aircraft, and small boats. Currently, MIDS-J is onboard the F/A-18E/F Super Hornet fighter family, the E-8C JSTARS battlefield surveillance &amp; communication aircraft, and the RC-135 Rivet Joint airplane. Future weapon systems include the EC-130H Compass Call electronic warfare variant of the Hercules turboprop, E-2 Hawkeye and AWACS air/maritime surveillance airplanes,  as well the Navy's aircraft carriers, destroyers, and cruisers. The USAF will eventually field it on F-15E Strike Eagles, its B-1B and B-52H bombers, Special Operations aircraft (mostly C-130 variants like the Compass Call), and Ground C2 &amp; ISR units.

The overall effect of the CE2T2 transfer is a net-zero profile change for the Department in FY 2018.</proc:Justification>
            <proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                <proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>expandItemSuppressExhibit</proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>
            </proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        </proc:LineItem>
    </proc:LineItemList>
</jb:JustificationBook>