<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:MasterJustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:BudgetYear>2021</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2020-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>DCSA PB21 - R1 Report_012220v2_DCSA#JFpAx.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:TableOfContents>
        <jb:TocItemList>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 1</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Missile Defense Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 2</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Office of the Secretary Of Defense</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 3</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Chemical and Biological Defense Program</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 4</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Contract Audit Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Contract Management Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Information Systems Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Logistics Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Security Cooperation Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Technical Information Center</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Defense Threat Reduction Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>DoD Human Resources Activity</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Operational Test and Evaluation, Defense</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Space Development Agency</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>The Joint Staff</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>United States Special Operations Command</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
            <jb:TocItem>
                <jb:Title>Washington Headquarters Services</jb:Title>
                <jb:Location>Volume 5</jb:Location>
            </jb:TocItem>
        </jb:TocItemList>
    </jb:TableOfContents>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:WorkFlowStatus>FINAL</jb:WorkFlowStatus>
        <jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>Title(s) undefined</jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>
        <jb:GenerateP1m>true</jb:GenerateP1m>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
        <jb:JustificationBookGroup>
            <jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
                <jb:JustificationBookInfo>
                    <jb:BookDescription>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</jb:BookDescription>
                    <jb:BookLabel>Volume</jb:BookLabel>
                    <jb:BookNumber>5</jb:BookNumber>
                    <jb:JustificationBook targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                        <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
                        <jb:BudgetYear>2021</jb:BudgetYear>
                        <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
                        <jb:SubmissionDate>2020-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
                        <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
                        <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
                        <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
                        <jb:CoverPage/>
                        <jb:ExternalDocuments>
                            <jb:UserR1Doc>
                                <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
                                <jb:FileName>DCSA PB21 - R1 Report_012220v2_DCSA#JFpAx.pdf</jb:FileName>
                            </jb:UserR1Doc>
                        </jb:ExternalDocuments>
                        <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                            <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
                            <jb:WorkFlowStatus>FINAL</jb:WorkFlowStatus>
                            <jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>Title(s) undefined</jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
                            <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
                            <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
                        </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                        <r2:ProgramElementList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
                            <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0604130V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Enterprise Security System (ESS)</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                <r2:R1LineNumber>199</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetYear>2021</r2:BudgetYear>
                                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                <r2:SubmissionDate>2020-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:AllPriorYears>123.200</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>9.395</r2:PriorYear>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>7.945</r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>14.632</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>13.490</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>9.685</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Counterintelligence Security Agency (DCSA) formerly known as the Defense Security Service (DSS) is a strategic asset to the nation and our allies – continuously ensuring a trusted federal, industrial, and affiliated workforce, and enabling industry’s delivery of uncompromised capabilities by leveraging advanced technologies and innovation.  DCSA uniquely blend critical technology protection, trusted personnel vetting, counterintelligence, and professional education and certification to advance and preserve America’s strategic edge.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>9.395</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>7.945</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>9.395</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>7.945</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                        <r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        </r2:CongressionalDirectedReductions>
                                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>National Industrial Security System (NISS) development consists of continued enhancements in response to user community requirements. These requirements consist of enhancements to Key Management Personnel (KMP) monitoring, NATO Control Point Inspection Triage Outreach Program, NISP Oversight Report, Outgoing Foreign Visits and enabling Industry with the ability to initiate Facility Profile updates.  A separate, parallel development effort will facilitate a SIPR NISS baseline consisting of an alternative Single Sign-On (SSO) capability to National Industrial Security Program (NISP) Central Access Information Security System (NCAISS), as well as Cross Domain Solution (CDS) for movement of NIPR-based data to SIPR for subsequent reporting and data aggregation. Development activities will include interface work between NISS and the Defense Information System for Security (DISS), NISP Contracts Classification System (NCCS) and Enterprise Mission Assurance Support Service (eMASS) systems as well as initial planning for refactoring of NISS functionality into National Background Investigative Services (NBIS). Achievement of Full Operational Capability (FOC) delayed due to the of the Period of Performance (PoP)2 which is scheduled for a March 2020 completion.  

The Adaptive Data Exchange (ADX)/ Joint Cyber Intelligence Tool Suite (JCITS) will assist DCSA with analysis of network telemetry data gathered from the JCITS unclassified cyber threat intelligence data, cleared contractor reporting and other government agency feeds for detecting anomalous behavior and enhancing data.

The Defense Information System for Security (DISS) which transfers to DCSA from DHRA/ DMDC beginning FY2021 is to consolidate the DoD personnel security mission into an enterprise adjudicative case management system that will automate the implementation of improved national investigative and adjudicative standards to eliminate costly and inefficient work processes and increase information collaboration across the community. This will provide comprehensive capabilities to perform processing and verification of security clearances for all DoD military personnel, civilians and contrators including the technology and processes to implement Continuous Evaluation.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                <r2:ProjectList>
                                    <r2:Project>
                                        <r2:ProjectNumber>000</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Enterprise Security System (ESS)</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:AllPriorYears>123.200</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>9.395</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>7.945</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>14.378</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>14.632</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>13.490</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>9.685</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Defense Counterintelligence Security Agency (DCSA) manages the Enterprise Security System (ESS) to provide an effective, real-time, security support capabilities for Military Departments, DoD Agencies, the NISP, and other Federal Agencies.  In compliance with the Expanded Electronic Government, President’s Management Agenda, and the DoD Enterprise Architecture Framework, Enterprise Security System (ESS) is the unified offering of security mission systems to facilitate and automate improved national investigative standards, streamline security processes, and increase DoD community collaboration.

DCSA Mission Information Technology (IT) systems provide critical service to the major DCSA mission areas for Industrial Security Oversight and Security Education.  DCSA performs this critical function through operation of its mission production systems to include the National Industrial Security System (NISS) and the DCSA Gateway. RDT&amp;E for DCSA mission systems primarily includes pre-planned product enhancements and improvements to the applications, research and improve assured information sharing to better posture systems and networks against vulnerabilities, ensure self-defense of systems and networks, and safeguard data at all stages to increase efficiencies through web-based systems to manage certification and accreditation activities. These IT systems are as follows:   

National Industrial Security System (NISS, formerly known as Field Operations System (FOS).  NISS is the next generation functional replacement for the Industrial Security Facility Database system (ISFD) and supports end to end facility identification and registration processing, Foreign Ownership Control or Influence (FOCI) mitigation, and supports Personnel Vetting business processes.  NISS provides a centralized web-based platform for National Industrial Security Program (NISP) personnel to manage the industrial security facility clearance process; from request initiation to approval (or rejection) storage of all associated data, and provides a centralized process for users to submit, update, search, and view facility verification requests.    

National Contract Classification System (NCCS).  NCCS is a web-based system that automates the DD Form 254 for contract security classification specification submission; provides submitter with intuitive form of instructions, drop-down selections, and linkage to relevant contract information for completing the form; and provides user access control, query/search, notification, tracking, and reporting capabilities for accountability of all contract security classification specifications. The Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) requires a DD Form 254 for each classified contract, and the National Industrial Security Operating Manual (NISPOM)(4-103a) requires a DD 254 be issued by the government with each Invitation for Bid, Request for Proposal, or Request for Quote. The DD Form 254 provides contractor (or a subcontractor) the security requirements and classification guidance necessary to perform on a classified contract. Contract Security Classification Specification required by DoD 5220.22-4, Industrial Security Regulation and the National Industrial Security Program Operating Manual (NISPOM) is to develop a federated system for the oversight and management of classified information access and guidance to perform on classified contracts. The DD 254, an underlying business process, is critical to ensure access to our Nation’s classified information is safeguarded.

National Industrial Security Program (NISP) DCSA NISP Central Access and Information Security System (NCAISS) a web-based Identity Management (IdM) enterprise portal, PKI compliant point-of-entry to the suite of services offered by DCSA, which controls user service accessibility through single sign-on authentication. User service-level permissions are verified, and authorized services are offered accordingly. Control Access and Information Security System (NCAISS) formerly known as Identity Management (IdM).  NCAISS is mandatory for compliance with Department of Defense (DoD) Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) Program Management Office and Office of the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Networks and Information Integration (ASD-NII), Joint Task Force for Global Networks Operations (JTF-GNO) Communications Tasking Order (CTO) 06-02, CTO 07-015, and Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Memo 11-11 (M-11-11), which directed accelerated use of PKI access across the enterprise.  This initiative is designed to enable multiple DCSA business systems to have service-accessibility that is controlled through PKI-compliant single sign-on authentication.  Potential expanded use of the NCAISS across the DCSA enterprise to provide CAC-based authentication for business support applications to support the SIPRNet and JWICS domains, provide enhanced identity and access control analytics. It incorporates any remaining DCSA operated application into the DcSA NCAISS solution.

DCSA is establishing a Controlled Unclassified Information (CUI) program for industry that requires development and implementation of tools that support integration with cybersecurity monitoring, threat indications and
warning, and supply chain illumination to protect critical technology. The development of a Security Rating Score (SRS) and its integration with the Contract Performance Assessment System will inform defense acquisition
decisions and prioritize DCSA Industrial Security with active monitoring of companies in a single system of record. Funding will purchase data licenses for supply chain illumination tools that can be integrated into CUI
cybersecurity assessments and will include business process tools to integrate data and manage DCSA business unit inputs from industrial and personnel security inputs. Funds will also support use of Artificial
Intelligence / Machine Learning to accelerate and enhance cyber I&amp;W via predictive analytics.

The Defense Information System for Security (DISS) is to consolidate the DoD personnel security mission into an enterprise adjudicative case management system that will automate the implementation of improved national investigative and adjudicative standards to eliminate costly and inefficient work processes and increase information collaboration across the community to provide comprehensive capabilities to perform processing and verification of security clearances for all DoD military personnel, civilians, and contractors including the technology and processes that need to be addressed in order to implement Continuous Evaluation.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                    <r2:Title>Systems Enhancement</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Description>Accomplishments:
1. NISS. Complete development of NISS Increment 2. Deploy NISS Increment 2 IOC in 2Q FY19. Initiate development of NISS Increment 3. Increment 3 will include enhancements to KMP monitoring, NATO CPI, Triage Outreach Program, NISP Oversight Report, and Outgoing Foreign Visits. Initiate Independent Verification and Verification (IV&amp;V) and Government Acceptance Testing (GAT) of Increment 2. IV&amp;V and GAT findings will be addressed.
2. NCCS. Continue scheduled enhancements through version releases and sustainment. Agile development approach will continue with two release cycles per year. Address any findings/bugs/issues encountered from Independent Verification and Verification (IV&amp;V) and Government Acceptance Testing (GAT).
3. NCAISS. No RDT&amp;E funding required.  Continue integration and application sustainment costs under the sustainment contract, with some software upgrades.3. NCAISS. Continue integration and application sustainment activities.  Contract period of performance ends 1st Qtr FY19.
4. eFCL. Usage of systems has been retired from DCSA use.</r2:Description>
                                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                                            <r2:Funding>9.395</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>1.	NISS. Continue development of NISS Increment 2. Increment 2 will include a SIPR instance of NISS, a Cross-domain Solution, and add enhancements to Security Violations, Security Vulnerability Assessments, and
Suspicious Contact Reports. Initiate Independent Verification and Verification (IV&amp;V) and Government Acceptance Testing (GAT) of Increment 2. IV&amp;V and GAT findings will be addressed. Initiate planning of NISS Increment 3.

2.	NCCS. Continue scheduled enhancements through version releases and sustainment. Agile development approach; two release cycles per year. Future enhancements will address updates to the New DD254 Form.
3.	NCAISS. Final option year on current contract completed and NCAISS will be in full operational capability (FOC) sustainment. Complete final transition activities for NCAISS over to Data Center Operations. Long-term sustainment actions and funding will then be aligned by EITS contract support.
4.	eFCL. DSS will sunset use eFCL once capabilities have transitioned into NISS.
5.	ISFD. DSS will retire ISFD once capabilities have transitioned into NISS.</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:Funding>7.945</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>1.) NISS. Continue development of NISS NIPR enhancements. Development of NISS SIPR Increment, IOC projected by Q4 FY20. 
2.)Initiate development of NISS Cross Domain Solution (CDS) 
3.) NIPR NISS Enhancements to Key Management Personnel (KMP) monitoring, NATO CPI, Triage Outreach Program, NISP Oversight Report, Outgoing Foreign Visits and Facility Profile. 
4.) Refine Processes and Requirements for Critical Threat Protection (CTP). 
5.)Initiate Independent Verification and Verification (IV&amp;V) and Government Acceptance Testing (GAT) of NIPR and SIPR NISS IV&amp;V and GAT findings will be addressed</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:Funding>14.378</r2:Funding>
                                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                            <r2:Funding>14.378</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>The application will require both MilCloud and alternative cloud instances for National Background Investigative Services (NBIS) refactoring related activities. 

Hardware and software required for the SIPR NISS instance will double overall development ramp-up costs.  NISS interfaces with DISS, NCCS and eMASS will drive additional developer expense, with only initial requirements or Technical Interchanges having been conducted to-date.  

Development efforts for enhancements (Key Management Personnel (KMP) monitoring, NATO CPI, Triage Outreach Program, NISP Oversight Report, and Outgoing Foreign Visits) were delayed due to a late FOC for NISS NIPR baseline

Adaptive Data Exchange (ADP)/JCITS will assist DCSA with analysis of network telemetry data gathered from the Joint Cyber Intelligence Tool Suite, unclassified cyber threat intelligence data, cleared contractor reporting and other government agency feeds for detecting anomalous behavior and enhancing data.

Funding will be used to complete development of the DISS functionality necessary to sunset the Joint Personnel Adjudication System (JPAS).</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        <r2:AppChangeSummary>The increase from FY20 to FY21 provides funding for ADX/JCITS funding will assist DCSA with analysis of network telemetry data gathered from the Joint Cyber Intelligence Tool Suite, unclassified cyber threat intelligence data, cleared contractor reporting and other government agency feeds for detecting anomalous behavior and enhancing data.

Transfers in from DHRA/DMDC funding for continued development of DISS.</r2:AppChangeSummary>
                                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>DCSA will use a variety of acquisition strategies such as Indefinite Delivery, Indefinite Quantity (IDIQ), Blanket Purchase Agreements (BPA), and multiple or single award contracts for the development of new applications, enhancement of other applications, and perform system integration with COTS and GOTS solutions and technology. These efforts will reduce the contract award process lead time and contract overhead, improve technical solutions, deployments, and deliver more effective and efficient automation projects for DCSA and the NISP community.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                                            <r2:Remarks>The Enterprise Security System supports development efforts of the next generation of integrated enterprise automated security solutions to replace DSS legacy IT systems to provide seamless integration of applications.</r2:Remarks>
                                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>NISS Development</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                                            <r2:ContractType>TBD</r2:ContractType>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>TBD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>TBD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>114.305</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>7.940</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2019-05</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>6.603</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-05</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>5.784</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>5.784</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>NISS Development/MilCloud</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>DISA</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Pensacola, FL</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>0.600</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.500</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2019-05</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.500</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-05</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>NCAISS Development</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:ContractMethod>Option</r2:ContractMethod>
                                                            <r2:ContractType>BPA</r2:ContractType>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Deloitt</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Arlington VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>3.740</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>NCCS Development</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>DLA</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Philadelphia, PA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>3.312</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.600</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2018-10</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.600</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2019-10</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-10</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>SBIR/STTR</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>AT&amp;L</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Arlington, VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>1.243</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.355</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2019-05</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.242</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-05</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>ADX/JCITS</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:ContractMethod>Option</r2:ContractMethod>
                                                            <r2:ContractType>TBD</r2:ContractType>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>TBD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>TBD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>4.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>4.000</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-04</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>DISS Development</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>TBD</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>TBD</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>TBD</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>4.594</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>4.594</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                                        <r2:R4aExhibit>
                                            <r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                                <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                                    <r2:Title>Enterprise Security System</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                        <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                            <r2:EventTitle>Production and Deployment of Appllications</r2:EventTitle>
                                                            <r2:Schedule>
                                                                <r2:Start>
                                                                    <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                                    <r2:Year>2017</r2:Year>
                                                                </r2:Start>
                                                                <r2:End>
                                                                    <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                                    <r2:Year>2025</r2:Year>
                                                                </r2:End>
                                                            </r2:Schedule>
                                                        </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                    </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                            </r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                        </r2:R4aExhibit>
                                    </r2:Project>
                                </r2:ProjectList>
                            </r2:ProgramElement>
                            <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0305128V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Security and Investigative Activities</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                <r2:R1LineNumber>231</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetYear>2021</r2:BudgetYear>
                                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                <r2:SubmissionDate>2020-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>2.400</r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency (DCSA) manages the Defense Vetting Directorate (DVD) for the entire government to support personnel vetting requirements. DVD has established itself as the mission authority for personnel security, continuous vetting, and insider threat for the federal government. Continuous Vetting (CV) program incorporates continual monitoring of individuals in support of the federal investigation standards for security clearances. This funding facilitates  critical objectives the Risk Rating Tool and a Research &amp; Innovation fund for future capabilities. DVD continues to develop the Risk Rating Tool (RRT) to focus data acquisition on individuals demonstrating high risk behaviors as identified by machine learning modeling approaches. DVD will expand, test, and evaluate RRT models for the entire DoD population. The second objective of the funds is to establish a Behavioral Research and Innovation fund to support such entities as PERSEREC to continue to understand cleared populations, validate and or inform policy offices, and support in the development of business rules with scientifically backed recommendations. Additional the funds in the out years will support prototypes, and pilots in Continuous Vetting to ensure an agile ability to test and evaluate state of the art technology that can support and off set existing Continuous Vetting processes in such areas as: Robotic Process Automation, Gamification, Bio-Metrics/Credibility, Augmented Reality, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Chatbots, and other state of the art technologies that can be developed, prototyped, and piloted.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>2.400</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>2.400</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                <r2:Title>One Time Increase</r2:Title>
                                                <r2:Funding>
                                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                </r2:Funding>
                                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                <r2:ProjectList>
                                    <r2:Project>
                                        <r2:ProjectNumber>000</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Risk Rating Tool</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>2.400</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>5.700</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency manages the Defense Vetting Directorate (DVD) for the entire government to support personnel vetting requirements. DVD has established itself as the mission authority for personnel security, vetting, and insider threat for the federal government. Continuous Evaluation (CE) program incorporates continual monitoring of individuals in support of the federal investigation standards for security clearances. This funding facilities two critical objectives the Risk Rating Tool and a Research &amp; Innovation fund for future capabilities. DVD continues to develop the Risk Rating Tool (RRT) to focus data acquisition on individuals demonstrating high behaviors risk as identified by Machine Learning modeling approaches. DVD will expand, test, and evaluate RRT models for the entire DoD population. The second objective of the funds is to establish a Behavioral Research and Innovation fund to support such entities as PERSEREC to continue to understand cleared populations, validate and or inform policy offices, and support in the development of business rules with scientifically back recommendations. Additional the funds in out years will support prototypes, and pilots in Continuous Vetting to ensure an agile ability to test and evaluate state of the art technology that can support and off set existing Continuous Vetting processes in such areas as: Robotic Process Automation, Gamification, Bio-Metrics/Credibility, Augmented Reality, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Chatbots, and other state of the art technologies that can be developed, prototyped, and piloted.

DVD will utilize the Risk Rating Tool models to identify individuals with high risk stressors mapped to the 13 Adjudicative guidelines. Use of the Risk Rating Tool for case management and enrollment into High, Medium, Low Continuous Vetting Tier management is projected to generate cost avoidance in data acquisition by focusing resources on high risks rather than a randomly selected process. Execution of small scale prototypes or pilots will facilitate demonstrating value added before full scale integration, ensuring funds are not executed on an effort that cannot scale or meet all requirements.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                    <r2:Title>RRT</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:Funding>2.400</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>1.	RRT. Continue development of RRT models with integration of results in future system of use with the National Background Investigation System.  
2.	Expansion of population to support full DoD Eligible personnel
 
3.      Expansion of data sets incorporating data currently utilized in systems such as DISS, and MIRADOR</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:Funding>5.700</r2:Funding>
                                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                            <r2:Funding>5.700</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>1.	RRT. Continue development of RRT models with integration of results in future system of use with the National Background Investigation System.  
2.	Establishment of a Research &amp; innovation Fund for Behavioral Research and policy impacts/recommendations as well as state of the art testing and evaluation of capabilities that can support continuous vetting and provide cost savings</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        <r2:AppChangeSummary>Support prototypes, and pilots in Continuous Vetting to ensure an agile ability to test and evaluate state of the art technology that can support and off set existing Continuous Vetting processes in such areas as: Robotic Process Automation, Gamification, Bio-Metrics/Credibility, Augmented Reality, Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Chatbots, and other state of the art technologies that can be developed, prototyped, and piloted.</r2:AppChangeSummary>
                                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                    <r2:Title>NA</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                                            <r2:Funding>0.000</r2:Funding>
                                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>Risk Rating Tool - GOTS Model Development</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Army Analytics Group</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Monterey, California</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>2.200</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2019-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>5.500</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>5.500</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>Risk Rating Tool - COTS Model Development</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:FundingVehicle>MIPR</r2:FundingVehicle>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>Army Analytics Group</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Monterey, California</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2019-08</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>0.200</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-08</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                                                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                                        <r2:R4aExhibit>
                                            <r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                                <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                                    <r2:Title>Risk Rating Tool</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                        <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                            <r2:EventTitle>Production and Deployment</r2:EventTitle>
                                                            <r2:Schedule>
                                                                <r2:Start>
                                                                    <r2:Quarter>3</r2:Quarter>
                                                                    <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                                                </r2:Start>
                                                                <r2:End>
                                                                    <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                                    <r2:Year>2021</r2:Year>
                                                                </r2:End>
                                                            </r2:Schedule>
                                                        </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                    </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                            </r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                        </r2:R4aExhibit>
                                    </r2:Project>
                                </r2:ProjectList>
                            </r2:ProgramElement>
                            <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0305327V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Insider Threat</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                <r2:R1LineNumber>244</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetYear>2021</r2:BudgetYear>
                                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                <r2:SubmissionDate>2020-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>7</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Operational Systems Development</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:AllPriorYears>23.502</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>5.954</r2:PriorYear>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>1.964</r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The DoD Insider Threat Management and Analysis Center (DITMAC):  Oversees the mitigation of insider threats to DoD and U.S. Government installations, facilities, personnel, missions, or resources; Assess enterprise-level risks, refer recommendations for action, synchronize responses, and oversee resolution of identified issues on the insider threats; Develops enterprise-level risk reporting criteria (thresholds) to facilitate component reporting of potential threat information and assess the effectiveness of actions taken by reporting elements to address, mitigate, or resolve the threat posed to DoD missions and resources; Supports the Office of the USD(I) in establishing standards to ensure that the DoD Insider Threat Program comply with applicable statutes, Executive Orders, and other national and DoD regulations and policies that specify insider threat program requirements; Provides a single repository for enterprise-level DoD insider threat-related information; and promotes the collaboration and the insider threat information sharing among DoD Components.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>5.954</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>1.964</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>5.954</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>1.964</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                <r2:ProjectList>
                                    <r2:Project>
                                        <r2:ProjectNumber>002</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                        <r2:ProjectTitle>Insider Threat</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:AllPriorYears>23.502</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>5.954</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>1.964</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The DoD Insider Threat Management and Analysis Center (DITMAC):  Oversees the mitigation of insider threats to DoD and U.S. Government installations, facilities, personnel, missions, or resources; Assess enterprise-level risks, refer recommendations for action, synchronize responses, and oversee resolution of identified issues on the insider threats; Develops enterprise-level risk reporting criteria (thresholds) to facilitate component reporting of potential threat information and assess the effectiveness of actions taken by reporting elements to address, mitigate, or resolve the threat posed to DoD missions and resources; Supports the Office of the USD(I) in establishing standards to ensure that the DoD Insider Threat Program comply with applicable statutes, Executive Orders, and other national and DoD regulations and policies that specify insider threat program requirements; Provides a single repository for enterprise-level DoD insider threat-related information; and promotes the collaboration and the insider threat information sharing among DoD Components.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                    <r2:Title>Insider Threat</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Description>Continued development of capabilities to better serve the insider threat community, and align with Personnel Vetting mission. Maturing of the systems has facilitated increased use of the DSoS as the case management system for DoD Component’s insider threat mission from 11 reported in 2017 to 37 as of 4th quarter 2018. The system redesign provides the next generation platform that can pace and align with the expanding mission. The re-architecture will deliver a new platform that fosters communication/information sharing, adaptability, and an enhanced cyber posture while reducing annual investments in software licensing and technical support.</r2:Description>
                                                    <r2:Accomplishment>
                                                        <r2:PriorYear>
                                                            <r2:Funding>5.954</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>Enhancements to the new platform; development and integration of additional advanced analytic capabilities; assessment of new technologies and interfaces between security domains and with external data sources on behalf of the enterprise.</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:PriorYear>
                                                    </r2:Accomplishment>
                                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            <r2:Funding>1.964</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>Continue enhancements to the new platform; development and integration of additional advanced analytic capabilities; assessment of new technologies and interfaces between security domains and with external data sources on behalf of the enterprise.</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                        <r2:AppChangeSummary>The decrease from FY20 to FY21 is due to the completion of the DSoS development efforts.</r2:AppChangeSummary>
                                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                            <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>N/A</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                        <r2:R3Exhibit>
                                            <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                                <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                                    <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                                    <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                        <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                            <r2:Name>DITMAC System Of Systems</r2:Name>
                                                            <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                                            <r2:ContractType>CPFF</r2:ContractType>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivity>NOVETTA</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                                            <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Mclean, VA</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                                            <r2:Cost>
                                                                <r2:TotalPreviousYears>23.502</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                                                <r2:PriorYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>5.954</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2019-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:PriorYear>
                                                                <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                                    <r2:Amount>1.964</r2:Amount>
                                                                    <r2:AwardDate>2020-09</r2:AwardDate>
                                                                </r2:CurrentYear>
                                                            </r2:Cost>
                                                        </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                                    </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                                </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                            </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                                        </r2:R3Exhibit>
                                        <r2:R4aExhibit>
                                            <r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                                <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                                    <r2:Title>Insider Threat</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                        <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                            <r2:EventTitle>Production Development</r2:EventTitle>
                                                            <r2:Schedule>
                                                                <r2:Start>
                                                                    <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                                    <r2:Year>2015</r2:Year>
                                                                </r2:Start>
                                                                <r2:End>
                                                                    <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                                    <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                                                </r2:End>
                                                            </r2:Schedule>
                                                        </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                                    </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                                </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                            </r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                                        </r2:R4aExhibit>
                                    </r2:Project>
                                </r2:ProjectList>
                            </r2:ProgramElement>
                            <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions">
                                <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0608197V</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
                                <r2:ProgramElementTitle>National Background Investigation Services - Software Pilot Program</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
                                <r2:R1LineNumber>269</r2:R1LineNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetYear>2021</r2:BudgetYear>
                                <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
                                <r2:SubmissionDate>2020-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
                                <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
                                <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
                                <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>8</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
                                <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>Software and Digital Technology Pilot Programs</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
                                <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                    <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearTwo>124.587</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearThree>127.330</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFour>129.371</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearFive>131.966</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                    <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                    <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                                <r2:ProgramElementNote>This effort is not a new start in FY2021. It continues FY2020 development effort funded in PE 0303430K, Federal Investigative Services Information Technology.</r2:ProgramElementNote>
                                <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>The Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency acquires, develops, and deploys software and manages digital talent to support the development of a modernized Federal Government background investigation information technology (IT) systems(s) to replace the current legacy IT systems formerly the responsibility of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) and provide a highly secured infrastructure. DoD assumed modernization efforts beginning in FY 2017, as decided by the Interagency Deputies Committee and the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). Funds support the development, sustainment, technical refresh of hardware and software, Cloud migration, and program management costs to develop and field a modernized Federal Investigation System. This modernized capability's data architecture will leverage and extend the existing secure Information Technology capabilities inherent to DoD infrastructure to the federal wide background investigation processes and data archives. This approach will provide essential security of this information and in turn protect the identities, lives, and livelihoods of these people, and the family members and associates identified as part of these records. The aim is to avert or eliminate the continuous and dynamic threat of identity theft, financial espionage and other attacks on this personal information, while providing a secure basis for background investigations necessary to Federal and DoD operations.
Using proven data architecture and identifiable security, DCSA will leverage critical and inherent information technology (IT) security capabilities; identify means and methods to efficiently and securely access digital services; enhance systems necessary to operate the background investigation processes and associated vast reservoirs of data and interfaces; provide Government-wide tools to assist agencies with workforce management; and, develop and provide investigative products that comply with the new, Federal Investigations Standards and Workforce 2.0. Resources will be used to implement and sustain agency network upgrades and security software maintenance to ensure a stronger, more reliable, and better protected network architecture for conducting background investigations. Costs include program management activities, payroll for security specialists, engineers, data architects, and business process management activities to develop, test, and deploy the new capability. As capabilities are fielded NBIS and DCSA will provide system maintenance, security licenses and operational support to the system and users worldwide.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
                                <r2:ChangeSummary>
                                    <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                                    <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                                    <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                        <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                            <r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                                <r2:Title>Establishment of Software Pilot Program</r2:Title>
                                                <r2:Funding>
                                                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                </r2:Funding>
                                            </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetail>
                                        </r2:OtherAdjustmentDetailList>
                                    </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                                    <r2:SummaryExplanation>Supports execution of software development, procurement, modification, and operations and maintenance using RDT&amp;E for pilot programs specified in BA 8.</r2:SummaryExplanation>
                                </r2:ChangeSummary>
                                <r2:ProjectList>
                                    <r2:Project>
                                        <r2:ProjectNumber>000</r2:ProjectNumber>
                                        <r2:ProjectTitle>National Background Investigation Services - Software Pilot Program</r2:ProjectTitle>
                                        <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                                        <r2:ProjectFunding>
                                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0.000</r2:AllPriorYears>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>121.676</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>124.587</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearThree>127.330</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFour>129.371</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearFive>131.966</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                        </r2:ProjectFunding>
                                        <r2:R2aExhibit>
                                            <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>The Defense Counterintelligence and Security acquires, develops, and deploys software and manages digital talent. The system used for this is the National Background Investigation Services (NBIS) which supports the government-wide background investigation process; replacing the OPM's legacy systems that were breached in 2015. The objectives of NBIS enhances security, meets new policy requirements, reduces the backlog of pending cases, and realizes cost avoidance as legacy systems are retired. The system establishes and streamlines the requirements intake (software factory model), establish as a services approach, implements the DevSecOps pipeline, standardizes test processes, automates unit component, and integration testing, implements cyber processes to achieve continuous ATO, consolidates help desk activities, and enhances monitoring capabilities.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                                <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                                    <r2:Title>Software Pilot Program</r2:Title>
                                                    <r2:Description>The Defense Counterintelligence and Security acquires, develops, and deploys software and manages digital talent. The system used for this is the National Background Investigation Services (NBIS) which supports the government-wide background investigation process; replacing the OPM's legacy systems that were breached in 2015. The objectives of NBIS enhances security, meets new policy requirements, reduces the backlog of pending cases, and realizes cost avoidance as legacy systems are retired. The system establishes and streamlines the requirements intake (software factory model), establish as a services approach, implements the DevSecOps pipeline, standardizes test processes, automates unit component, and integration testing, implements cyber processes to achieve continuous ATO, consolidates help desk activities, and enhances monitoring capabilities.</r2:Description>
                                                    <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                            <r2:Funding>121.676</r2:Funding>
                                                        </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                            <r2:Funding>121.676</r2:Funding>
                                                            <r2:Text>FY 2021 O&amp;M Plans: $83.176
NBIS will continue to provide support functions for DMDC capabilities that are running in the DISA Data Centers along with the COOP to ensure continuous operations in event of failure. NBIS will leverage programmatic, operations and support contracts to provide Program Control, Financial and Budget support as well as the Operations functions to support the Cloud environment and transition of existing and new services into the Gov Cloud environments. NBIS will provide travel, non-centralized training, credit card, supplies, new laptops, Joint Enterprise Licensing Agreement (JELA) costs, and common licensing costs that supports running a PEO and Program Office. Finally, in FY2021 NBIS will pay any residual moving costs required for the transition from the DISA campus to a DCSA facility. Additionally, under Budget Authority (BA) 8, the previous BA4 funds will be capitalized to offset the shortfalls in the previous BA7 funds to continue development of the evolving Investigation Services.


FY 2021 RDT&amp;E Plans: $38.500
DoD will continue to develop, enhance and improve the capabilities. As part of an Agile development process, the National Background Investigation System (NBIS) will deploy additional releases in FY21 to improve automation of the background investigation process, improve analytics to address insider threat analysis, improve continuous evaluation capabilities, and develop capabilities to meet additional Federal Agency requirements (e.g., Trusted Workforce 2.0). The system will continue to defend against cyber-attacks and improve defensibility by meeting new and evolving threats. Specifically, NBIS will continue to support Investigation Management (IM) Development for automation, new models, rules engines, and algorithms for optimization of assignments (i.e., continuous development); continue evolving the automation of IT infrastructure and DevSecOps tools and processes; implement Security Enterprise Architecture and Data Services to develop the capability to re-use data and analytics across multiple security missions, all while, simplifying system security and user access; supporting business transformation and late-derived requirements, technology change management, and Tier support for the NBIS Customers; identifying, developing, and testing multiple prototype efforts; and continuing to evolve and execute the adjusted implementation strategy based on lessons learned from prototype efforts and results of independent assessments.</r2:Text>
                                                        </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                        <r2:AppChangeSummary>The increase from FY 2020 to FY 2021 is due to the implementation of a pilot Budget Authority that combines the NBIS funding lines to better support the movement of Continual Evaluation (CE)/Continuous Vetting (CV) Compliance; Data Sources (CV Data Sources Connections); NBIS Application Development (eApp, NBIS Billing, IMT1 and Adjudication); and NBIS IT Infrastructure (Amazon Web Service (AWS) Gov Cloud and DevSecOps Pipeline) from development and testing to implementation and sustainment.</r2:AppChangeSummary>
                                                    </r2:PlannedProgram>
                                                </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                                        </r2:R2aExhibit>
                                    </r2:Project>
                                </r2:ProjectList>
                            </r2:ProgramElement>
                        </r2:ProgramElementList>
                    </jb:JustificationBook>
                </jb:JustificationBookInfo>
            </jb:JustificationBookInfoList>
        </jb:JustificationBookGroup>
    </jb:JustificationBookGroupList>
</jb:MasterJustificationBook>