<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2021</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2020-02</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Contract Management Agency</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0400</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserR1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit R-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>R1_DCMA#iumjT.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserR1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:WorkFlowStatus>FINAL</jb:WorkFlowStatus>
        <jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>Title(s) undefined</jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateProgramElementTocByBA>
        <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <r2:ProgramElementList xmlns:r2="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/r2" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
        <r2:ProgramElement monetaryUnit="Millions">
            <r2:ProgramElementNumber>0605013BL</r2:ProgramElementNumber>
            <r2:ProgramElementTitle>Information Technology Development</r2:ProgramElementTitle>
            <r2:R1LineNumber>129</r2:R1LineNumber>
            <r2:BudgetYear>2021</r2:BudgetYear>
            <r2:BudgetCycle>PB</r2:BudgetCycle>
            <r2:SubmissionDate>2020-02</r2:SubmissionDate>
            <r2:ServiceAgencyName>Defense Contract Management Agency</r2:ServiceAgencyName>
            <r2:AppropriationCode>0400</r2:AppropriationCode>
            <r2:AppropriationName>Research, Development, Test &amp; Evaluation, Defense-Wide</r2:AppropriationName>
            <r2:BudgetActivityNumber>5</r2:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <r2:BudgetActivityTitle>System Development &amp; Demonstration (SDD)</r2:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <r2:ProgramElementFunding>
                <r2:AllPriorYears>178.795</r2:AllPriorYears>
                <r2:PriorYear>11.988</r2:PriorYear>
                <r2:CurrentYear>3.070</r2:CurrentYear>
                <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
            </r2:ProgramElementFunding>
            <r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>DCMA is currently engaged in several major initiatives to improve our information technology environment.  Information technology is the primary enabling capability our acquisition workforce is reliant upon to communicate with contractors, the DoD acquisition community and our customers.  These initiatives are driven by the National Defense Strategy business reform line of effort.  On December 21, 2017, the Reform Management Group directed the Information Technology (IT) and Business Systems Reform Lead to review Fourth Estate IT networks, policies, business processes, functions, costs and Chief Information Officer (CIO) organizational structures and manpower requirements across the Fourth Estate.  In support of this directive, DCMA is structuring its information technology investments to be in synchronization with the vision of the DoD guidance. One early result of this review is the decision to transfer commodity information technology administrative control to Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA), which will occur in FY 2021. 

DCMA's IT investment strategy is being driven by the Director's initiatives to: 1) Develop Mission Business Systems; 2) Leverage Commodity IT Buying Power Through DISA; and 3) Focus On The Last Tactical Mile.  These initiatives directly align and support the Optimization and Modernization efforts of the DoD CIO, which include: 1) Network Optimization; 2) Data Center Optimization; 3) Mission Partner Engagement; 4) Defense Travel Modernization ; 5) Enterprise Collaboration; 6) Consolidation of Cyber and IT Responsibilities; 7) Rationalize Business Systems; 8) Streamline IT Commodity Purchasing.

Development and research initiatives are a core component in DCMA’s ability to align efforts appropriately to the DoD CIO IT Reform Initiative. In order to meet the needs of the DoD community, DCMA’s current efforts are focused on the development of investments in two core areas: 1)  DCMA App Store; and 2) Wide Area Work-Flow (WAWF).
 
These initiatives will empower mobile and fixed users ability to  utilize DoD enterprise capabilities with the same level or better efficiency and effectiveness. DCMA also has a mandate to align with DoD strategy for digital modernization of enterprise capabilities. This involves migrating DCMA application infrastructure to enterprise hosting environments and modern technology platforms, rationalizing existing applications to ensure capabilities align with mission requirements, and adopting new DoD strategies for modern software development methodologies.</r2:ProgramElementMissionDescription>
            <r2:ChangeSummary>
                <r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>11.988</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>3.070</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:PreviousPresidentBudget>
                <r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                    <r2:PriorYear>11.988</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>3.070</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:CurrentPresidentBudget>
                <r2:TotalAdjustments>
                    <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    <r2:CurrentYear>0.000</r2:CurrentYear>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0.000</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                </r2:TotalAdjustments>
                <r2:AdjustmentDetails>
                    <r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                        <r2:PriorYear>0.000</r2:PriorYear>
                    </r2:CongressionalGeneralReductions>
                </r2:AdjustmentDetails>
            </r2:ChangeSummary>
            <r2:ProjectList>
                <r2:Project>
                    <r2:ProjectNumber>01</r2:ProjectNumber>
                    <r2:ProjectTitle>Systems Modifications and Development</r2:ProjectTitle>
                    <r2:SpecialProject>0</r2:SpecialProject>
                    <r2:ProjectFunding>
                        <r2:AllPriorYears>178.795</r2:AllPriorYears>
                        <r2:PriorYear>11.988</r2:PriorYear>
                        <r2:CurrentYear>3.070</r2:CurrentYear>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOne>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                        <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>1.441</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                        <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0.000</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        <r2:BudgetYearThree>0.000</r2:BudgetYearThree>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFour>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFour>
                        <r2:BudgetYearFive>0.000</r2:BudgetYearFive>
                        <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                        <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                    </r2:ProjectFunding>
                    <r2:R2aExhibit>
                        <r2:ProjectArticles>
                            <r2:AllPriorYears>0</r2:AllPriorYears>
                            <r2:PriorYear>0</r2:PriorYear>
                            <r2:CurrentYear>0</r2:CurrentYear>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>0</r2:BudgetYearOne>
                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>0</r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                            <r2:BudgetYearTwo>0</r2:BudgetYearTwo>
                        </r2:ProjectArticles>
                        <r2:ProjectMissionDescription>Development and research initiatives are a core component in DCMA’s ability to align efforts appropriately to the DoD CIO IT Reform Initiative. DCMA has a mandate to align with DoD strategy for digital modernization of enterprise capabilities. This involves migrating DCMA application infrastructure to enterprise hosting environments and modern technology platforms, rationalizing existing applications to ensure capabilities align with mission requirements, and adopting new DoD strategies for modern software development methodologies.  This will ensure delivery of secure, interoperable, and optimized solutions.  In order to meet the needs of the DoD community, DCMA’s current effort is to develop the DCMA App Store.</r2:ProjectMissionDescription>
                        <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                            <r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                                <r2:Title>System Modifications and Development</r2:Title>
                                <r2:Description>The DCMA will use the system and modifications program to focus on two main efforts which support: 1) messaging and collaboration (DCMA App Store). The DCMA App Store is required to centralize DCMA's acquisition mission specific applications into one application platform that will be housed on a DISA existing Impact Level 4 accredited cloud platform.This effort is predicated on the implementation of the 4th Estate IT Reform Initiative, which includes migrating application workloads to milCloud2. DCMA began this migration effort in FY 2019, but schedule delays have shift the start of the business application modernization to 3rd Quarter FY 2020.</r2:Description>
                                <r2:Accomplishment>
                                    <r2:PriorYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>11.988</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>MOCAS
In FY 2019 the MOCAS JPMO's focus will transition from modernizing business processes to implementing the modernized conceptual design architectures. The JPMO anticipates the legacy MOCAS architecture transition will commence through prototyping and analysis of detailed designs of early development focused on three key enterprise service segments; Data Migration and Stabilization, Enhanced Reporting and User Workflow Automation. Additionally, in parallel, the MOCAS JPMO working through the DoD-wide enterprise governance model will continue to study, select, design, develop, test, and implement critical System Change Requests (SCRs) to further yield efficiency within the DoD's Procure to Pay (P2P) Business Process.

IWMS
IWMS will complete development and deployment of contract close-out and subsequently integrate with The Defense Contract Audit Agency (DCAA) and DCMA's Contract Business Analysis Repository to provide a "one stop shop" for DOD contract integration and close-out capabilities. 

Business Intelligence (BI) Modernization
BI Modernization will continue to provide internal DCMA end users self-service customization allowing for the creation and modification of canned and unique dashboards, displays, workspaces, and reporting across a multitude of DCMA functional capabilities. This cost category also includes online analytical processing (OLAP) which is a broader category of business intelligence which can be used for report writing.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:PriorYear>
                                </r2:Accomplishment>
                                <r2:PlannedProgram>
                                    <r2:CurrentYear>
                                        <r2:Funding>3.070</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>DCMA App Store 
DCMA will begin consolidating IT investments and transitioning subsequent applications to milCloud2 and other existing DoD capabilities/environments by 2nd Qtr FY 2020. Funding in FY 2020 and FY 2021 will be used to develop the concept of operations for building mission capabilities in a cloud environment, prototyping configuration management solutions that enable Development, Security, and Operations methodologies, and creating frameworks for automated testing solutions for rapid verification of application functionality.

WAWF
This effort will provide a more efficient way to retrieve accepted receiving report information for their active Commercial and Government Entity (CAGE) Codes and applicable extensions when initiating invoices for WAWF direct and vendor direct-shipping deliveries.  It will reduce significant manual processes as an electronic solution is currently unavailable. In addition, funding will be used to develop processes to increase electronic submissions and decrease manual labor to create paper corrected receiving reports and prevent delays due to manual processing of documents.  Requested changes for Wide Area WorkFlow were submitted to the Operational Requirements Committee (ORC) for review and approval.  This committee is chaired by Defense Pricing and Contracting Office (DPC) and the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) (OUSD (C)).</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:CurrentYear>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                        <r2:Funding>1.441</r2:Funding>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                    <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                        <r2:Funding>1.441</r2:Funding>
                                        <r2:Text>DCMA App Store 
FY 2021 RDT&amp;E will be used for activities in the material solution analysis and technology maturation and risk reduction phases of the acquisition life cycle, including Analysis of Alternatives, initial lifecycle sustainment plan, and initial concept of operations, system engineering plan, high level system design, prototyping, test and evaluation master plan.</r2:Text>
                                    </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                    <r2:AppChangeSummary>Explanation of change from FY 2020 to FY 2021 decreases result from anticipated WAWF requirements identified and a delay in the DCMA transition of application infrastructure to DISA enterprise hosting environments and modern technology platforms, which caused a slight schedule shift to the rationalization of existing applications to ensure capabilities align with mission requirements, and adopting new DoD strategies for modern software development methodologies for DCMA's App Store.</r2:AppChangeSummary>
                                </r2:PlannedProgram>
                            </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgram>
                        </r2:AccomplishmentPlannedProgramList>
                        <r2:AcquisitionStrategy>The DoD CIO’s strategy addresses Cloud, Cyber and Artificial Intelligence Initiatives and their implementation via the DoD IT Reform Initiative.  The DCMA Director has identified three DCMA initiatives in alignment with the DoD CIO’s initiatives to include: 1) Off-Ramping IT Services 2) Mission System Development and 3) The Last Tactical Mile.</r2:AcquisitionStrategy>
                    </r2:R2aExhibit>
                    <r2:R3Exhibit>
                        <r2:Remarks>The DCMA Information Technology supports the Agency’s CAS mission by capitalizing on IT investment innovations that leverage technology to achieve an agile enterprise architecture that improves its contract management workforce’s productivity, efficiency, and effectiveness.</r2:Remarks>
                        <r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                            <r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                                <r2:Name>Product Development</r2:Name>
                                <r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:Name>DCMA App Store</r2:Name>
                                        <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                        <r2:ContractType>FFP</r2:ContractType>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivity>Various</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                        <r2:Cost>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:Amount>2.270</r2:Amount>
                                                <r2:AwardDate>2020-01</r2:AwardDate>
                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                                <r2:Amount>1.441</r2:Amount>
                                            </r2:BudgetYearOne>
                                            <r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                                <r2:Amount>1.441</r2:Amount>
                                            </r2:BudgetYearOneBase>
                                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            <r2:TargetValue>3.712</r2:TargetValue>
                                        </r2:Cost>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:Name>WAWF</r2:Name>
                                        <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                        <r2:ContractType>FFP</r2:ContractType>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivity>Various</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                        <r2:Cost>
                                            <r2:CurrentYear>
                                                <r2:Amount>0.800</r2:Amount>
                                                <r2:AwardDate>2020-01</r2:AwardDate>
                                            </r2:CurrentYear>
                                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                            <r2:TargetValue>0.800</r2:TargetValue>
                                        </r2:Cost>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                    <r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                        <r2:Name>Other Programs</r2:Name>
                                        <r2:ContractMethod>C</r2:ContractMethod>
                                        <r2:ContractType>FFP</r2:ContractType>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivity>Various</r2:PerformingActivity>
                                        <r2:PerformingActivityLocation>Various</r2:PerformingActivityLocation>
                                        <r2:Cost>
                                            <r2:TotalPreviousYears>178.795</r2:TotalPreviousYears>
                                            <r2:PriorYear>
                                                <r2:Amount>11.988</r2:Amount>
                                            </r2:PriorYear>
                                            <r2:CostToComplete>Continuing</r2:CostToComplete>
                                            <r2:TotalCost>Continuing</r2:TotalCost>
                                        </r2:Cost>
                                    </r2:CostCategoryItem>
                                </r2:CostCategoryItemList>
                            </r2:CostCategoryGroup>
                        </r2:CostCategoryGroupList>
                    </r2:R3Exhibit>
                    <r2:R4aExhibit>
                        <r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                            <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                <r2:Title>WAWF</r2:Title>
                                <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Requirement</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>2</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>2</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Development</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>2</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                            </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                            <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                <r2:Title>Other Programs</r2:Title>
                                <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Requirement</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2018</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2019</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                            </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                            <r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                                <r2:Title>DCMA App Store Capability Release Sprint 1</r2:Title>
                                <r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Requirement</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2018</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>2</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Design</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>3</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2020</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>2</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2021</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Development</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2021</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>4</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2021</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Testing</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>2</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2021</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2022</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                    <r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                        <r2:EventTitle>Deployment</r2:EventTitle>
                                        <r2:Schedule>
                                            <r2:Start>
                                                <r2:Quarter>2</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2021</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:Start>
                                            <r2:End>
                                                <r2:Quarter>1</r2:Quarter>
                                                <r2:Year>2022</r2:Year>
                                            </r2:End>
                                        </r2:Schedule>
                                    </r2:ScheduleDetail>
                                </r2:ScheduleDetailList>
                            </r2:SubProjectSchedule>
                        </r2:SubProjectScheduleList>
                    </r2:R4aExhibit>
                </r2:Project>
            </r2:ProjectList>
        </r2:ProgramElement>
    </r2:ProgramElementList>
</jb:JustificationBook>