<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<jb:JustificationBook xmlns:jb="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/022009/jb" targetSchemaVersion="1.0">
    <jb:Title>Justification Book</jb:Title>
    <jb:BudgetYear>2020</jb:BudgetYear>
    <jb:BudgetCycle>PB</jb:BudgetCycle>
    <jb:SubmissionDate>2019-03</jb:SubmissionDate>
    <jb:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</jb:ServiceAgencyName>
    <jb:AppropriationCode>0300D</jb:AppropriationCode>
    <jb:AppropriationName>Procurement, Defense-Wide</jb:AppropriationName>
    <jb:CoverPage/>
    <jb:ExternalDocuments>
        <jb:UserP1Doc>
            <jb:Title>Comptroller Exhibit P-1</jb:Title>
            <jb:FileName>P-1 (25 Feb)_TJS_TJS#C#AXs.pdf</jb:FileName>
        </jb:UserP1Doc>
    </jb:ExternalDocuments>
    <jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        <jb:ForceEvenPages>true</jb:ForceEvenPages>
        <jb:WorkFlowStatus>DRAFT</jb:WorkFlowStatus>
        <jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>Title(s) undefined</jb:VolumeTitleAggregation>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByTitle>
        <jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>true</jb:GenerateLineItemTocByBA>
        <jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>true</jb:IncludeTableOfVolumes>
    </jb:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
    <proc:LineItemList xmlns:proc="http://www.dtic.mil/comptroller/xml/schema/20100219/procurement">
        <proc:LineItem quantityUnits="Each" quantityUnitName="Each" unitCostUnits="Millions" totalCostUnits="Millions" manufacturerRateUnits="Monthly" combinedP5Flag="false">
            <proc:LineItemNumber>10</proc:LineItemNumber>
            <proc:LineItemTitle>Major Equipment, TJS</proc:LineItemTitle>
            <proc:P1LineNumber>46</proc:P1LineNumber>
            <proc:BudgetYear>2020</proc:BudgetYear>
            <proc:BudgetCycle>PB</proc:BudgetCycle>
            <proc:SubmissionDate>2019-03</proc:SubmissionDate>
            <proc:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</proc:ServiceAgencyName>
            <proc:AppropriationNumber>0300D</proc:AppropriationNumber>
            <proc:AppropriationTitle>Procurement, Defense-Wide</proc:AppropriationTitle>
            <proc:BudgetActivityNumber>1</proc:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetActivityTitle>Major Equipment</proc:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>15</proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>Major Equipment, TJS</proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>
            <proc:ResourceSummary>
                <proc:TotalCost>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>84.017</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>9.341</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>4.36</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>6.905</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>6.905</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>2.908</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>2.909</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>2.909</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>2.909</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalCost>
                <proc:NetProcurementP1>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>84.017</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>9.341</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>4.36</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>6.905</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>6.905</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>2.908</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>2.909</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>2.909</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>2.909</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:NetProcurementP1>
                <proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>84.017</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>9.341</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>4.36</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>6.905</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>6.905</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>2.908</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>2.909</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>2.909</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>2.909</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
            </proc:ResourceSummary>
            <proc:Description>The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) is the principal military adviser to the President, National Security Council, and Secretary of Defense. The Chairman presides over and serves as a member of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. CJCS relies upon the Joint Staff to craft and distribute guidance for combatant forces' unified strategic direction, operations under unified commands, and integration into effective combat forces. On behalf of the Chairman, the Joint Staff provides Combatant Commands (CCMDs), the Services, and U.S. war fighters with joint policy, strategy, and doctrine necessary to employ effective joint combat forces in contingencies worldwide.</proc:Description>
            <proc:Justification>The Joint Staff requests $6.905M in FY 2020 procurement for mission critical information technology systems and applications investment requirements. The procurement request resources various efforts across the Joint Staff, including investments in joint force development data center and Information Technology (IT) / Information Security (IS) equipment.  

Note: In FY20, Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) is moved to a new line item (line 15) to improve visibility into Cyber program resources.

Program Change Summary:

FY18 – FY19: net decrease of $5.0M is due to realignment of resources from PROC to O&amp;M to better align resources to requirements. Realignments were PDAS ($3.0M), JIOR ($0.8M), Suffolk Training Facility ($0.6), and JIAMDO ($0.1M). In addition, an armored vehicle purchase was canceled in FY19 valued at $0.5M.

FY19 – FY20: net increase of $2.6M is due to PDAS (apparent increase of $3.0M due to FY19 reduction of $3.0M), PDAS (actual increase of $1.0M for increase users), JIOR (decrease of $1.4M due to moving to a separate line).

1. Planning and Decision Aid System (PDAS):

PDAS realigned Procurement funding, $3.0M per year, to O&amp;M to fund higher priority requirements for the following years:  FY 2019, FY 2021 – FY 2024.  FY 2020 Procurement funding is necessary to support equipment modernizations and technology refresh for major systems and data centers. Due to an expanding base of users, Procurement funding was increased by $1.0M in FY 2020 to support additional user client systems.

PDAS is a classified, protected program operated by the Joint Staff.  PDAS supports the planning and execution of Joint Staff and Unified Combatant Commanders (CCMD) operations.  PDAS is a world-wide network protecting sensitive information that meets the Intelligence Community Directive 503 security requirements.  PDAS provides office automation packages, document and information management tools; collaboration, voice, and video tools in a secure, flexible architecture that promotes a distributed enterprise.  Within the enterprise, PDAS users have access to their data regardless of log-on location, secure data exchange, conferencing and planning sessions among physically distributed continental United States and outside continental United States locations. Users are provided access to a Help Desk and remote troubleshooting within the PDAS enterprise. 

Equipment modernization will allow the Joint Staff to develop plans to implement materiel solutions to address hardware and software configuration items that are outdated, nearing end-of-life or end-of-support or which can no longer be commercially acquired.  Historically, this equipment has been purchased as required due to failures, end-of-life, or end-of-service which has led to many baselines and configurations of deployed hardware, software and communications equipment. Items reach end-of-life in different years providing a cascade of equipment replacement requirements.  This spacing lessens the financial impact but requires constant purchase, integration, testing and installation.  Integration and testing ensures that hardware or software is compatible with other installed hardware and software configuration items and does not introduce vulnerabilities into PDAS, or allow unauthorized personnel to gain access to information for which they are not authorized.  There are four specific focus uses as follows.

PDAS funding will be used to procure equipment modernizations, datacenter refresh, and client refresh. Due to the cyclic nature of the PDAS technical refresh requirement of datacenters, client computers and other IT equipment, this program presents a non-linear funding profile with noticeable spikes in funding requirements during technical refresh years.  When possible, equipment is purchased in increments across fiscal years to lessen spikes in funding requirements where possible. Funding spikes support major system upgrades for data centers in FY 2018 and user clients in FY 2020.

PDAS is composed of hundreds of user sites with thousands of users worldwide. In recent years, the number of PDAS sites grew by 25 percent with planned expansion of both sites and users.  PDAS sites provide capabilities, services and the infrastructure necessary to meet operational mission needs. 

Datacenter refresh allows the Joint Staff to provide refreshed datacenter hardware and software. The hardware and software to be replaced is reaching the end of its service life and approaching obsolescence.  New equipment for the datacenters will enable the PDAS program to consolidate equipment baselines and provide commonality at the datacenters. This periodic refresh provides PDAS with an updated hardware and software infrastructure, enabling improved performance, security, efficiency, and reduced logistical requirements.  From an operational perspective, it moves the program from event-driven, reactive situations of coping with the latest problem to a more proactive, forward-facing operational posture. The focus becomes one of preemptive quality assurance, standardization, and optimization. 

Client refresh will allow the Joint Staff to provide updated computer hardware to the PDAS users in order to be compliant with Security Control 28 (protection of information at rest to prevent insider threats). This periodic refresh will provide users with an up to date hardware and software infrastructure, enabling improved performance, security, efficiency, and reducing logistical requirements. Client refresh is planned for FY 2020.  

2. Management Headquarters:

Management Headquarters provides the day-to-day financial resources necessary to conduct Joint Staff operations. Funding supports the mission-unique non-Joint Service Provider (JSP), Joint Staff IT requirements, and technology upgrades for the joint training facility, and Joint Integrated Air &amp; Missile Defense Organization (JIAMDO), Joint Range Extender (JRE). 

Management Headquarters funds are also used to procure major hardware and software technology upgrade investments for the Suffolk, VA, joint training facility. These funds provide significant network distribution/security, data processing, and capacity upgrades to the Suffolk Data Center to increase performance, security, reliability, and accessibility to the Combatant Commands and Services. Capability upgrades are required to host current joint training applications (Joint Knowledge Online, Joint Training Information Management System, Joint Lessons Learned Information Systems, and Joint Live, Virtual, and Constructive simulations). Additionally, the upgrades provide support to multi-site, multi-command, distributed live, virtual, and constructive joint force training events addressing transregional, multi-domain, and multi-functional threat environments.

The Deputy Secretary of Defense approved the alignment of common IT services in the Pentagon and the National Capital Region to JSP operating as a field service activity in Defense Information Systems Agency (DISA). In 2018, the Joint Staff Information Network resources permanently transferred to the JSP (DISA PE 0305830K).  The overall effect to the Department was a net-zero profile change for FY 2018 and beyond.  Limited IT procurement funding was retained for mission-unique, non-JSP Joint Staff IT requirements. 

Note: In FY 2019 and beyond, all JIAMDO procurement funding (~$100K per year) was moved to JIAMDO's RDT&amp;E account.  JIAMDO funds are used to support a Near Real Time Server in support of Combat Identification applications and semi rugged laptop, software licenses, and help desk services for JRE advanced combat identification efforts. 

3.  Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR):

The Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) provides DoD with a closed-loop network that forms a global live-fire information operations range complex. JIOR uses encrypted tunneling over existing transport networks to conduct mission rehearsal, training, testing, concept development and experimentation in support of Information Operations (IO), Electronic Warfare (EW), Offensive Cyber Operations (OCO), Defensive Cyber Operations (DCO), Spectrum Warfare, Space Operations, and Special Operations Forces mission areas in a realistic threat representative environment. JIOR provides the capability to train and certify Cyber Mission Forces on the full spectrum of cyber weapons/capabilities without risk of observation or fratricide. JIOR is unique within the Department of Defense and is accredited by DIA for operations at Unclassified through Top Secret-Special Compartment Information (TS-SCI) in a Multiple Independent Levels of Security (MILS) environment. JIOR is approved for use by Special Access Programs (SAP), Special Access Required Programs (SAR), and for Special Technical Operations (STO). JIOR provides Combatant Commands, Services and Agencies (C/S/A's) and key allied partners the ability to test deployment and collaboratively gain insights into advanced cyberspace and Electronic Warfare (EW) capabilities under current and future operational environments. JIOR integrates available cyberspace ranges with the training/test audience providing access to low density/high demand test and training resources including critical infrastructure, cyber targets, internet traffic, and opposing forces. JIOR supports Presidential policy and CJCS mandates for training, certification, and recertification of 6000+ cyber mission forces and DoD/Interagency cyber vulnerability assessments. C/S/A's conduct hundreds of mission rehearsal, training, testing, and experimentation events on the JIOR annually.

JIOR procurement funding is used to purchase technology upgrades/modernization to the JIOR enterprise network. Planned equipment and software modernization enable the JIOR to extend service to 36 new sites while continuing support to the existing 138 JIOR access points. Equipment for 7 of these sites will be procured in FY 2020.

Historically, JIOR had limited IT refresh funding and has purchased replacement hardware due to failures, end-of-life, or end-of-service constraints which has not allowed for a focused modernization effort. Given the increased cyber mission focus, periodic technology upgrades are required to make the JIOR more efficient, agile, and sufficiently robust to accommodate this significant network expansion to meet the additional Cyber Mission Force demand.</proc:Justification>
            <proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                <proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>expandItemSuppressExhibit</proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>
            </proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        </proc:LineItem>
        <proc:LineItem quantityUnits="Each" quantityUnitName="Each" unitCostUnits="Millions" totalCostUnits="Millions">
            <proc:LineItemNumber>15</proc:LineItemNumber>
            <proc:LineItemTitle>TJS Cyber</proc:LineItemTitle>
            <proc:P1LineNumber>47</proc:P1LineNumber>
            <proc:BudgetYear>2020</proc:BudgetYear>
            <proc:BudgetCycle>PB</proc:BudgetCycle>
            <proc:SubmissionDate>2019-03</proc:SubmissionDate>
            <proc:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</proc:ServiceAgencyName>
            <proc:AppropriationNumber>0300D</proc:AppropriationNumber>
            <proc:AppropriationTitle>Procurement, Defense-Wide</proc:AppropriationTitle>
            <proc:BudgetActivityNumber>1</proc:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetActivityTitle>Major Equipment</proc:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>15</proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>Major Equipment, TJS</proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>
            <proc:ResourceSummary>
                <proc:TotalCost>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1.458</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>1.458</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>1.467</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>1.459</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>1.459</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>1.459</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalCost>
                <proc:NetProcurementP1>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1.458</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>1.458</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>1.467</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>1.459</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>1.459</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>1.459</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:NetProcurementP1>
                <proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>1.458</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>1.458</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>1.467</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>1.459</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>1.459</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>1.459</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                    <proc:Continuing>true</proc:Continuing>
                </proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
            </proc:ResourceSummary>
            <proc:Description>The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) is the principal military adviser to the President, National Security Council, and Secretary of Defense. The Chairman presides over and serves as a member of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. CJCS relies upon the Joint Staff to craft and distribute guidance for combatant forces' unified strategic direction, operations under unified commands, and integration into effective combat forces. On behalf of the Chairman, the Joint Staff provides Combatant Commands (CCMDs), the Services, and U.S. war fighters with joint policy, strategy, and doctrine necessary to employ effective joint combat forces in contingencies worldwide.</proc:Description>
            <proc:Justification>NOTE: This is a new line item to provide visibility into Joint Staff Cyber resources. P-1 Line 15 is a net-zero realignment from P-1 Line 10 (Major Equipment, TJS) from FY 2020 through FY 2024. P-1 Line 10 has been decreased by the amounts displayed in this new line item.

Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) 

The Joint Information Operations Range (JIOR) provides DoD with a closed-loop network that forms a global live-fire information operations range complex. JIOR uses encrypted tunneling over existing transport networks to conduct mission rehearsal, training, testing, concept development and experimentation in support of Information Operations (IO), Electronic Warfare (EW), Offensive Cyber Operations (OCO), Defensive Cyber Operations (DCO), Spectrum Warfare, Space Operations, and Special Operations Forces mission areas in a realistic threat representative environment. JIOR provides the capability to train and certify Cyber Mission Forces on the full spectrum of cyber weapons/capabilities without risk of observation or fratricide. JIOR is unique within the Department of Defense and is accredited by DIA for operations at Unclassified through Top Secret-Special Compartment Information (TS-SCI) in a Multiple Independent Levels of Security (MILS) environment. JIOR is approved for use by Special Access Programs (SAP), Special Access Required Programs (SAR), and for Special Technical Operations (STO). JIOR provides Combatant Commands, Services and Agencies (C/S/A's) and key allied partners the ability to test deployment and collaboratively gain insights into advanced cyberspace and Electronic Warfare (EW) capabilities under current and future operational environments. JIOR integrates available cyberspace ranges with the training/test audience providing access to low density/high demand test and training resources including critical infrastructure, cyber targets, internet traffic, and opposing forces. JIOR supports Presidential policy and CJCS mandates for training, certification, and recertification of 6000+ cyber mission forces and DoD/Interagency cyber vulnerability assessments. C/S/A's conduct hundreds of mission rehearsal, training, testing, and experimentation events on the JIOR annually.

JIOR procurement funding is used to purchase technology upgrades/modernization to the JIOR enterprise network. Planned equipment and software modernization enable the JIOR to extend service to 36 new sites while continuing support to the existing 138 JIOR access points. Equipment for 7 of these sites will be procured in FY 2020.

Historically, JIOR had limited IT refresh funding and has purchased replacement hardware due to failures, end-of-life, or end-of-service constraints which has not allowed for a focused modernization effort. Given the increased cyber mission focus, periodic technology upgrades are required to make the JIOR more efficient, agile, and sufficiently robust to accommodate this significant network expansion to meet the additional Cyber Mission Force demand.</proc:Justification>
            <proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                <proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>expandItemSuppressExhibit</proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>
            </proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        </proc:LineItem>
        <proc:LineItem quantityUnits="Each" quantityUnitName="Each" unitCostUnits="Millions" totalCostUnits="Millions">
            <proc:LineItemNumber>80</proc:LineItemNumber>
            <proc:LineItemTitle>Major Equipment, TJS - CE2T2</proc:LineItemTitle>
            <proc:P1LineNumber>48</proc:P1LineNumber>
            <proc:BudgetYear>2020</proc:BudgetYear>
            <proc:BudgetCycle>PB</proc:BudgetCycle>
            <proc:SubmissionDate>2019-03</proc:SubmissionDate>
            <proc:ServiceAgencyName>The Joint Staff</proc:ServiceAgencyName>
            <proc:AppropriationNumber>0300D</proc:AppropriationNumber>
            <proc:AppropriationTitle>Procurement, Defense-Wide</proc:AppropriationTitle>
            <proc:BudgetActivityNumber>1</proc:BudgetActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetActivityTitle>Major Equipment</proc:BudgetActivityTitle>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>15</proc:BudgetSubActivityNumber>
            <proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>Major Equipment, TJS</proc:BudgetSubActivityTitle>
            <proc:ResourceSummary>
                <proc:TotalCost>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>0</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>0.903</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>0.904</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>0</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>0</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>0</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>0</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>0</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                </proc:TotalCost>
                <proc:NetProcurementP1>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>0</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>0.903</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>0.904</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>0</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>0</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>0</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>0</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>0</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                </proc:NetProcurementP1>
                <proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
                    <proc:AllPriorYears>0</proc:AllPriorYears>
                    <proc:PriorYear>0.903</proc:PriorYear>
                    <proc:CurrentYear>0.904</proc:CurrentYear>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOneBase>0</proc:BudgetYearOneBase>
                    <proc:BudgetYearOne>0</proc:BudgetYearOne>
                    <proc:BudgetYearTwo>0</proc:BudgetYearTwo>
                    <proc:BudgetYearThree>0</proc:BudgetYearThree>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFour>0</proc:BudgetYearFour>
                    <proc:BudgetYearFive>0</proc:BudgetYearFive>
                </proc:TotalObligationAuthority>
            </proc:ResourceSummary>
            <proc:Description>The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff (CJCS) is the principal military adviser to the President, National Security Council, and Secretary of Defense. The Chairman presides over and serves as a member of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. CJCS relies upon the Joint Staff (TJS) to craft and distribute guidance for combatant forces' unified strategic direction, operations under unified commands, and integration into effective combat forces. On behalf of the Chairman, TJS provides Combatant Commands (CCMDs), the Services, and U.S. war fighters with joint policy, strategy, and doctrine necessary to employ effective joint combat forces in contingencies worldwide.</proc:Description>
            <proc:Justification>The FY 2020 - FY 2024 Joint Staff program realigns CE2T2 procurement resources to CE2T2 O&amp;M to satisfy higher priority requirements.

FY 2019 CE2T2 procurement funding is being used to support the following activities: 

1 . USCYBERCOM-led CYBER FLAG, CYBER GUARD, and CYBER KNIGHT exercises. The exercise environment includes a "blue forces" Department of Defense Information Network to include Network Operations Security Centers, a "gray" network of internet spaces to include .gov and .edu domains that will emulate Internet sites and user activities, a realistic representation of an adversary "red" network, and a management systems network. This emulated training environment is designed to utilize the existing Joint Information Operation Range (JIOR) transport layer to directly support USCYBERCOM's mission. Procurement funding increases storage capacity and improves the survivability/durability of the target environment.
 
2. Joint Interoperability Division (JID).  JID is a critical enabler to the training transformation program as sole DoD provider of Tactical Data Link and Joint Interface Control Officer (JICO) training. Procurement funds support acquisition of one Satellite Simulator (SATSIM) and two Situational Awareness Data Link (SADL) radio systems required for JICO mission equipment kits #2 and #3. SATSIM, SADL radios, and Thinklogical systems enable the JID to bring real-time situational awareness, location, targeting, and C2 data to smart bombs, dispersed joint forces on foot, or tactical vehicles in the air, land, or maritime environments.</proc:Justification>
            <proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
                <proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>expandItemSuppressExhibit</proc:p40AItemScheduleSetting>
            </proc:DocumentAssemblyOptions>
        </proc:LineItem>
    </proc:LineItemList>
</jb:JustificationBook>